<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.eastafro.www:http/2018/08/27/ethiopia-ousts-state-firm-metec-from-nile-dam-project/</field>
<field name="title">Ethiopia Ousts State Firm (METEC) From Nile Dam Project</field>
<field name="name">Ethiopia Ousts State Firm (METEC) From Nile Dam Project</field>
<field name="created">2018-08-27T22:10:47Z</field>
<field name="desc">Ethiopia Ousts State Firm (METEC) From Nile Dam Project   Ethiopia Ousts State Firm From Nile Dam Project       ADDIS ABABA —  Ethiopia has ousted state-run Metals and Engineering Corporation (METEC) from a $4 billion dam project on the River Nile due to numerous delays in completing the project.     The Grand Renaissance Dam is the centerpiece of Ethiopia’s bid to become Africa’s biggest power exporter.     Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed said at the weekend that the government had cancelled the contract of METEC  which is run by Ethiopia’s military  and would award it to another company.       Italian firm Salini Impregilo remains the main contractor building the dam  while METEC was the contractor for the electromechanical and hydraulic steel structure divisions of the project.     The government has touted the 6 000-megawatt dam project  which is 60 percent finished  as a symbol of its economic reforms.     “It is a project that was supposed to be completed within five years  but seven or eight years later not a single turbine is operational ” Abiy said during a news conference in Addis Ababa on Saturday.     “Salini has even demanded compensation because of the delays. We decided to cancel a contract with METEC and offer companies with experience. Otherwise  it will take even longer ” he said.     Abiy has presided over a series of reforms since coming to power in April  releasing political prisoners  relaxing state control of the economy and dramatically improving relations with Ethiopia’s neighbor Eritrea.     The government had previously said the dam would be completed within two years  but recently Abiy said it may face a lengthy delay.     An official at METEC  who did not wish to be named  said the company first heard of the cancellation on Saturday.   “Even now our workers are on the site ” the official said.   </field>
<field name="tag">eastafro</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/eastafro/2018_Aug/37697072a890cf67b6956adc0361153d.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.eastafro.com/2018/08/27/ethiopia-ousts-state-firm-metec-from-nile-dam-project/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
