<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/pm-abiy-says-future-of-ethiopia-depends-on-youth-immersed-in-technology-science-and-national-confidence/</field>
<field name="title">Premier Abiy says future of Ethiopia depends on youth immersed in technology  science  and national confidence</field>
<field name="name">Premier Abiy says future of Ethiopia depends on youth immersed in technology  science  and national confidence</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-04T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Premier Abiy says future of Ethiopia depends on youth immersed in technology  science  and national confidence On Jun 14  2025 882 Addis Ababa  June 14  2025 (FMC) – Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed has called on Ethiopian families  educators  and the youth to explore the newly inaugurated permanent exhibition at the Science Museum  highlighting its significance as a gateway to the future and a rare opportunity to engage directly with transformative technologies. The Science Museum  initially launched two years ago with a temporary display  now houses a fully installed permanent exhibition composed of five major interactive sections  Artificial Intelligence  Environment  Agriculture  Water   Energy  and Space   Aeronautics. The Prime Minister noted that while the physical construction of the museum took less time  assembling and installing the permanent exhibitions required two years of intensive work and a substantial investment of resources. Each section of the exhibition is designed to educate and inspire  especially Ethiopia’s younger generation. The Artificial Intelligence section presents the evolution of AI  from its origins to its current applications and future potential  with demonstrations of service robots and smart technologies used in hotels and urban settings. The Environment section highlights the impact of human actions on nature  illustrating how deforestation  soil degradation  and other missteps lead to long-term consequences like drought and crop failure. It underlines the importance of living in harmony with the natural world. The Agriculture section reflects on Ethiopia’s early role in the development of agriculture  while examining why technological advancement in the sector lagged behind. It promotes modern techniques like precision farming and emphasizes how greater yields can be achieved even on small plots of land. It also pays tribute to Ethiopia’s native crops—such as teff  enset  and coffee—and their contribution to global food culture. In the Water and Energy section  visitors can explore the formation and use of water  including its role in food production  sanitation  and power generation. The exhibit features models of various energy sources such as solar  geothermal  nuclear  fusion  and hydro. A scaled representation of the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam (GERD) is a key highlight  allowing visitors to engage with one of the country’s flagship infrastructure projects without needing to visit the site. The Space and Aeronautics section showcases technologies not commonly accessible in Africa or even in many parts of the world. It includes immersive simulators of a Boeing 777 aircraft  a Leonardo helicopter  and a spacewalk simulator that allows visitors to experience astronaut movement in zero gravity. The exhibit also features systems related to air traffic management  unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs)  and aviation manufacturing. The Prime Minister emphasized that many of the exhibition’s components—including original hardware from international aerospace and tech companies—are not available in university laboratories. He recognized the support of General Electric (GE)  Boeing  Leonardo  and several French  UAE  and Ethiopian firms in helping bring the project to life. Stressing the importance of youth engagement  the Prime Minister encouraged families to bring their children during the rainy season  noting that the hands-on  interactive nature of the exhibition makes it especially impactful. By allowing children to touch  try  and see the technologies firsthand  the exhibition is designed to cultivate a generation that is not just informed  but innovative and forward-thinking. The Prime Minister described the museum as an artistic and educational milestone  and a national asset with the power to nurture future scientists  engineers  and visionaries. He underscored that children who grow up interacting with such environments will be better prepared to contribute to Ethiopia’s development. The inauguration marks a milestone in Ethiopia’s broader push toward science education  innovation  and technological self-reliance. With its focus on both the country’s heritage and its future  the permanent exhibition stands as a symbol of aspiration and possibility for generations to come. 882 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/72058dd4f538157e4b00f76be6bc1d42.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/pm-abiy-says-future-of-ethiopia-depends-on-youth-immersed-in-technology-science-and-national-confidence/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
