<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/afreximbank-lauds-ethiopias-growing-financial-sector/</field>
<field name="title">Afreximbank Lauds Ethiopia’s Growing Financial Sector</field>
<field name="name">Afreximbank Lauds Ethiopia’s Growing Financial Sector</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-04T20:10:39Z</field>
<field name="desc">Afreximbank Lauds Ethiopia’s Growing Financial Sector On Jun 4  2025 654 Addis Ababa  June 4  2025 (FMC) – African Export-Import Bank (Afreximbank) has praised Ethiopia’s transformative economic reforms  reaffirming its commitment to scaling up continued support for one of Africa’s fastest growing economies. Client Relations Acting Group Managing Director at Afreximbank  Eric Monchu Intong commended Ethiopia’s immense reforms being implemented in various spheres. “Ethiopia is making us proud and giving us hope; the reforms have been immense in the financial sector  the deregulation of the FX market  and the encouragement of local manufacturing for import substitution ” he said. He noted the agricultural sector as a whole  the transportation sector  the local manufacturing  the logistics  and all the other sectors are driven by the financial sector. He added “We can use our credit intervention  be it short term loans  medium term loans  long term loans  or we can use our guarantees and specialized financing using short term  medium term  and long-term guarantee to de-risk investment.” For the Acting Group Managing Director  Ethiopia is a founding member of Afreximbank  a Pan-African multilateral financial institution and a key supporter of the bank’s initiatives. Since 2021  we have set about 2 billion USD to Ethiopia on a revolving basis  he told ENA. Given the GDP  the population and the size of the economy as well as the reforms under implementation  the 2 billion USD revolving support is not enough  he disclosed. “I think comfortably  we can manage an exposure of 5 billion USD over the next three to five years ” he affirmed. The bank has also expressed its readiness to finance trade and trade enabling projects such as railways  airports  industrial parks  local manufacturing  and valueadded exports  like coffee  among others. Ethiopia’s GDP is expected to continue its upward trajectory  reflecting Ethiopia’s position as one of Africa’s fastest growing economies  he further noted. 654 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/916a0198f710b5bb082b062df7e8d8f3.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/afreximbank-lauds-ethiopias-growing-financial-sector/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
