<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/fifa-president-infantino-hints-at-possible-cristiano-ronaldo-participation-in-club-world-cup/</field>
<field name="title">FIFA president Infantino hints at possible Cristiano Ronaldo participation in Club World Cup</field>
<field name="name">FIFA president Infantino hints at possible Cristiano Ronaldo participation in Club World Cup</field>
<field name="created">2025-05-24T09:25:19Z</field>
<field name="desc">FIFA president Infantino hints at possible Cristiano Ronaldo participation in Club World Cup On May 24  2025 952 Addis Ababa  May 24  2025 (FMC) – The upcoming FIFA Club World Cup  set to take place in the United States  is already generating major anticipation. With soccer’s top clubs and players vying to compete on the global stage  speculation is mounting over who will take part. One name drawing particular attention is Cristiano Ronaldo—and FIFA president Gianni Infantino recently hinted at the possibility of his involvement. The topic came up during a live stream hosted by popular American internet personality IShowSpeed  who featured Infantino as a guest. When the conversation shifted to the Club World Cup  the FIFA president appeared to leave the door open for a Ronaldo appearance in the tournament. “And Ronaldo might play for one of the teams at the Club World Cup ” Infantino said. Speed  taken aback  responded with surprise  “Really?” and quickly followed up with  “Wait  so Ronaldo might be in the Club World Cup?” Infantino doubled down on his remarks. “Yeah  Cristiano Ronaldo might play at a Club World Cup. These are discussions with some clubs ” he said. “So if any club is watching and is interested in hiring Ronaldo for a Club World Cup… who knows? There’s still some time. It would be fun.” As the conversation progressed  the topic naturally turned to the long-standing debate between Cristiano Ronaldo and Lionel Messi—two of the sport’s greatest icons. But rather than choose between them  Infantino expressed a wish shared by many fans  seeing both players on the same team. When Speed asked him to pick between the two  Infantino paused before offering a heartfelt answer. “Listen  two great players  two incredible players. If you’re Portuguese  you go for Ronaldo; if you’re Argentine  you go for Messi. But if you’re a soccer fan  you want to see both—because you love the game.” “I’d love to see both of them playing together ” he continued. “Imagine the two of them on the same team. That would be something special.” Speed then joked that he had a feeling it might happen one day  to which Infantino laughed and replied  “In the FIFA team  maybe.” Cristiano Ronaldo’s presence at the Club World Cup would undoubtedly elevate the competition to another level. At 39  he remains one of the most recognizable and prolific figures in global soccer. His participation would not only attract massive viewership but could potentially reignite his legendary rivalry with Messi. 952 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/53b82ac324c4c1ecc3e3db74fb8969a7.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/fifa-president-infantino-hints-at-possible-cristiano-ronaldo-participation-in-club-world-cup/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
