<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/china-proposes-zero-tariff-access-for-53-african-countries-with-diplomatic-ties/</field>
<field name="title">Beijing proposes zero-tariff access for 53 African countries with diplomatic ties</field>
<field name="name">Beijing proposes zero-tariff access for 53 African countries with diplomatic ties</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-11T11:08:31Z</field>
<field name="desc">Beijing proposes zero-tariff access for 53 African countries with diplomatic ties On Jun 11  2025 1 012 Addis Ababa  June 11  2025 (FMC) — Chinese President Xi Jinping has announced China’s readiness to negotiate and sign a China-Africa Economic Partnership for Shared Development that would grant zero-tariff treatment for all tariff lines to 53 African countries maintaining diplomatic relations with Beijing. The proposal was shared in a congratulatory letter to the Ministerial Meeting of Coordinators on the Implementation of FOCAC Follow-up Actions  held in Changsha  China. Xi said the initiative aims to facilitate greater market access for African exports  especially from least developed countries  and inject new momentum into China-Africa economic ties. Highlighting the 25-year legacy of the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation (FOCAC)  Xi said the platform has become a model for Global South solidarity and has entered a new phase since the 2023 Beijing Summit  where leaders agreed on a six-point modernization plan and 10 partnership actions. Xi also welcomed the consensus to make 2026 the China-Africa Year of People-to-People Exchanges  and reaffirmed China’s commitment to cooperation in green development  digital trade  AI  security  and finance. In a separate letter  Republic of the Congo President Denis Sassou Nguesso  co-chair of FOCAC  praised the progress of strategic cooperation with China and pledged to deepen joint efforts. He voiced support for working with Beijing and other Global South nations to build a multipolar world free from unilateralism and protectionism. Both leaders underscored the shared goal of building an all-weather China-Africa community and contributing to global peace and development. 1 012 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/ccacb32b015aa97c50eda120bec7fcda.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/china-proposes-zero-tariff-access-for-53-african-countries-with-diplomatic-ties/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
