<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/china-and-africa-reaffirm-global-south-solidarity-in-changsha-declaration/</field>
<field name="title">China and Africa reaffirm global south solidarity in Changsha Declaration</field>
<field name="name">China and Africa reaffirm global south solidarity in Changsha Declaration</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">China and Africa reaffirm global south solidarity in Changsha Declaration On Jun 11  2025 955 Addis Ababa  June 11  2025 (FMC) – China  53 African countries  and the African Union Commission have adopted the China-Africa Changsha Declaration on Upholding Solidarity and Cooperation of the Global South  reaffirming commitments from the 2024 Beijing Summit of the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation (FOCAC). The declaration was finalized during the Ministerial Meeting of Coordinators on the Implementation of FOCAC follow-up actions  held June 10–12 in Changsha  China. The meeting gathered representatives to advance the full implementation of the Beijing Declaration on building an all-weather China-Africa community with a shared future. The Chinese Foreign Ministry said the declaration “recognizes the rise of the Global South as the trend of the times and the future of development” and calls on all countries “to build a community with a shared future for mankind” through initiatives like the Belt and Road and the Global Development  Security  and Civilization Initiatives. The statement condemns “unilateralism  protectionism and economic bullying” as major challenges for African and developing countries  urging “all countries  the United States in particular  to return to resolving trade disputes through consultation based on equality  respect and mutual benefit.” It calls for increased development assistance to Africa  not unilateral cuts. China’s role was praised  highlighting its “courage and resolve to defend international equity and justice and safeguard international economic and trade order.” The declaration calls on the international community to “uphold true multilateralism ” defend the U.N.-centered system and WTO-based trading order  and promote more inclusive economic globalization. On trade  China committed to expanding zero-tariff treatment on all tariff lines to all 53 African countries with diplomatic ties (except Eswatini)  alongside enhanced market access  inspection  and customs facilitation for Africa’s least developed nations. The declaration also prioritizes cooperation in green industry  e-commerce  science and technology  AI  security  finance  and the rule of law  supporting Africa’s Agenda 2063. The Forum on China-Africa Cooperation was hailed as “a fine example of Global South solidarity ” with plans for a 2026 China-Africa Year of People-to-People Exchanges to strengthen ties. 955 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/08796eedf0c8ad2943b402ce7743ade3.jpeg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/china-and-africa-reaffirm-global-south-solidarity-in-changsha-declaration/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
