<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/mou-signed-to-enable-export-of-ethiopian-avocado-products-to-china/</field>
<field name="title">MOU signed to enable export of Ethiopian avocado products to China</field>
<field name="name">MOU signed to enable export of Ethiopian avocado products to China</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-12T17:35:59Z</field>
<field name="desc">MOU signed to enable export of Ethiopian avocado products to China On Jun 12  2025 644 Addis Ababa  June 12  2025 (FMC) — A Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) enabling the export of Ethiopian avocado products to China was officially signed on June 12  2025  during the China-Africa Economic and Trade Expo held in Changsha  China. The agreement was signed by Ambassador Tefera Derbew  Plenipotentiary Ambassador of the Federal Democratic Republic of Ethiopia to the People’s Republic of China  and Mr. Wang Lingjun  Vice Minister of the General Administration of Customs of China. The Ethiopian Embassy in Beijing told Fana Media Corporation that the MoU marks a significant milestone in expanding Ethiopia’s agricultural export portfolio. It was stated that the agreement is expected to substantially boost the volume of value-added Ethiopian avocado exports entering the Chinese market. The protocol is the result of a six-month joint technical preparation and review process carried out by Ethiopian agricultural authorities in close collaboration with China’s General Administration of Customs. Following the successful conclusion of this process  the protocol received official endorsement and approval from the Chinese side  authorizing the registration and commencement of avocado exports. Prior to the signing ceremony  Ambassador Tefera held discussions with Chinese customs officials aimed at further strengthening bilateral cooperation. He also urged the acceleration of the registration and approval processes for other Ethiopian agricultural products currently under review. This agreement represents a critical step forward in Ethiopia’s strategy to diversify its export markets and deepen economic ties with China. 644 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/eb3a1f9d35d9c5e5fa49ceebc10f74d0.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/mou-signed-to-enable-export-of-ethiopian-avocado-products-to-china/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
