<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/president-taye-inaugurates-kegna-beverages-s-c-boosting-local-industry-and-employment/</field>
<field name="title">Prez. Taye inaugurates Kegna Beverages S.C.  boosting local industry and employment</field>
<field name="name">Prez. Taye inaugurates Kegna Beverages S.C.  boosting local industry and employment</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Prez. Taye inaugurates Kegna Beverages S.C.  boosting local industry and employment On Jun 14  2025 457 Addis Ababa  June 14  2025 (FMC) — President Taye Atske-Selassie officially inaugurated Kegna Beverages S.C. today  marking the launch of one of Ethiopia’s newest beverage production enterprises. The inauguration event  held in the Oromia Region  was attended by Oromia’s Chief Administrator Shimelis Abdisa  senior federal and regional officials  and other dignitaries. Kegna Beverages S.C.  located on a 110-hectare site  represents a significant investment exceeding 22 billion birr. The company is designed to produce more than 3 million hectoliters annually using modern  competitive technologies aimed at global standards. The enterprise is structured as a joint-stock company with over 4 000 Ethiopian shareholders  including cooperatives and organizations  demonstrating strong local ownership and participation. Currently  Kegna Beverages S.C. provides employment for 250 people  with projections to expand the workforce to 1 000 once operations reach full capacity. This development is expected to contribute significantly to Ethiopia’s industrial growth  local job creation  and the enhancement of the country’s beverage sector. 457 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/5adf7415743253ce2612b0e623c37ddd.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/president-taye-inaugurates-kegna-beverages-s-c-boosting-local-industry-and-employment/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
