<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/au-calls-for-accelerated-efforts-to-deepen-afcfta-implementation77288-2/</field>
<field name="title">AU calls for accelerated efforts to deepen AfCFTA implementation</field>
<field name="name">AU calls for accelerated efforts to deepen AfCFTA implementation</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">AU calls for accelerated efforts to deepen AfCFTA implementation On Jun 9  2025 510 Addis Ababa  June 9  2025 (FMC) — The African Union called for accelerated efforts to deepen the Africa Continental Free Trade Area (AfCFTA)  stimulate industrialization  and drive innovation-led growth. The 50th session of the Permanent Representatives Committee (PRC) took place today at the AU headquarters. In her keynote address to the session  Ambassador Selma Malika Haddadi  the Deputy Chairperson of the African Union Commission  noted that the new administration has been intensifying efforts to identify areas of concern for member states. According to her  critical areas have been identified that require action and joint  collaborative efforts  as well as enhanced dialogue and communication. To this effect  she called upon all member states of the African Union to accelerate their efforts to implement the AfCFTA  stimulate industrialization  and drive innovation-led growth. “We must accelerate efforts to deepen the AfCFTA  stimulate industrialization  and drive innovation-led growth ” the deputy chairperson underscored. She also stressed the need for strengthening relations between the Commission and Regional Economic Communities and Regional Mechanisms (RECs/RMs)  a key priority for the new leadership. Malika mentioned that the AU recently convened a Coordination Committee Meeting with the executives and secretary-generals of the RECs/RMs. She remarked that the goal of this joint meeting was “to strengthen coordination  avoid duplication  and reinforce our shared commitment to the principles of subsidiarity  complementarity  and comparative advantage  which underpin the institutional architecture of the African Union.” Regarding progress in covering 100 percent of the AU’s operational budget through member states’ assessed contributions  she noted that the continent is lagging in achieving the Johannesburg targets of financing 75 percent of the program budget and 25 percent of peace support operations. She recalled that  to date  only 17 member states have implemented the Kigali decision on the levy  which requires member countries to commit to a 0.2 percent levy on all eligible imported goods to finance the continental body. The deputy chairperson commented that the lack of financing still limits the institution’s activities and success and  she reaffirmed the new leadership’s resolute stance on changing this reality  local news agency ENA reported. She urged member countries to contribute their fair share to achieve the African Union’s financial sustainability. 510 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/bc45e9c9588726fc2e2d6a6b4dd1b3bb.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/au-calls-for-accelerated-efforts-to-deepen-afcfta-implementation77288-2/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
