<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/trio-of-ethiopian-athletes-eye-5000m-world-record-in-oslo/</field>
<field name="title">Trio of Ethiopian athletes eye 5000m world record in Oslo</field>
<field name="name">Trio of Ethiopian athletes eye 5000m world record in Oslo</field>
<field name="created">2025-05-26T16:43:27Z</field>
<field name="desc">Trio of Ethiopian athletes eye 5000m world record in Oslo On May 26  2025 1 051 Addis Ababa  May 26  2025 (FMC) – Hagos Gebrhiwet  Yomif Kejelcha and Berihu Aregawi of Ethiopia are part of a star-studded field which will attack the 5000m world record at the Wanda Diamond League meeting in Oslo next month. The world’s best male 5000m runners will assemble at the Wanda Diamond League meeting in Oslo on June 12 as they continue their quest to break the world record for the first time in five years. The three Ethiopian stars Hagos Gebrhiwet  Yomif Kejelcha  Berihu Aregawi and Telahun will be joined by Kenyan rivals Jacob Krop and Nicolas Kipkorir at the Bislett Games in a field which includes eight of the top 20 ranked 5000m runners in the world. As well as valuable Diamond League points  they will all have their eyes on Joshua Cheptegei’s world record of 12 35.36  set at the Diamond League meeting in Monaco back in 2020. The record has teetered a few times in recent years  most notably at last season’s Diamond League meeting in Oslo  when Gebrhiwet missed the mark by just over a second. Fans at the Bislett Games will be hoping Gebrhiwet and his colleagues can go one better this year and notch up the Bislett Stadium’s 72nd world record. Aregawi currently leads the Diamond League standings alongside Kenya’s Reynold Cheruiyot. The Ethiopian clocked a meeting record of 12 50.45 to win in Keqiao while Cheruiyot took victory with a PB of 13 16.40 in Doha. The Wanda Diamond League is the elite one-day meeting series in global athletics. It comprises 15 of the most prestigious events in global track and field. Athletes compete for points at the 14 series meetings in a bid to qualify for the two-day Wanda Diamond League Final  which will be held in Zurich on 27 and 28 August 2025. 1 051 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/4f9e0abc036df3815cf84ac1e1d4a541.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/trio-of-ethiopian-athletes-eye-5000m-world-record-in-oslo/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
