<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/china-to-open-first-museum-of-african-culture/</field>
<field name="title">China to open first museum of African culture</field>
<field name="name">China to open first museum of African culture</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-04T00:52:57Z</field>
<field name="desc">China to open first museum of African culture On Jun 4  2025 306 Addis Ababa  June 3  2025 (FMC) — China has announced plans to open its first museum dedicated entirely to African history and culture. The announcement was made by Ye Hailin  Director of the China-Africa Institute at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences  TV BRICS reported  citing the News Agency of Nigeria (NAN). The planned museum aims to present Africa’s cultural heritage through a wide array of exhibits  including traditional artefacts  artworks  and historical narratives. According to Ye  it will serve as an important educational tool while also encouraging collaboration between Chinese and African artists  scholars  and broader communities. “The museum is expected to attract both local and international visitors  providing a unique perspective on African history that is often overlooked in traditional narratives ” he said. In addition to the museum  China is advancing plans to establish five China-Africa research centres  part of President Xi Jinping’s broader Beijing-Southeast Asia 2024 partnership strategy. One of the centres will be based in South Africa  where preliminary consultations have already taken place. 306 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/eb43dd423b8005e99a4412f86934392b.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/china-to-open-first-museum-of-african-culture/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
