<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/brics-countries-agree-on-cooperation-in-field-of-sports/</field>
<field name="title">BRICS countries agree on cooperation in field of sports</field>
<field name="name">BRICS countries agree on cooperation in field of sports</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-06T16:50:11Z</field>
<field name="desc">BRICS countries agree on cooperation in field of sports On Jun 6  2025 633 Addis Ababa  June 6  2025 (FMC) – The sports ministers of the BRICS countries have signed a memorandum of cooperation in the field of sport. It is expected that this partnership will help reduce social inequality and support economic development in the member countries of the association  TV BRICS reported today  citing the official website of the Brazilian Presidency in BRICS. Brazilian Sports Minister Andre Fufuca emphasised that physical activity unites peoples. He noted the need for investment in protecting the rights of athletes and the exchange of experience between countries. Ethiopia’s Ambassador to Brazil  Leulseged Tadese Abebe  said that sport contributes to strengthening peace  creating jobs and developing cultural ties between the group’s states. According to South African Minister of Sport  Arts and Culture  Gayton McKenzie  sport is a factor in social cohesion. He said that in South Africa  this sphere has helped to create a national identity  uniting people regardless of social and racial differences. 633 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/b39a7c4f5a13162708668c484b11ed9c.jpeg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/brics-countries-agree-on-cooperation-in-field-of-sports/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
