<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/huajian-group-emphasizes-commitment-to-job-creation-and-technology-transfer-in-ethiopia/</field>
<field name="title">Huajian Group emphasizes commitment to job creation and technology transfer in Ethiopia</field>
<field name="name">Huajian Group emphasizes commitment to job creation and technology transfer in Ethiopia</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-11T03:47:41Z</field>
<field name="desc">Huajian Group emphasizes commitment to job creation and technology transfer in Ethiopia On Jun 11  2025 1 059 Addis Ababa  June 11  2025 (FMC) — Huajian Group has reaffirmed its firm commitment to job creation  technology transfer  and mutual economic development through its pioneering investment in Ethiopia’s Geda Special Economic Zone (SEZ)  focusing on a New Energy Industrial Park project. In an exclusive interview with Fana Media Corporation  Chairman HuaRong Zhang highlighted Huajian’s role as the first company to operate in Geda SEZ  pledging to bring the company’s vast experience and success from China and the Dukem Industrial Park to foster the development of the new industrial hub. “We are dedicated to growing together with the Geda SEZ and contributing significantly to its development. Our investment aims not only to create more jobs for local people but also to introduce new technologies that will enhance skills and production capabilities ” Zhang said. Zhang stressed the company’s intention to export goods from Ethiopia while ensuring that technology transfer empowers local workers and strengthens Ethiopia’s manufacturing base. “This is a shared journey ” he said  “and we commit to sharing the outcomes of economic development with the local communities to achieve mutual prosperity.” Recognizing the importance of supportive governance  Zhang called on both the Oromia regional and Ethiopian federal governments to provide strong  practical support to foreign investors. “Government facilitation  infrastructure  and a welcoming investment environment are essential to sustaining long-term growth ” he noted. Emphasizing the principle of mutual consensus  negotiation  and cooperation  Zhang said  “Achieving win-win results requires a foundation of trust and joint development between all stakeholders. We believe this approach is vital for building a high-efficiency industrial park.” Zhang further expressed confidence in the deepening economic cooperation between Ethiopia and China  especially in finance and investment sectors. He praised Ethiopia’s macroeconomic reforms  describing them as critical to revitalizing foreign investment opportunities and improving the overall business climate. “We advocate for a more open and practical environment that protects foreign investors and encourages sustainable growth. Such a framework will enable Ethiopia to fully harness its industrial potential ” Zhang concluded. Huajian Group’s latest $100 million solar production project in Geda SEZ underscores its long-term commitment to Ethiopia’s industrialization ambitions  job creation  and green energy development — reinforcing the deep bilateral ties between Ethiopia and China. 1 059 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/93eae211f35f1f5bf01450ae9b973062.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/huajian-group-emphasizes-commitment-to-job-creation-and-technology-transfer-in-ethiopia/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
