<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/govt-committed-to-ensuring-lasting-peace-in-ethiopia-pm-abiy/</field>
<field name="title">Gov’t committed to ensuring lasting peace in Ethiopia  PM Abiy</field>
<field name="name">Gov’t committed to ensuring lasting peace in Ethiopia  PM Abiy</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-04T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Gov’t committed to ensuring lasting peace in Ethiopia  PM Abiy On Jun 14  2025 240 Addis Ababa  June 14  2025 (FMC) – Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed has affirmed the government’s unwavering commitment to achieving lasting peace across Ethiopia. The Prime Minister made the remarks during a nationwide consultation held with teachers from across the country  where he elaborated on the government’s ongoing efforts to promote peace and stability. Highlighting key initiatives  the Prime Minister recalled the establishment of the Ministry of Peace as a major step toward institutionalizing the peace process. He also noted the government’s continuous efforts to resolve conflicts through dialogue  particularly with armed groups. Despite some groups rejecting calls for peace  the Prime Minister emphasized that dialogue remains the only viable path forward. He urged those still outside the peace process to recognize that lasting solutions can only be achieved through discussion and negotiation. Demonstrating its commitment  the government has welcomed those who laid down arms and opted for peaceful reintegration  allowing them to participate in the political process. Abiy underlined that Ethiopia’s door remains open to all who wish to resolve issues through dialogue and to those who believe they have better ideas to contribute. However  he cautioned that law enforcement actions will continue against groups that persist in violence—such as taking hostages or disrupting public services  including the closure of schools. The Prime Minister cited the Pretoria Agreement as a concrete example of the government’s resolve to pursue peace through negotiation and compromise. “Ethiopia needs peace ” he underscored  reaffirming the government’s determination to reach this goal. He concluded by stressing the importance of working together with all peace-seeking actors and involving them meaningfully in the national peacebuilding process. 240 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/dcf0f4a2380ab53cf2c172749d9e5fd7.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/govt-committed-to-ensuring-lasting-peace-in-ethiopia-pm-abiy/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
