<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/scholars-emphasize-ethiopias-just-and-strategic-pursuit-of-sea-access-as-essential-for-future-generations/</field>
<field name="title">Scholars emphasize Ethiopia’s just and strategic pursuit of sea access as essential for future generations</field>
<field name="name">Scholars emphasize Ethiopia’s just and strategic pursuit of sea access as essential for future generations</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-14T09:53:19Z</field>
<field name="desc">Scholars emphasize Ethiopia’s just and strategic pursuit of sea access as essential for future generations On Jun 14  2025 901 Addis Ababa  June 14  2025 (FMC) — Ethiopian scholars have underscored the country’s ongoing pursuit of sea access as a fair and vital national objective  essential not only for current development but also for safeguarding the future of coming generations. Despite being the most populous nation in East Africa and one of the continent’s fastest-growing economies  Ethiopia remains landlocked—a condition that continues to pose significant challenges to its economic trajectory and strategic autonomy. Citing global studies  experts noted that countries with direct access to the sea tend to experience two to three percent higher annual economic growth. The lack of a maritime outlet  therefore  not only limits Ethiopia’s economic potential but also affects its broader geopolitical and security positioning. Amare Kenaw  lead researcher at the Institute of Foreign Affairs  emphasized that Ethiopia’s demand for access to the sea transcends economic rationale. “It is a matter of sovereignty  long-term national security  and generational equity ” he stated. He further argued that Ethiopia’s approach—anchored in mutual benefit and regional cooperation—has garnered increasing understanding from international institutions and policymakers  especially in light of the country’s geographic proximity to the Red Sea. “Ethiopia has maintained a close watch on Red Sea developments ” Amare told state-affiliated local news agency ENA  adding that the Institute of Foreign Affairs continues to raise awareness and provide evidence-based recommendations on the matter. Expressing cautious optimism  Amare said he hopes Ethiopia’s legitimate and peaceful quest will be addressed constructively  through dialogue that also respects the interests of neighboring countries. Echoing similar sentiments  Professor Jeilu Omar  Vice President for Academic Affairs at Addis Ababa University  called Ethiopia’s demand for a sea outlet both appropriate and achievable. “The principle of give-and-take must guide these discussions ” he noted. Professor Jeilu also highlighted the critical role of academic institutions in producing rigorous research to support national efforts and in educating younger generations on the strategic importance of maritime access. 901 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/97a36ce986c0fa6c89b3b8007cd5cfbb.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/scholars-emphasize-ethiopias-just-and-strategic-pursuit-of-sea-access-as-essential-for-future-generations/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
