<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/ethiopian-athletes-shine-as-eisa-and-barega-claim-dominant-victories-at-great-manchester-run/</field>
<field name="title">Ethiopian Athletes Shine as Eisa and Barega Claim Dominant Victories at Great Manchester Run</field>
<field name="name">Ethiopian Athletes Shine as Eisa and Barega Claim Dominant Victories at Great Manchester Run</field>
<field name="created">2025-05-19T00:17:14Z</field>
<field name="desc">Ethiopian Athletes Shine as Eisa and Barega Claim Dominant Victories at Great Manchester Run On May 19  2025 919 Addis Ababa  May 18  2025 (FMC) — Ethiopian long-distance stars Medina Eisa and Selemon Barega delivered outstanding performances at the 2025 AJ Bell Great Manchester Run on Sunday  each claiming convincing victories in the 10km races and securing a memorable double win for the nation. Medina Eisa  the reigning world U20 5000m champion and seventh-place finisher in the 5000m at the Tokyo Olympics  produced a stunning run to win the women’s 10km race in 30 42. Her performance saw her pull away from a highly competitive field on a clear and bright morning in north-west England. Starting as part of a nine-woman lead group that included former world champion Gotytom Gebreslase and Kenya’s Hellen Obiri  Eisa made a decisive move after the halfway mark. After a steady 5km split of 15 36  she surged ahead with back-to-back kilometers of 2 59 and 2 58  breaking away as she passed the iconic Old Trafford stadium. She closed the second half in a remarkable 15 08  finishing well ahead of her rivals. The USA’s Emily Sisson finished second in 31 03  overtaking both Obiri and Gebreslase in the final stages. In the men’s race  Olympic 10 000m champion Selemon Barega showcased his versatility and tactical brilliance with a powerful late surge to take victory in 27 49. Though headwinds on parts of the course made record-chasing difficult  Barega remained undeterred  asserting control in the final kilometre against a strong field that included defending champion Vincent Ngetich of Kenya and rising Uruguayan talent Santiago Catrofe. This marks Barega’s first 10km road race since winning the Great Ethiopian Run in 2017. Since then  his track career has reached remarkable heights—including Olympic gold in Tokyo—but the 24-year-old is now turning his focus increasingly toward road racing. Over 30 000 participants took part in the various waves of the event  which also featured half marathon competitions. The symbolic starting gun was fired by three generations of Olympic 800m champions  Ann Packer (1964)  Kelly Holmes (2004)  and Keely Hodgkinson (2024). 919 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/ca1d4955b5cb50410bb2d0ea53c547ac.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/ethiopian-athletes-shine-as-eisa-and-barega-claim-dominant-victories-at-great-manchester-run/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
