<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/science-museums-permanent-exhibition-section-inaugurated-in-presence-of-pm-abiy-ahmed/</field>
<field name="title">Science Museum’s Permanent Exhibition Section Inaugurated in Presence of PM Abiy Ahmed</field>
<field name="name">Science Museum’s Permanent Exhibition Section Inaugurated in Presence of PM Abiy Ahmed</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-04T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Science Museum’s Permanent Exhibition Section Inaugurated in Presence of PM Abiy Ahmed On Jun 14  2025 477 Addis Ababa  June 14  2025 (FMC) – Prime Minister Abiy Ahmed attended the official launch of the Permanent Exhibition Section at Ethiopia’s Science Museum  marking a major milestone in the country’s drive to promote science and technology-led development. According to the Office of the Prime Minister  the newly inaugurated section features five immersive exhibition zones dedicated to artificial intelligence  climate change and Ethiopia’s response  agriculture  hydropower  and aeronautics and aviation. Each area offers an interactive learning experience designed to inspire innovation and scientific inquiry among visitors. A highlight of the launch was the unveiling of Ethiopia’s first Planetarium Dome — a pioneering facility spanning over 1 000 square meters with a 36-meter diameter. Equipped with advanced 4K digital projection systems  the dome accommodates over 200 visitors and provides high-resolution  immersive views of the cosmos. The Science Museum is now fully open to the public  offering an inspiring space where citizens — especially young people — can explore cutting-edge technologies and envision Ethiopia’s future through science. 477 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/ba5296fd0557e30d4a70899f98cfaa75.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/science-museums-permanent-exhibition-section-inaugurated-in-presence-of-pm-abiy-ahmed/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
