<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/unhcr-chief-applauds-ethiopias-refugee-inclusion-efforts-urges-greater-global-support/</field>
<field name="title">UNHCR chief applauds Ethiopia’s refugee inclusion efforts  urges greater global support</field>
<field name="name">UNHCR chief applauds Ethiopia’s refugee inclusion efforts  urges greater global support</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T23:59:51Z</field>
<field name="desc">UNHCR chief applauds Ethiopia’s refugee inclusion efforts  urges greater global support On Jun 13  2025 846 Addis Ababa  June 13  2025 (FMC) — United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees  Mr. Filippo Grandi  has praised Ethiopia for its progressive and inclusive approach to refugee protection  calling it a model for the region and the broader international community. Speaking at the High-Level Dialogue on Advancing Refugee Inclusion and Support to Host Communities held in Addis Ababa  Grandi highlighted Ethiopia’s decades-long partnership with UNHCR and its enduring commitment to providing refuge for people fleeing conflict and instability. “Ethiopia has long been a generous host to refugees  not only in policy but also in practice across all sectors of society ” Grandi stated. “What I see here is a pioneering  forward-looking approach that integrates refugees into national systems — something that many countries can learn from.” Grandi commended Ethiopia’s application of the principles of the Global Compact on Refugees  noting that with adequate resources and sound policies in place  tangible results are being achieved. “Progress is visible in Ethiopia. Even amid the challenges of recent years  the country remains a destination for refugees — and that deserves international recognition.” Reflecting on his recent visit to the Melkadida refugee site in southern Ethiopia  the High Commissioner described witnessing “incredible humanity” and commended the country’s comprehensive inclusion strategies — from legal documentation and digital ID registration to access to education  health care  and financial services. He welcomed the government’s shift from traditional humanitarian responses toward development-oriented  resilient approaches. In particular  he highlighted the “Makatet” model — a locally driven strategy promoting food self-sufficiency and reduced aid dependency — as a commendable innovation that could inspire similar models elsewhere. Grandi stressed that Ethiopia’s example should be amplified globally  and he urged international donors and stakeholders to increase financial  technical  and political support. “We must reinforce the nexus between humanitarian and development aid. Declining support jeopardizes progress  especially in a volatile region affected by conflict and climate change.” Calling on the private sector  international organizations  and other governments to follow Ethiopia’s lead  he emphasized the need to scale inclusive strategies that empower both refugees and host communities. “Ethiopia is doing its part. Now  the world must do the same ” he concluded. 846 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/57147b287c5067529c32213dd2fa809c.png</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/unhcr-chief-applauds-ethiopias-refugee-inclusion-efforts-urges-greater-global-support/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
