<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/new-book-on-legendary-athlete-haile-gebre-selassie-slated-for-august-launch/</field>
<field name="title">New book on legendary athlete Haile Gebre-Selassie slated for August launch</field>
<field name="name">New book on legendary athlete Haile Gebre-Selassie slated for August launch</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">New book on legendary athlete Haile Gebre-Selassie slated for August launch On Jun 7  2025 719 Addis Ababa  June 7  2025 (FMC) – A book titled ”Dissecting Haile”  which delves into the life and experiences of the renowned Ethiopian athlete Haile Gebre-Selassie  authored by his daughter Melat  is set to be released in August of this year. During a media briefing held this morning  Melat revealed that she  along with her co-author  the Pan-African youth statesman  innovator  and author Abayomi Rotimi Mighty  dedicated over a year to the preparation of this book  which comprises 12 chapters. The briefing highlighted that the book provides an unprecedented and intimate examination of Haile Gebre-Selassie’s life  recognizing him as one of the most remarkable athletes and visionary entrepreneurs of our era. It was noted that the book transcends mere headlines  offering a distinctive viewpoint on the universal values of discipline  resilience  and purpose that have driven his extraordinary achievements in athletics and his lasting influence in business and philanthropy. Additionally  it was mentioned that the book explores Haile’s humble beginnings and his ascent to becoming a global icon  featuring untold stories and offering a profound insight into the mindset that revolutionized long-distance running. Moreover  the media briefing suggested that readers will uncover Haile’s seldom-shared philosophies and tactics for overcoming challenges  setting world records  and establishing a lasting legacy through this book. The media briefing confirmed that the book launch is scheduled for August of this year and will be graced by high-ranking dignitaries and other key stakeholders  as reported by ENA. 719 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/8d4146d5682fa44a5369d22afaa37601.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/new-book-on-legendary-athlete-haile-gebre-selassie-slated-for-august-launch/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
