<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/auc-chairperson-bill-gates-underline-need-for-global-solidarity-fair-trade-and-investment-in-african-innovation/</field>
<field name="title">AUC Chairperson  Bill Gates underline need for global solidarity  fair trade  and investment in African innovation</field>
<field name="name">AUC Chairperson  Bill Gates underline need for global solidarity  fair trade  and investment in African innovation</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">AUC Chairperson  Bill Gates underline need for global solidarity  fair trade  and investment in African innovation On Jun 2  2025 604 Addis Ababa  June 2  2025 (FMC) – African Union Commission Chairperson Mahmoud Ali Youssouf and Bill Gates  Co-Chair and Trustee of the Gates Foundation  have jointly reaffirmed the urgent need for global solidarity  fair trade  and greater investment in African-led innovation  governance  and resilience. The statement followed a high-level meeting held this morning at the AU Headquarters in Addis Ababa  where the two dignitaries discussed ways to strengthen collaboration between the AU and the Gates Foundation. Their talks focused on improving Africa’s health systems  scaling up local vaccine and medicine production  and enhancing food security across the continent. Chairperson Youssouf raised serious concerns about global aid reductions and unfulfilled climate finance pledges. Bill Gates echoed the concerns  noting Africa’s marginal contribution to global emissions and the unfair treatment it receives in global climate discussions. He pledged to continue advocating for sustained international support and deeper  equitable partnerships with African institutions. The AUC Chairperson and the U.S. billionaire emphasized that lasting progress in Africa requires a global commitment to empowering homegrown solutions and ensuring fair access to resources and opportunities. 604 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/52f05d0d2996c8958b4a43200045d234.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/auc-chairperson-bill-gates-underline-need-for-global-solidarity-fair-trade-and-investment-in-african-innovation/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
