<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/conference-highlights-need-for-collaboration-in-cybersecurity-and-digital-transformation-in-ethiopia/</field>
<field name="title">Conference highlights need for collaboration in cybersecurity and digital transformation in Ethiopia</field>
<field name="name">Conference highlights need for collaboration in cybersecurity and digital transformation in Ethiopia</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Conference highlights need for collaboration in cybersecurity and digital transformation in Ethiopia On Jun 14  2025 582 Addis Ababa  June 14  2025 (FMC) – A national conference on cybersecurity and digital transformation is underway in Addis Ababa  bringing together key stakeholders to discuss integrating security principles into digital systems and enhancing collaboration across sectors. Opening the two-day forum  State Minister of Innovation and Technology Fozia Amin underscored the importance of adopting a “cybersecurity by design” approach—embedding security frameworks into systems from the early stages of development through implementation and operation. She emphasized that securing digital infrastructure is vital for the smooth functioning of all sectors and that integrating robust cybersecurity from the outset builds trust among users  investors  educational institutions  and the wider public. “People and organizations will embrace the digital economy when they feel secure about their digital engagement ” Fozia said  adding that the burden of securing the digital space cannot fall on a single ministry  agency  or even country. Given the transboundary nature of cyber threats  she called for strong cooperation among government bodies  private sector actors  academia  civil society  and international partners to build a safe and resilient digital ecosystem. Fozia also highlighted the need to cultivate local innovation and talent to stay ahead of evolving threats  encouraging research and knowledge-sharing that will shape both domestic policy and global cybersecurity understanding. Regional Director for Africa at the International Telecommunication Union (ITU)  Emmanuel Manasseh  echoed these points  noting that connectivity underpins digital transformation. As such  rising connectivity must be matched with robust cybersecurity measures to safeguard users. President of the Ethiopian Cyber Security Association  Berhanu Beyene  further stressed the importance of comprehensive policies  strategies  and long-term engagement in addressing cybersecurity challenges. “Collaboration is one of the crucial elements in securing our digital assets and critical infrastructure ” he said  calling for both national and global efforts to meet the challenges of the evolving threat landscape. The conference  according to ENA  continues tomorrow  with sessions focused on innovation  capacity building  and regional cooperation in cyber resilience. 582 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/fb2e1379f7adc065e87b4acb1eaeffee.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/conference-highlights-need-for-collaboration-in-cybersecurity-and-digital-transformation-in-ethiopia/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
