<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/brazil-unveils-biodiversity-strategy-to-restore-12-million-hectares-by-2030/</field>
<field name="title">Brazil unveils biodiversity strategy to restore 12 million hectares by 2030</field>
<field name="name">Brazil unveils biodiversity strategy to restore 12 million hectares by 2030</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T13:07:24Z</field>
<field name="desc">Brazil unveils biodiversity strategy to restore 12 million hectares by 2030 On Jun 13  2025 166 Addis Ababa  June 13  2025 (FMC) – Brazil has launched a renewed national strategy to protect biodiversity and restore ecosystems  aiming to recover 12 million hectares of native vegetation by 2030. The new Brazil’s National Biodiversity Strategy and Action Plan was signed into law on 3 June by President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva and Environment and Climate Change Minister Marina Silva. This is reported by the official website of Brazil’s Ministry of Environment. The updated action plan outlines 25 national targets and replaces the 2017 version. Key objectives include halting illegal deforestation  preventing the conversion of native vegetation  and advancing spatial planning across terrestrial and marine areas. The strategy also addresses species protection  habitat restoration  the reduction of invasive species  pollution control  and minimising climate change impacts on biodiversity. The policy emphasises inclusive participation  recognising the essential role of Indigenous peoples  traditional communities  and family farmers in preserving biodiversity through sustainable practices and traditional knowledge. Monitoring will be led by the Ministry of the Environment and Climate Change. An implementation plan will be finalised within 90 days  and the current strategy will remain in effect until 2030  with updates scheduled every ten years  TV BRICS reported. 166 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/2370735dc749d05cb111f5e983406483.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/brazil-unveils-biodiversity-strategy-to-restore-12-million-hectares-by-2030/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
