<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.fanamc.www:https/english/brics-parliamentary-representatives-call-for-reform-of-global-governance/</field>
<field name="title">BRICS parliamentary representatives call for reform of global governance</field>
<field name="name">BRICS parliamentary representatives call for reform of global governance</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-07T18:56:06Z</field>
<field name="desc">BRICS parliamentary representatives call for reform of global governance On Jun 7  2025 549 Addis Ababa  June 7  2025 (FMC) – The 11th BRICS Parliamentary Forum was held in Brasilia. Delegations from 16 countries  including BRICS members and invited states  took part in the event. Brazil was represented at the opening of the forum by Davi Alcolumbre  President of the Federal Senate (upper house) of the Brazilian National Congress. In his speech  he called for reform of the international security architecture  strengthening of national health systems and the development of rules in the field of artificial intelligence. Alcolumbre recalled that BRICS countries account for 40 per cent of global GDP and separately noted the active participation of women parliamentarians in the forum  calling it an important achievement. Brazilian Vice President Geraldo Alckmin also delivered a speech. He outlined the priorities of Brazil’s presidency of BRICS  including the formation of a pandemic response mechanism  the expansion of settlements in national currencies  and the financing of projects by the New Development Bank (NDB). Alckmin called for the strengthening of parliamentary ties and collective action in the areas of global security and health. Indonesia was represented at the forum by House of Representatives (DPR) legislator Mardani Ali Sera. He stressed the importance of deepening cooperation in the areas of trade  investment  finance and technology  and noted BRICS’ desire to strengthen multilateral cooperation. “In addition  BRICS member nations have been promoting the use of local currencies in trade among them as a strategic measure to bolster economic resilience ” he pointed out. Deputy Head of Inter-Parliamentary Cooperation Agency (BKSAP) Hussein Fadluloh  in turn  said that Indonesia is interested in implementing joint projects on investment and technology transfer  especially in the context of the national policy on deep processing of raw materials. Belarus was represented at the forum by Sergey Rachkov  Chairperson of the Standing Commission of the House of Representatives of the National Assembly of Belarus. He stated that the republic aims to become a full member of BRICS and is interested in expanding cooperation with the association in the areas of food  mechanical engineering  and agricultural technology. Rachkov also noted the importance of BRICS as a platform reflecting the interests of the Global South. Delegations from Russia  India  China  South Africa  Iran  the UAE  Nigeria  Cuba  Egypt  Bolivia  and Ethiopia also participated in the forum. A joint declaration was adopted at the end of the forum  TV BRICS reported. 549 </field>
<field name="tag">fanabcen</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/fanabcen/2025_Jun/3e338696734d6847f7daeb5e127fd5e0.jpeg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.fanamc.com/english/brics-parliamentary-representatives-call-for-reform-of-global-governance/</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
