<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/russia-returns-1200-bodies-of-fallen-ukrainian-soldiers</field>
<field name="title">Russia returns 1 200 bodies of fallen Ukrainian soldiers</field>
<field name="name">Russia returns 1 200 bodies of fallen Ukrainian soldiers</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T20:23:25Z</field>
<field name="desc">News | Russia-Ukraine war Russia returns 1 200 bodies of fallen Ukrainian soldiers Moscow says Kyiv failed to return any prisoners in the latest exchange  as fighting continues on the ground. People hold up photos of their missing relatives to Ukrainian soldiers returning after a POW exchange between Russia and Ukraine. [Efrem Lukatsky/ AP] Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 Russia has returned the bodies of 1 200 Ukrainian soldiers to Kyiv   marking one of the largest repatriations of remains since the war began more than three years ago. The return on Friday was made following an agreement reached during peace talks in Istanbul last month. However  Moscow has claimed this latest exchange was one-sided  claiming that Ukraine has failed to return the bodies of its fallen soldiers. “Today  Russia handed over 1 200 bodies of deceased soldiers of the Ukrainian armed forces to Ukraine. Not a single one was handed over to us ” an unnamed source told Russia’s state-run TASS news agency. Russian presidential aide Vladimir Medinsky also claimed that Ukraine suddenly postponed the handover of remains and prisoner exchanges on June 7  without offering a public explanation. Ukraine’s Coordination Headquarters for the Treatment of Prisoners of War said in a statement on Friday that forensic experts will now work to identify the remains they received  adding that the bodies were believed to be those of Ukrainian military personnel. Advertisement Earlier this week  Russia returned another 1 212 bodies and received just 27 bodies of its own troops in return. Despite tensions  both sides have agreed in principle to exchange up to 6 000 bodies and prioritise the release of sick and severely wounded prisoners of war  as well as those under the age of 25. EU protection for Ukrainian refugees Meanwhile  as the war continues between Russia and Ukraine  the European Union has extended its temporary protection scheme for Ukrainian refugees by another year  allowing them to remain in the bloc until March 2027. The EU’s move  announced on Friday  comes amid ongoing air raids and strikes across Ukraine  which have displaced millions since the start of Russia’s invasion in February 2022. More than 4.3 million Ukrainians are currently registered under the scheme  with Germany  Poland  and the Czech Republic hosting the largest refugee populations. “While Russia continues to terrorise Ukrainian civilians with indiscriminate air strikes  the EU continues to show its solidarity ” said Tomasz Siemoniak  Poland’s interior minister. “We will continue to offer protection for millions of Ukrainian refugees for another year.” Fighting continues Heavy fighting continued across the front line on Friday  with new casualties reported in both Ukraine and Russia. In Russia’s Belgorod region  a two-year-old boy was killed and two adults  including his grandmother  were wounded in what officials said was a Ukrainian drone strike overnight  according to Governor Vyacheslav Gladkov. Advertisement Russia’s Ministry of Defence claimed it had intercepted 260 Ukrainian drones over the past 24 hours  while over the past week  Moscow says its air defences downed a Neptune long-range missile  18 JDAM guided bombs  nine US-made HIMARS rockets  and 1 582 fixed-wing drones from Ukraine. In Zaporizhzhia  Ukrainian Governor Ivan Fedorov reported one person killed and three injured in Russian shelling  while in Donetsk  Ukrainian Governor Vadym Filashkin said two civilians were killed and five injured across the region. It comes after the Ukrainian military said it had struck the Rezonit electronics factory near Moscow  triggering explosions. The General Staff of the Armed Forces of Ukraine later reported 113 Russian assaults across key fronts  including in Lyman  Pokrovsk  Novopavlivka and Kurakhove. Source  Al Jazeera and news agencies aj-logo </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/5f2ee20ad8b0cdbb8f8963e7109c61d3.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/russia-returns-1200-bodies-of-fallen-ukrainian-soldiers</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
