<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/iran-to-double-down-on-nuclear-programme-after-israeli-strikes-analysts</field>
<field name="title">Israel strikes may make Iran more determined to pursue nuclear programme</field>
<field name="name">Israel strikes may make Iran more determined to pursue nuclear programme</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T21:21:41Z</field>
<field name="desc">News | Nuclear Weapons Israel strikes may make Iran more determined to pursue nuclear programme Analysts believe that Iran may accelerate efforts to acquire a nuclear bomb as it faces a major Israeli assault. Rescuers work at the site of a damaged building  in the aftermath of Israeli strikes  in Tehran  Iran  June 13  2025 [Iranian Red Crescent Society/WANA] By Mat Nashed Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 Israel’s attacks on Iranian nuclear and military sites mark a significant escalation in regional tensions  and may reshape Tehran’s nuclear calculus. The coordinated strikes killed several senior military and security officials  including the head of Iran’s military Mohammad Bagheri   and the head of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC)  Hossein Salami . Recommended Stories Israel may have just pushed Iran across the nuclear line end of list “One of the concerns in attacking the nuclear sites has been that setbacks could lead Iran to reconstitute their operations with a more determined effort to obtain a nuclear deterrent ” said Ali Vaez  an expert on Iran for the International Crisis Group (ICG). Sceptics validated Iran has long had an internal debate among reformers and hardliners about whether to reach an agreement with the United States on its nuclear programme. “[The attacks] likely confirmed the position of hardliners and ultra hardliners who said that Iran was wasting its time to try and negotiate with the West … they said Iran can never negotiate from a position of weakness and appeasement ” said Reza H Akbari  an analyst on Iran and the Middle East and North Africa Programme Manager at the Institute for War and Peace Reporting. Advertisement Talks between Iran and the US have suffered from a large trust deficit after President Donald Trump unilaterally pulled out of the nuclear deal between Iran and several Western nations  known as the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA)  during his first term in 2018. The JCPOA was orchestrated by Trump’s predecessor Barack Obama and endorsed by the United Nations Security Council in 2015. It aimed to monitor Iran’s nuclear programme to ensure it did not approach weaponisation levels. In exchange  some sanctions were lifted from Iran. While the deal was lauded as an achievement of diplomacy  Israel disapproved of the JCPOA. Ten years later  the US and Iran appeared interested in striking another similar deal. The former ostensibly did not want to get dragged into a regional war as tensions mounted across the Middle East  while the latter was again looking for much-needed sanction relief. But Israel’s strikes on Iran   which were reportedly planned months in advance and with US approval  have scuttled any diplomatic solution in the short term  said Akbari. “It’s hard to imagine that someone in the shoes of Iran’s supreme leader [Ali Khamenei] is not taking the side of hardliners after this ” he told Al Jazeera. Iran’s Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei speaks during a meeting in Tehran  Iran  May 20  2025 [File  Office of the Iranian Supreme Leader/WANA/Handout via Reuters] No other options In response to Israel’s strikes  Iran has launched drones and ballistic missiles at Israel  with some hitting targets on the ground. Advertisement In the past  Iran’s deterrence against external aggression relied primarily on its self-described “Axis of Resistance”. The axis consisted of powerful armed groups across the region  such as Lebanon’s Hezbollah  as well as Syria under former President Bashar al-Assad. However  Hezbollah’s capabilities were degraded significantly during the peak of its recent war with Israel  which lasted from September to late November last year. Al-Assad’s fall in December  the culmination of a more than decade-long civil war in Syria  also compromised Iran’s ability to resupply Hezbollah through Syria  as it used to do. Trump is now exploiting Iran’s weakness by urging it to capitulate to a deal that would see it give up its nuclear programme  said Michael Stephens  an expert on regional response to Iran’s nuclear programme with the Royal United Service Institute (RUSI)  a defence think tank. On Friday  Trump posted on Truth Social that Iran must make a deal before there is “nothing left” of the country and that the next Israeli attacks will be even “more brutal”. Later that evening  Israel carried out more air strikes on Iran’s military sites and nuclear facilities. “There are no good options for [Iran] really ” said Stephens. “Either Khamenei … orders his negotiators to compromise on the nuclear file or … he holds firm [and] more sites are hit and further targeted assassinations of high-level officials take place ” he told Al Jazeera. “Either way  if Iran decides to sprint towards a bomb  it’s going to be very  very difficult to do that now ” he added. Advertisement Last stand Despite Iran’s military weakness compared with the US and Israel  it is wary of giving up its nuclear programme  analysts told Al Jazeera. Negar Mortazavi  an expert on Iran with the Centre for International Policy (CIP)  said Iranian officials have long referred to the fate of former Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi  who agreed to give up his nuclear weapons programme in exchange for US sanction relief in 2003. The deal came after the US President George W Bush had launched his so-called “War on Terror” after the September 11  2001  attacks  which led to the invasion and prolonged occupation of Iraq and Afghanistan. At the time  Bush warned his partners and foes in the region that they were either “with us or against us”. Former US President George W. Bush  right  with Vice President Dick Cheney at his side  speaks during a meeting with congressional leaders in the White House Oval Office on September 18  2002 [File  Doug Mills/AP] Eight years after Gaddafi gave up his nuclear programme  the US backed a pro-democracy uprising in Libya  which spiralled into an armed rebellion and led to Gaddafi’s overthrow and eventual death. “The [Libya] scenario is something that Iran has taken notice of  and they don’t want to go down that path ” Mortazavi explained. She added that Iran may likely pull out from the JCPOA and try to quickly expand its nuclear programme in reaction to Israel’s ongoing assault. “Just how far and how soon Iran will expand its nuclear programme is unclear ” Mortazavi told Al Jazeera. Advertisement </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/e4db529c241765fa9de99d8840c1248e.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/iran-to-double-down-on-nuclear-programme-after-israeli-strikes-analysts</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
