<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/un-officials-urge-israel-iran-to-show-restraint-at-emergency-meeting</field>
<field name="title">UN officials urge Israel  Iran to show ‘restraint’ at emergency meeting</field>
<field name="name">UN officials urge Israel  Iran to show ‘restraint’ at emergency meeting</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T22:13:29Z</field>
<field name="desc">News | Nuclear Weapons UN officials urge Israel  Iran to show ‘restraint’ at emergency meeting Iran’s UN envoy told the Security Council Israel’s attack amounts to a ‘declaration of war’ and promised a ‘decisive’ response. Iran s Ambassador and Permanent Representative Amir Saeid Iravani attends a meeting of the United Nations Security Council  at the UN s headquarters in New York City  US  June 13 [Eduardo Munoz/Reuters] Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 Israel’s aerial assault on Iran has destroyed the above-ground enrichment plant at Natanz  where there is now “contamination”  according to Rafael Grossi  chief of the United Nations nuclear watchdog. Grossi delivered the update during an emergency UN Security Council meeting in New York on Friday  where he and other senior UN officials urged both Israel and Iran to show restraint to prevent a deeper regional conflict. Recommended Stories Iran fires wave of missiles toward Israel in retaliatory strike end of list “I have repeatedly stated that nuclear facilities should never be attacked regardless of the context or circumstances  as it could harm both people and the environment ” said Grossi  who heads the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA). He reported radiological and chemical contamination inside the Natanz facility  where Iran was producing uranium enriched up to 60 percent. However  he added that the contamination is “manageable with appropriate measures”  and said the IAEA is ready to send nuclear security experts to help secure the sites if requested. “I call on all parties to exercise maximum restraint to avoid further escalation ” he added. Israel’s Ambassador Danny Danon listens to IAEA Director General Rafael Grossi on screen during a meeting of the United Nations Security Council  in New York  US  June 13 [Eduardo Munoz/Reuters] UN Undersecretary-General for Political Affairs Rosemary DiCarlo also urged both sides to show “maximum restraint at this critical moment”. Advertisement “A peaceful resolution through negotiations remains the best means to ensure the peaceful nature of Iran’s nuclear programme ” she told the council. “We must at all costs avoid a growing conflagration which would have enormous global consequences.” Israeli ‘declaration of war’ The 15-member Security Council  also joined by representatives of Israel and Iran  met at Iran’s request after Israel struck several Iranian nuclear facilities and military sites in the early hours of Friday  and carried out assassinations of senior military officials and nuclear scientists. Iran’s UN Envoy Amir Saeid Iravani told the emergency meeting that the attacks  which he described as a “declaration of war” and “a direct assault on international order”  had killed 78 people and injured more than 320. He accused the US of providing Israel with both intelligence and political support for the attacks  the consequences of which he said it “shares full responsibility” for. “Supporting Israel today is supporting war crimes ” he said. The US representative  McCoy Pitt  insisted the US was not involved militarily in the strikes  but defended them as necessary for the self-defence of Israel. He warned that the “consequences for Iran would be dire” if it targeted US bases or citizens in retaliation. “Iran’s leadership would be wise to negotiate at this time ” he said. ‘How long did the world expect us to wait?’ Israel’s UN envoy Danny Danon cast its attack on Iran’s nuclear sites as “an act of national preservation”  claiming Iran was days away from producing enough fissile material for multiple bombs. Advertisement “This operation was carried out because the alternative was unthinkable ” said Danon. “How long did the world expect us to wait? Until they assemble the bomb? Until they mount it on a Shahab missile? Until it is en route to Tel Aviv or Jerusalem?” “We will not hesitate  we will not relent  and we will not allow a genocidal regime to endanger our people ” said Danon An Iranian counterattack on Israel took place while the UN meeting was in progress  with Iran firing waves of ballistic missiles at Israeli targets. “Iran affirms its inherent right to self-defence ” said Iran’s Iravani  promising to respond “decisively and proportionately” against Israel. “This is not a threat  this is the natural  legal and necessary consequence of an unprovoked military act ” he said. Vassily Nebenzia  Russia’s UN ambassador  told the council Israel’s actions in the Middle East are “pushing the region to a large-scale nuclear catastrophe”. “This completely unprovoked attack  no matter what Israel says to the contrary  is a gross violation of the UN Charter and international law ” he said. Source  Al Jazeera and news agencies aj-logo </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/d1b79feefb8b427727842a80b0a7da9b.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/un-officials-urge-israel-iran-to-show-restraint-at-emergency-meeting</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
