<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/opinions/2025/6/13/israel-may-have-just-pushed-iran-across-the-nuclear-line</field>
<field name="title">Israel may have just pushed Iran across the nuclear line</field>
<field name="name">Israel may have just pushed Iran across the nuclear line</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T16:49:12Z</field>
<field name="desc">Opinions | Nuclear Weapons Israel may have just pushed Iran across the nuclear line The strikes meant to prevent Iran from going nuclear may instead push it to build the bomb – and draw the region into wider conflict. By Ibrahim Al-Marashi and Mohammad Eslami Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 This picture shows a building damaged in an Israeli strike on Tehran on June 13  2025  during a wave of attacks that hit about 100 targets [Meghdad Madadi/Tasnim News via AFP] Historians may well mark June 13  2025  as the day the world crossed a line it may not easily step back from. In a move that shocked the international community and sent global markets reeling  Israel launched a wide-scale military operation against Iran in the early hours of the morning  striking targets across at least 12 provinces  including the capital  Tehran  and the northwestern hub of Tabriz. Among the targets were suspected nuclear facilities  air defence systems  and the homes and offices of senior military personnel. Iranian state media confirmed the deaths of several top commanders in the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC). The Israeli government officially confirmed responsibility for the attacks  naming the campaign Operation Raising Lion. Iranian officials described it as the most direct act of war in the countries’ decades-long shadow conflict. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu appears to be pursuing two objectives. First  Israeli officials fear that Iran is nearing the technical capability to build a nuclear weapon – something Netanyahu has repeatedly promised to prevent  by force if necessary. Second  Israel hopes a dramatic escalation will pressure Tehran into accepting a new nuclear agreement more favourable to United States and Israeli interests  including the removal of its enriched uranium stockpiles. Just as Netanyahu has failed to destroy Hamas through military force  both goals may ultimately serve only to perpetuate a broader regional war. Advertisement While the prospect of all-out war between Iran and Israel has long loomed  Friday’s events feel dangerously different. The scale  audacity and implications of the attack – and the near-certain Iranian response – raise the spectre of a regional conflict spilling far beyond its traditional bounds. Since the 2011 Arab Spring  a Saudi-Iranian cold war has played out across the region as each country has sought to expand its influence. That rivalry was paused through Chinese mediation in March 2023. But since October 2023  a war of attrition between Israel and Iran has unfolded through both conventional and asymmetrical means – a conflict that now threatens to define the trajectory of the Middle East for years to come. Whether this confrontation escalates further now hinges largely on one man  Ayatollah Ali Khamenei. If Iran’s supreme leader comes to view the survival of the Islamic Republic as fundamentally threatened  Tehran’s response could expand far beyond Israeli territory. In recent months  Israeli leaders had issued repeated warnings that a strike on Iran’s nuclear facilities was imminent. Intelligence assessments in Tel Aviv claimed Iran was only weeks away from acquiring the necessary components to build a nuclear weapon. Although this claim was disputed by other members of the international community  it nonetheless shaped Israel’s decision to act militarily. At the same time  indirect negotiations between Iran and the US had been under way  focused on limiting Iran’s uranium enrichment and reducing tensions through a revised nuclear agreement. US President Donald Trump publicly supported these diplomatic efforts  describing them as preferable to what he called a potentially bloody war. However  the talks faltered when Iran refused to halt enrichment on its own soil. Advertisement The US administration  while officially opposing military escalation  reportedly gave tacit approval for a limited Israeli strike. Washington is said to have believed that such a strike could shift the balance in negotiations and send a message that Iran was not negotiating from a position of strength – similar to how Trump has framed Ukraine’s position in relation to Russia. Although US officials maintain they had advance knowledge of the attacks but did not participate operationally  both the aircraft and the bunker-busting bombs used were supplied by the US  the latter during Trump’s first term. Initial reports from Iranian sources confirm that the strikes inflicted significant damage on centrifuge halls and enrichment pipelines at its Natanz facility. However  Iranian officials insist the nuclear programme remains intact. Iran’s nuclear infrastructure includes multiple deeply buried sites – some more than 500 metres (550 yards) underground and spread across distances exceeding 1 000km (620 miles). As a result  the total destruction of the programme by air strikes alone in this initial phase appears unlikely. Iranian officials have long warned that any direct military aggression on their territory by Israel would cross a red line  and they have promised severe retaliation. Now  with blood spilled on its soil and key targets destroyed  Khamenei faces enormous internal and external pressure to respond. The elimination of multiple high-ranking military officials in a single night has further intensified the demand for a multifaceted response. Advertisement Iran’s reply so far has taken the form of another wave of drone attacks  similar to those launched in April and October – most of which were intercepted by Israeli and Jordanian defences. If Iran does not engage with the US at the upcoming talks in Oman on Sunday regarding a possible nuclear deal  the failure of diplomacy could mark the start of a sustained campaign. The Iranian government has stated that it does not view the Israeli operation as an isolated incident  but rather as the beginning of a longer conflict. Referring to it as a “war of attrition” – a term also used to describe Iran’s drawn-out war with Iraq in the 1980s – officials have indicated the confrontation is likely to unfold over weeks or even months. While retaliatory missile and drone strikes on Israeli targets are likely to continue  many now anticipate that Iran could also target US military bases in the Gulf  Bahrain  Qatar  the United Arab Emirates and even Jordan. Such an escalation would likely draw US forces directly into the conflict  implicate critical regional infrastructure and disrupt global oil supplies  particularly through the Strait of Hormuz. That  in turn  could trigger a steep rise in energy prices and send global markets spiralling – dragging in the interests of nearly every major power. Even if an immediate  proportionate military response proves difficult  Iran is expected to act across several domains  including cyberattacks  proxy warfare and political manoeuvring. Among the political options reportedly under consideration is a full withdrawal from the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (NPT). Iran has long used the NPT framework to assert that its nuclear programme is peaceful. Exiting the treaty would signal a significant policy shift. Additionally  there is growing speculation within Iran’s political circles that the religious decree issued by Khamenei banning the development and use of nuclear weapons may be reconsidered. If that prohibition is lifted  Iran could pursue a nuclear deterrent openly for the first time. Advertisement Whether Israel’s strikes succeeded in delaying Iran’s nuclear ambitions – or instead provoked Tehran to accelerate them – remains uncertain. What is clear is that the confrontation has entered a new phase. Should Iran exit the NPT and begin advancing its nuclear programme without the constraints of international agreements  some may argue that Israel’s campaign – intended to stop a bomb – may instead end up accelerating its creation. The views expressed in this article are the author’s own and do not necessarily reflect Al Jazeera’s editorial stance. aj-logo </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/9b721ee3bf97d0d3fa503909dc188b19.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/opinions/2025/6/13/israel-may-have-just-pushed-iran-across-the-nuclear-line</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
