<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/11/how-the-los-angeles-protests-unfolded-a-visual-guide</field>
<field name="title">How the Los Angeles protests unfolded  A visual guide</field>
<field name="name">How the Los Angeles protests unfolded  A visual guide</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-11T14:33:20Z</field>
<field name="desc">How the Los Angeles protests unfolded  A visual guide The protests erupted following ICE immigration raids  igniting a battle between state and federal officials. By Al Jazeera Staff Published On 11 Jun 202511 Jun 2025 Parts of Downtown Los Angeles were under a nighttime curfew on Tuesday after LA Mayor Karen Bass declared a local emergency to “stop the vandalism” and “to stop the looting”. The protests began on Friday after United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) authorities conducted a series of immigration raids across the city. The next day  US President Donald Trump issued an executive order to deploy 2 000 National Guard troops to LA without California Governor Gavin Newsom’s consent. Trump ordered the deployment of 700 Marines and an additional 2 000 National Guard forces on Monday. This provoked an ongoing battle between state and federal authorities  with Newsom calling Trump’s order a “blatant abuse of power” and Mayor Bass describing the deployment as an “intentional effort to sow chaos”. On the federal side  Department of Homeland Security (DHS) Secretary Kristi Noem referred to Los Angeles as a “city of criminals” and accused local officials of inaction. (Al Jazeera) Advertisement Friday  June 6 Morning  ICE conducted coordinated raids across LA  targeting a Home Depot  garment factories  warehouses and street vendor locations. At least 44 individuals were arrested for “immigration violations”. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) said they included gang members and criminals. The raids quickly triggered protests and demonstrations blocked entrances and exits for the Edward R Roybal Federal Building in Downtown LA  where the detainees were being processed. Afternoon  David Huerta  president of Service Employees International Union (SEIU)  one of the largest and most influential labour unions in the country  was arrested outside a garment warehouse where protesters had gathered to oppose an immigration raid. Huerta was taken to the Metropolitan Detention Center in Downtown LA  where protesters assembled in solidarity. Evening  The Los Angeles Police Department (LAPD) declared the area an unlawful assembly  deployed tear gas  issued tactical alerts and made several arrests. Los Angeles Police Department officers move to disperse a protest after federal immigration authorities conducted an operation on Friday  June 6  2025  in Los Angeles [Jae C Hong/AP Photo] Saturday  June 7 Morning  The next morning  reports emerged of more immigration raids  this time outside a Home Depot store in Paramount  about 26km (16 miles) southeast of downtown LA  where day labourers often gather in hopes of being hired for short-term jobs. There  protesters clashed with security forces  who used tear gas and flashbang grenades to disperse the crowd. (Al Jazeera) Afternoon  The protests escalated as demonstrators blocked streets  threw stones and set a vehicle on fire. The LA County Sheriff declares the gathering an unlawful assembly and uses tear gas to disperse the crowd. BREAKING  ICE raid and community resistance in front of Home Depot in Paramount  California. pic.twitter.com/WdM1Gr93Wi — Jeremy Lindenfeld (@jeremotographs) June 7  2025 Advertisement Evening  President Trump orders at least 2 000 National Guard troops to be deployed to Los Angeles  federalising them under Title 10 of the US Code  which allows the federal government to mobilise National Guard units without the consent of state governors. It marked the first time since 1965 that a president had deployed National Guard troops to a state without a governor’s request. (Al Jazeera) Sunday  June 8 Morning  About 300 National Guard troops arrive in downtown LA  Paramount  and neighbouring Compton to secure federal sites  prompting anger and fear among many residents. On the most intense day of demonstrations so far  thousands of protesters gathered in downtown LA near the Metropolitan Detention Center  where they were met by National Guard troops deployed to support immigration officials. (Al Jazeera) Afternoon  Large crowds march from City Hall to the Federal Detention Center. The LAPD once again issues dispersal orders and begins arrests. Protesters briefly block sections of the 101 Freeway  disrupting one of Los Angeles’ busiest highways. Some demonstrators also set fire to several self-driving cars  escalating tensions further. In response  authorities deployed tear gas  rubber bullets and flashbang grenades to disperse the crowd. A man holds signs as Waymo autonomous vehicles burn  as protesters clash with law enforcement in the streets surrounding the federal building during a protest following federal immigration operations in Los Angeles  California  on June 8  2025 [Ringo Chiu/AFP] Monday  June 9 Morning  After a relatively calm night  the fourth day begins with renewed ICE raids targeting workplaces across Southern California  including in suburban areas like Santa Ana and Paramount. Thousands gather for a large rally at Grand Park in downtown Los Angeles  organised by the SEIU. The demonstration  joined by local officials and members of Congress  calls for an end to the raids  the immediate release of the SEIU’s Huerta  and the withdrawal of National Guard troops from the city. Huerta is later released on a $50 000 bond. People attend a rally against the detention of SEIU California and SEIU-USWW union president David Huerta amid federal immigration sweeps  with Los Angeles City Hall in the background  in downtown Los Angeles  on June 9  2025 [David Ryder/Reuters] Afternoon  The state of California files a lawsuit against President Trump and Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth  arguing that the Title 10 deployment of National Guard troops unlawfully oversteps state sovereignty. Advertisement Trump doubles the number of National Guard troops from 2 000 to 4 000  while also deploying 700 Marines in a domestic deployment not seen in decades. Marines stand near vehicles as they prepare to depart for Los Angeles on June 9  2025 [Handout/US Northern Command via X/Reuters] Evening  Protests continue around the federal building  with a mix of peaceful rallies and sporadic clashes with police. Authorities deploy tear gas and rubber bullets  and hundreds of arrests are reported throughout the day. Tuesday  June 10 The protests entered their fifth day  with demonstrations remaining mixed  many peaceful  while others involved vandalism  looting  rock throwing and the use of crowd-control measures. Newsom and Bass continued to condemn the military presence as illegal and damaging  warning it tarnishes the city’s image as it prepares for major events like the 2028 Olympics and the World Cup. A Pentagon official estimated that the deployment of Marines and National Guard troops to Los Angeles will cost about $134m. In this image taken from video  Los Angeles Mayor Karen Bass gives a news conference following days of unrest  Tuesday  June 10  2025  in Los Angeles [ABC7 Los Angeles via AP] Despite mounting criticism  President Donald Trump doubles down on his decision to deploy the National Guard and Marines to confront protesters in Los Angeles. Mayor Bass announces a curfew for a portion of the downtown area  effective from 8pm on Tuesday until 6am on Wednesday. The curfew covers an area of approximately 20sq km (7.7sq miles). Advertisement The city of Los Angeles at a glance The state of California has the largest Latino or Hispanic population of any US state  both in total numbers and as a share of its population  with nearly half of its residents identifying as such in the 2024 Census. Los Angeles is the United States’s second-largest city  after New York City  with a population of some 3.8 million residents within its city limits. The city is home to more than 1.35 million migrants  which means that one in every three residents is a migrant  according to the LA city government in 2024 . What are sanctuary cities? Los Angeles is one of many self-claimed sanctuary cities across the US  which limit their cooperation with federal immigration enforcement  particularly US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE)  to protect undocumented citizens from detention and deportation. Sanctuary laws differ from place to place. Some ban asking about immigration status  while others only refuse to hold people on ICE detainers. Being in a sanctuary city or state does not mean someone is safe from deportation. ICE can still operate and arrest people in sanctuary jurisdictions. (Al Jazeera) Nationwide protests against ICE deportations The most recent protests in LA are part of a series of continuing demonstrations by civil society and various groups opposing Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) due to the detention and deportation of community members. According to the Armed Conflict Location   Event Data Project (ACLED)  an organisation that tracks political violence and protests worldwide  at least 2 112 demonstrations against Immigration and Customs Enforcement have occurred since January 2025. Advertisement These protests are shown on the map below. Source  Al Jazeera </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/cd93d4d6c8a28cf736b27d38964e18c7.png</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/11/how-the-los-angeles-protests-unfolded-a-visual-guide</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
