<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/economy/2025/6/12/air-india-crash-refuels-boeing-and-airlines-problems</field>
<field name="title">Air India crash refuels Boeing and airline’s problems</field>
<field name="name">Air India crash refuels Boeing and airline’s problems</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-12T21:38:16Z</field>
<field name="desc">Economy | Aviation Air India crash refuels Boeing and airline’s problems The fatal crash raises new concerns for both firms as they try to revamp after years of problems that marred their reputations. Firefighters work at the site of an aeroplane that crashed in India s northwestern city of Ahmedabad in Gujarat state [Ajit Solanki/AP] By Andy Hirschfeld Published On 12 Jun 202512 Jun 2025 The fatal crash of a 787 Dreamliner that was being operated by Air India from Ahmedabad in northwestern India to London Gatwick Airport has once again fueled scrutiny of both Boeing and the airline  as the two companies have been trying to emerge from years of crises and poor reputations. The nearly 12-year-old Dreamliner crashed on a densely populated part of the city soon after takeoff  killing 241 of the 242 people on board on Thursday. The total death toll is expected to rise as the plane fell on a medical college hostel and rescue operations are still under way. Recommended Stories In nixing EV standards  Trump strikes at two foes  California and Elon Musk end of list The crash raises new concerns for Boeing  which continues to face mounting safety issues that have undermined public trust in its aircraft. These challenges come as the Seattle-based aerospace giant grapples with economic pressures from tariffs imposed by United States President Donald Trump  as well as increased regulatory attention that followed its recent safety issues. The reason behind the crash is not yet clear. But it is yet another fatal accident involving a Boeing aircraft  adding to a string of public relations crises that have made many travellers wary of flying on its planes. Advertisement “Boeing has become notorious and infamous with flyers at this moment  regardless of the model of the plane. Even the word ‘Boeing’ triggers a lot of people ” Adnan Bashir  an independent global communications and corporate affairs consultant who specialises in crisis communications  told Al Jazeera. The company’s safety reputation began to unravel in October 2018 when a Lion Air flight operating a 737 MAX crashed due to a malfunction in the Maneuvering Characteristics Augmentation System (MCAS)  a programme designed to prevent stalls. That crash killed all 189 people on board. Just months later  in March 2019  an Ethiopian Airlines flight using the same aircraft model crashed for the same reason  killing all 157 people aboard. Turmoil resurfaced in January 2024  when a door panel detached mid-flight on an Alaska Airlines route between Ontario  California  and Portland  Oregon. But until now  the 787 Dreamliner aircraft had maintained a relatively strong safety record. “This is the first fatal crash of the 787  so despite all of its problems in the early days and all the production issues that Boeing had with the aeroplane  this has had a perfect safety record up to this point ” aviation expert Scott Hamilton told Al Jazeera. Safety-related scrutiny First launched in 2011  Boeing has sold more than 2 500 of the model globally. Air India bought 47 of them  and to date  Boeing has delivered 1 189 Dreamliners. The model has faced years of safety-related scrutiny. In 2024  John Barnett   a former Boeing quality manager  was found dead under suspicious circumstances after long voicing concerns about the 787. Barnett had alleged that Boeing cut corners to meet production deadlines  including installing inadequate parts. He also claimed that testing revealed a 25-percent failure rate in the aircraft’s emergency oxygen systems. Advertisement In 2019  The New York Times published an expose that revealed Boeing had pressured workers not to report safety violations  citing internal emails  documents  and employee interviews. More recently  another whistleblower  Sam Salehpour  told lawmakers he was threatened for raising safety concerns about Boeing aircraft. Today’s crash is the latest fatal incident to occur under the leadership of Boeing CEO Kelly Ortberg   who returned from retirement in 2024 to replace Dave Calhoun. Ortberg had pledged to restore the company’s safety reputation. Previously  the last fatal Boeing incident occurred in December  when a Jeju Airlines flight crashed after a bird strike  killing 179 of the 181 people on board. Earlier this month  the US Department of Justice reached a settlement with Boeing that allowed the company to avoid prosecution for previous crashes. The deal required Boeing to pay $1.1bn  including investments to improve safety standards and compensation to victims’ families. On Wall Street  Boeing’s stock dropped nearly 5 percent from the previous day’s market close. At this point  experts believe that ultimately  Boeing executives will be careful with their words because of the looming legal challenges they may face if an investigation finds the fault lies with the plane-maker. “You can almost guarantee there’s going to be lawsuits of some sort. Right now  they’re likely triaging internal and external communication plans with their legal team. Because anything they say in public right now could be used as evidence. And so what they’re going to be doing right now is staying quiet  most likely until more facts come out ” Amanda Orr  founder of the legal and policy communications consultancy firm Orr Strategy Group  told Al Jazeera. Advertisement In response to today’s crash  Boeing said  “We are in contact with Air India regarding Flight 171 and stand ready to support them … Our thoughts are with the passengers  crew  first responders and all affected.” Boeing did not respond to Al Jazeera’s request for comment. Air India turnaround setback For Air India  which has been undergoing a major reinvention in the last few years  today’s crash is a major setback in its efforts to rebrand and modernise. Founded in 1932  the airline was nationalised in 1953. After years of financial struggles and mounting debt  Tata Group acquired the airline for $2.2bn in 2022. As India’s only long-haul international carrier to Europe and North America  Air India has a strong hold on global travel from across the country. In 2023  the carrier ordered 220 Boeing aircraft  including 20 Dreamliners  10 777x jets  and 190 of the embattled 737 MAX. For now  Air India is focused on its response to the crash. “At this moment  our primary focus is on supporting all the affected people and their families. We are doing everything in our power to assist the emergency response teams at the site and to provide all necessary support and care to those impacted ” said N Chandrasekaran  chairperson of Tata Sons  the holding company of Tata Group  in a statement provided to Al Jazeera. “I express our deep sorrow about this incident. This is a difficult day for all of us at Air India. Our efforts now are focused entirely on the needs of our passengers  crew members  their families and loved ones ” Craig Wilson  the airline’s CEO  said in a video statement. Advertisement The airline has experienced a few fatal accidents in recent years. In 2020  an Air India Express flight skidded off the runway in Kozhikode in India  killing 20. A similar accident in Mangalore involving a 737-800 claimed 156 lives. Despite the shock of today’s crash  flying remains one of the safest modes of travel. According to a 2024 study by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology   the risk of dying in a commercial airline accident is one in every 13.7 million passengers. This continues to be the safest decade in aviation history. Source  Al Jazeera </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/c52a2a73c11c1c3fc2c313482fdca375.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/economy/2025/6/12/air-india-crash-refuels-boeing-and-airlines-problems</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
