<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/united-nations-slams-us-and-israel-backed-gaza-aid-group-as-a-failure</field>
<field name="title">United Nations slams US- and Israel-backed Gaza aid group as a ‘failure’</field>
<field name="name">United Nations slams US- and Israel-backed Gaza aid group as a ‘failure’</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T15:05:21Z</field>
<field name="desc">United Nations slams US- and Israel-backed Gaza aid group as a ‘failure’ UN spokesman says Gaza Humanitarian Foundation is not delivering supplies safely to those in need. Women mourn the death of a loved one killed in an overnight Israeli bombardment on June 12  2025  at al-Shifa Hospital in Gaza City [Omar Al-Qattaa/AFP] Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 The United Nations says the Israeli- and United States-backed Gaza Humanitarian Foundation (GHF) is a “failure” from a humanitarian perspective. Jens Laerke  spokesperson for the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA)  said aid operations have stalled because the GHF is not delivering supplies safely to those in need. Recommended Stories Unarmed Palestinian brothers killed in Israeli raid on West Bank’s Nablus end of list “GHF  I think it’s fair to say  has been  from a principled humanitarian standpoint  a failure ” Laerke told reporters in Geneva on Friday. “They are not doing what a humanitarian operation should do  which is providing aid to people where they are  in a safe and secure manner.” The UN and major aid groups have refused to cooperate with the GHF  citing concerns that it prioritises Israeli military objectives over humanitarian needs. The newly formed private organisation began operations on May 26 after Israel had completely cut off supplies into Gaza for more than two months  sparking warnings of mass famine. It says it has distributed more than 18 million meals since then. Advertisement On Friday  at least 44 Palestinians were killed in Israeli attacks  medical sources told Al Jazeera. Al Jazeera’s Tariq Abu Azzoum  reporting from Deir el-Balah in central Gaza  said Israeli forces were targeting parts of Khan Younis in southern Gaza with artillery fire and ground attacks. “The Israeli military is deepening its ground operations ” Azzoum said  saying there were clashes in the eastern part of the city. The besieged territory remained under a communications blackout for a second day on Friday. Hamas has denounced what it described as an Israeli decision to cut communication lines in Gaza  calling it “a new aggressive step” in the country’s “war of extermination”. Israel recently was pressured to allow some aid deliveries to enter Gaza after barring them for more than two months (AFP) Israel continues to force civilians into what it calls the “safe zone” of al-Mawasi  a barren coastal strip with no infrastructure  which it has repeatedly bombed . A drone strike on a tent there killed at least two people on Friday. The attack left “everyone on the ground quite confused about where they can go in order to find safety”  Azzoum said. Israel locks down occupied West Bank In the occupied West Bank  Israel sealed all crossings and checkpoints between Palestinian towns and cities early on Friday  shortly after it launched a wave of air strikes on targets in Iran. Sources told Al Jazeera the closures were imposed without any indication of when they might be lifted. The Palestine Red Crescent Society said its ambulances were being denied access to patients  including those in urgent need of medical care. Advertisement In occupied East Jerusalem  Israeli forces closed Al-Aqsa Mosque  preventing Palestinians from attending Friday prayers. Palestinian Prime Minister Mohammad Mustafa held an emergency cabinet meeting in response and activated crisis committees across the West Bank. Source  Al Jazeera and news agencies aj-logo </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/7fe83aeb54ccd7b032b902c147c2ed28.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/united-nations-slams-us-and-israel-backed-gaza-aid-group-as-a-failure</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
