<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/israel-attacksiran-what-we-know-so-far</field>
<field name="title">Israel attacks Iran  What we know so far</field>
<field name="name">Israel attacks Iran  What we know so far</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T05:58:14Z</field>
<field name="desc">Trump warns of ‘chance of massive conflict’ amid Israel-Iran tensions end of list The aggression has led to fears of a wider military conflict in the region  with Tehran promising a “harsh response”. Iranian Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei warned that Israel faces a “bitter and painful” fate following the attack. “By God’s will  the powerful hand of the Armed Forces of the Islamic Republic will not let it [Israel] go unpunished ” he said. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in a prerecorded message that the strikes early on Friday were aimed at hurting Iran’s nuclear infrastructure and ballistic missile factories. Advertisement What has Israel attacked in Iran? Strikes have been confirmed in the following locations  The capital  Tehran  and military sites in the surrounding area. The city of Natanz  where explosions were reported at the main uranium enrichment facility. The city of Tabriz  where explosions have been reported near a nuclear research centre and two military bases. The city of Isfahan  south of Tehran. The city of Arak  southwest of Tehran. The city of Kermanshah  west of Tehran  where an underground facility storing ballistic missiles was hit near the Iraqi border. Images posted on social media showed damaged structures  including residential buildings  across the Iranian capital. Later on Friday morning  the Israeli army said it had damaged the Natanz uranium enrichment site’s underground structures  including a multistorey enrichment hall with centrifuges  electrical rooms and additional supporting infrastructure. It added that “vital infrastructure at the site that allows for its continuous functioning and the continued advancement of the Iranian regime’s project to obtain nuclear weapons was attacked”. The Atomic Energy Organization of Iran said radioactive contamination caused by the strike on the Natanz facility had been contained within the site and there had been no casualties. On Friday afternoon  the Israeli army said its fighter jets had completed a series of strikes against Iran’s surface-to-surface missile array. Dozens of launchers  surface-to-surface missile storage sites and other military sites were destroyed in the operation  Israel’s military said. Who has Israel killed? According to Iranian media  Hossein Salami  commander-in-chief of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps  and Mohammad Bagheri  chief of staff of the Iranian military  were among those killed in the Israeli attack. Advertisement State-run news outlet Nour News said Khamenei adviser Ali Shamkhani was “critically injured”. According to Tasnim  the commander of Khatam al-Anbiya Headquarters  Major-General Gholamali Rashid  was killed. Al Jazeera’s Tohid Asadi  who is reporting from the Iranian capital  Tehran  said that aside from military officials  two top nuclear scientists  Fereydoon Abbasi and Mohammad Tehranchi  were also killed in targeted assassinations. Abbasi was the former chief of Iran’s Atomic Energy Organization  while Tehranchi was the head of the Islamic Azad University. What has been the reaction in Iran? People in Iran woke up to terrifying scenes of destruction in their neighbourhoods. In a statement  Khamenei said Israel “opened its dirty and bloody hand to a crime” against Iran  revealing its evil nature more than ever by striking residential centres. “The regime must expect severe punishment.” Abolfazl Shekarchi  the spokesperson for Iran’s armed forces  was quoted by Iranian media as saying that Israel will pay a “heavy price” for its attacks. IRGC Commander-in-Chief Major-General Hossein Salami was reportedly killed in the attacks [File  Majid Asgaripour/WANA Reuters] What has been the reaction in Israel? Israeli military chief of staff  Eyal Zamir  said Israel had reached a “point of no return” with the attack on Friday. Describing the early morning strikes on Iran as a “fight to preserve our existence”  Zamir said Israel launched the attacks as it could not “wait for another moment to act”. Advertisement He also said  “Anyone who tries to challenge us will pay a heavy price.” Israeli opposition politician Yair Lapid posted a message on X  formerly Twitter  congratulating the Israeli army for its attack. This handout photo released by the IRGC’s official Sepah News Telegram channel shows smoke billowing from a site bombed by Israel in Tehran early on June 13  2025 [Sepah News/AFP] How has the US responded? Iran and the United States are currently involved in talks on Iran’s nuclear programme  aiming to reach an agreement that would limit the programme in return for sanctions relief for Iran. In an interview with Fox News  US President Donald Trump said Washington was not involved in the Israeli strikes. “Iran cannot have a nuclear bomb  and we are hoping to get back to the negotiating table. We will see ” Trump said  adding that the US will help defend Israel if Iran retaliates. Trump is expected to convene a meeting of the National Security Council on Friday morning  the White House said. In a statement  US Secretary of State Marco Rubio said the US was not involved in the operation. “Our top priority is protecting American forces in the region ” Rubio said. “Let me be clear  Iran should not target US interests or personnel.” Opposition Democratic Senator Chris Murphy said the Israeli strikes are “clearly intended to scuttle” the Trump administration’s diplomacy with Iran. People gather near damaged vehicles in the aftermath of Israeli strikes in Tehran early on Friday [Majid Asgaripour/WANA via Reuters] What is the danger of hitting nuclear facilities? Attacking nuclear facilities can cause several consequences of unpredictable scope  including radioactive leaks  explosions and long-term contamination. Advertisement Rafael Grossi  head of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA)  says the UN body is closely monitoring the situation in Iran. He said that the IAEA can confirm that the Natanz site was among the targets hit by Israel. “The Agency is in contact with Iranian authorities regarding radiation levels. We are also in contact with our inspectors in the country.” This satellite photo from Planet Labs PBC shows the Natanz nuclear facility in Iran on May 20  2025 [Planet Labs PBC via AP] What has been the global reaction to the attacks? In a statement  United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres called for “maximum restraint” to avoid “descent into deeper conflict” following the Israeli strike. “The Secretary-General condemns any military escalation in the Middle East ” his deputy spokesperson  Farhan Haq  said. “He is particularly concerned by Israeli attacks on nuclear installations in Iran while talks between Iran and the United States on the status of Iran’s nuclear programme are underway.” Oman  which is mediating nuclear talks between the US and Iran  called Israel’s action “a dangerous  reckless escalation  representing a flagrant violation” of the UN charter. “Such aggressive  persistent behavior is unacceptable and further destabilizes the regional peace and security. “The Sultanate of Oman holds Israel responsible for this escalation and its consequences  and calls upon the international community to adopt a firm and unequivocal stance to halt this dangerous course of action.” Iranian Armed Forces Chief of Staff  Major-General Mohammad Bagheri  has also reportedly been killed by Israel [Iranian Army/WANA via Reuters] Source  Al Jazeera and news agencies aj-logo </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/6b07ead779e576a0b4effb8991c70360.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/israel-attacksiran-what-we-know-so-far</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
