<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/features/2025/6/13/how-deadly-air-india-crash-shattered-dreams-wiped-out-entire-families</field>
<field name="title">How deadly Air India crash shattered dreams  wiped out entire families</field>
<field name="name">How deadly Air India crash shattered dreams  wiped out entire families</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T07:07:40Z</field>
<field name="desc">Features | Aviation How deadly Air India crash shattered dreams  wiped out entire families The dead include a young man who won a visa lottery; families returning from a wedding and Eid; and a student eating lunch. Many have been charred beyond recognition. Grieving women outside Ahmedabad Civil Hospital  where the dead and wounded from Thursday s Air India plane crash were taken [Marhaba Hilali/Al Jazeera] By Marhaba Hilali Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 Ahmedabad  India — For the Patel family  April was a month of answered prayers. The news arrived in a simple email  their son  Sahil Patel  had won a visa lottery. He was one of 3 000 Indians chosen by a random ballot for a coveted two-year United Kingdom work visa  under the British government’s India Young Professionals Scheme. For the 25-year-old from a middle-class family  it was a pathway from a modest home in Sarod village  150km (93 miles) from Ahmedabad  the biggest city in the western Indian state of Gujarat  to a new life in London. For his family  the visa was the culmination of every prayer  a chance for the social mobility they had worked their whole lives for. But less than two months later  that excitement has turned to grief  Sahil was one of the 241 people on Air India 171 who died when the plane crashed into a medical college’s hostel just outside Ahmedabad airport on Thursday  June 12  seconds after taking off. Only one passenger survived India’s deadliest aviation disaster in more than three decades. Dozens of people on the ground were killed  including several students at BJ Medical College  when the plane erupted into a ball of fire after crashing into their mess. Several others were injured  many of them still in critical care. Advertisement Those killed on board include young students on their way to London on scholarships  a family returning home from a wedding in Gujarat  another that was visiting India for Eid  and those like Sahil whose families believed they had won the luck of a lifetime. The father (in the blue shirt) of Irfan  one of the flight crew killed when the Air India plane crashed  at the hospital [ Marhaba Hilali/Al Jazeera] ‘Why my child?’ In the mess hall at Gujarat’s oldest medical school  Rakesh Deora was finishing his lunch along with more than 70 other medical students. From a small town in Bhavnagar in southeastern Gujarat  Deora was in the second year of his undergraduate studies – but  friends and family recalled  did not like wearing his white coat. When the plane struck the building  he was killed by the falling debris. In the chaos that followed  many of the bodies – from the plane and on the ground – were charred beyond recognition. Deora’s face was still recognisable when his family saw his body. At the Ahmedabad Civil Hospital  five hours after the crash  another family rushed in. Irfan  22  was an Air India cabin crew member  his uniform a symbol of pride for his family. They rushed to the morgue  unaware of what they were about to face. When an official showed Irfan’s father his son’s body – his face still recognisable – the man’s composure shattered. He collapsed against a wall  his voice a raw lament to God. “I have been religious my whole life ” he cried  his words echoing in the sterile hallway. “I gave to charity  I taught my son character … Why this punishment upon him? Why my child?” Beside him  Irfan’s mother refused to believe that her son was dead. “No!” she screamed at anyone who came near. “He promised he would see me when he got back. You’re lying. It’s not him.” Advertisement For another family  recognition came not from a face  but from a small  gold pendant. It was a gift from a husband to his wife  Syed Nafisa Bano  and it was the only way to identify her. Nafisa was one of four members of the Syed family on board  including her husband Syed Inayat Ali  and their two young children  Taskin Ali and Waqee Ali. They had been buzzing with excitement  talking about their return to London after spending a wonderful two months in India celebrating Eid al-Adha with their relatives. On Thursday  their family in Gujarat huddled together in the hospital corridor in mourning  the laughter they had shared consigned to memories. Syed Inayat Ali and his wife Syed Nafisa Bano  in a photo taken with Gujarat-based family members at the airport before they took off in the Air India plane that crashed  killing them along with their two children [Marhaba Hilali/Al Jazeera] ‘God saved us  but he took so many others’ Just 500 metres from the main crash site  rickshaw driver Rajesh Patel was waiting for his next customer. The 50-year-old was the sole earner for his family. He wasn’t struck by debris  but by the explosion’s brutal heat  which engulfed him in flames. He now lies in a critical care unit  fighting for his life. His wife sits outside the room  her hands clasped in prayer. In the narrow lanes of the Meghaninagar neighbourhood near the crash site  Tara Ben had just finished her morning chores and was lying down for a rest. The sudden  deafening roar that shook her home’s tin roof sounded like a gas cylinder explosion  a familiar danger in the densely packed neighbourhood. But the screams from outside that followed told her this was different. “Arey  aa to aeroplane chhe! Plan tooti gayo! [Oh  it’s an aeroplane! It’s a plane crash!]” a man shrieked in Gujarati; his voice laced with a terror she had never heard before. Tara Ben ran out into the chaos. The air was thick with smoke and a smell she couldn’t place – acrid and metallic. Advertisement As she joined the crowd rushing to view the crash site  a cold dread washed over her – a mix of gratitude and guilt. It wasn’t just for the victims  but for her own community. She looked back at the maze of makeshift homes in her neighbourhood  where hundreds of families lived stacked one upon another. “If it had fallen here ” she later said  her voice barely a whisper  “there would be no one left to count the bodies. God saved us  but he took so many others.” Veteran rescue worker Tofiq Mansuri has seen tragedy many times before  but nothing had prepared him for this  he said. For four hours  from mid-afternoon until the sun began to set  he and his team worked in the shadow of the smouldering wreckage to recover the dead with dignity. “The morale was high at first ” Mansuri recalled  his gaze distant  his face etched with exhaustion. “You go into a mode. You are there to do a job. You focus on the task.” He described lifting body bag after body bag into the ambulances. But then  they found her. A small child  no more than two or three years old  her tiny body charred by the inferno. In that moment  the professional wall Mansuri had built to allow himself to deal with the dead  crumbled. “We are trained for this  but how can you train for that?” he asked  his voice breaking for the first time. “To see a little girl … a baby … it just broke us. The spirits were gone. We were just men  carrying a child who would never go home.” Mansuri knows the sight will stay with him. “I won’t be able to sleep for many nights ” he said  shaking his head. Relatives of people on the plane register for DNA tests to help identify bodies  many of which were charred beyond recognition [Marhaba Hilali/Al Jazeera] ‘Air India killed him’ By 7pm  five hours after the crash  ambulances were arriving at Ahmedabad Civil Hospital in a grim procession  not with sirens blaring  but in a near-silent parade of the dead. Inside the hospital  a wave of anguish rippled through the crowd each time the doors of the morgue swung open. In one corner  a woman’s voice rose above the din  a sharp  piercing cry of accusation. “ Air India killed him !” she screamed. “Air India killed my only son!” Then she collapsed into a heap on the cold floor. No one rushed to help; they simply watched  everyone struggling with their own grief. Dozens of families waited – for a name to be called  for a familiar face on a list  for a piece of information that might anchor them amid a disorienting nightmare. They huddled in small  broken circles  strangers united by a singular  unbearable fate. Some were called into small  sterile rooms to give DNA samples to help identify their dead relatives. Advertisement Then an official’s announcement cut through the air  identified remains would only be released after 72 hours  after post-mortem procedures. As the night deepened  some relatives  exhausted and emotionally spent  began their journey home  leaving one or two family members behind to keep vigil. But many refused to leave. They sat on the floor  their backs against the wall  their eyes vacant. While some families still cling to the fragile hope of survival  such as in the case of Rajesh Patel  the rickshaw driver  others are grappling with the grief differently. Away from the hospital’s frantic chaos  Sahil Patel’s father Salim Ibrahim was away in his village  calm and composed. Over the telephone  his voice did not break but remained chillingly calm  his grief masked by a single practical question. “Will they give him back to us in a closed box?” he asked. “I just … I cannot bear for anyone to see him like that. I want him to be brought home with dignity.” The visa that promised a new world to Sahil is now a worthless piece of paper. The plane was a Dreamliner  an aircraft named for the very thing it was meant to carry. The dream of London has dissolved into a nightmare in a morgue. And in the end  all a father can ask for his son is the mercy of a closed lid. Source  Al Jazeera </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/82cd90f0e1535477c345e0356f3342f6.jpeg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2025/6/13/how-deadly-air-india-crash-shattered-dreams-wiped-out-entire-families</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
