<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/which-airlines-paused-or-cancelled-flights-after-israels-attack-on-iran</field>
<field name="title">Which airlines paused or cancelled flights after Israel’s attack on Iran?</field>
<field name="name">Which airlines paused or cancelled flights after Israel’s attack on Iran?</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T10:31:57Z</field>
<field name="desc">Which airlines paused or cancelled flights after Israel’s attack on Iran? Airlines suspend flights and some countries close airspace after Israel launches attacks on Iran and Tehran retaliates. Aeroplanes are parked on the tarmac at Israel s Ben Gurion airport near Tel Aviv [File  Gil Cohen-Magen/AFP] Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 Several airlines have suspended or cancelled flights in the Middle East and some countries have shut their airspace after Israel launched a wave of air strikes on Iran. The Israeli attacks targeted military facilities  nuclear sites and residential areas in the early hours of Friday. Iran has since retaliated with a wave of missile strikes across Israel. Recommended Stories end of list Here is a list of suspended and rerouted flights  Emirates  the Middle East’s largest airline  said it had cancelled flights to and from Iraq  Jordan  Lebanon and Iran until June 15. Several flights scheduled for Friday and one Tehran flight on Saturday were listed as cancelled on the airline’s website. Qatar Airways  the country’s national carrier and one of the Middle East’s largest  said it had temporarily cancelled flights to and from Iran and Iraq “due to [the] current situation in the region”. It also said flights to Damascus will be cancelled until June 14. El Al Airlines  an Israeli flag carrier  said it had suspended flights to and from Israel and was moving some of its planes out of the country. It has advised customers  whose flights are scheduled for Saturday and Sunday evening  to avoid airports and to await updates regarding their flight status. Israir  a budget Israeli carrier  said it had canceled all its flights to and from Israel until June 15 and was evacuating its planes from Tel Aviv airport  which it said was expected to remain closed through the weekend. Arkia  an Israeli airline  has cancelled all its flights until June 14. Flydubai  or the Dubai Aviation Corporation  a budget carrier  said it had suspended flights to Amman  Beirut  Damascus  Iran and Israel and a number of other flights had been cancelled  rerouted or returned to their departure airports. Turkish Airlines  Turkey’s flag carrier  and other Turkish operators have cancelled flights to Iran  Iraq  Syria and Jordan until June 16  Turkiye’s Transport Minister Abdulkadir Uraloglu said in a statement. Etihad Airways  one of the United Arab Emirate’s airlines  said it had cancelled two flights between Abu Dhabi and Tel Aviv and delayed the departure of four others. Etihad and Turkish Airlines also diverted some flights to Baku  Azerbaijan  according to Heydar Aliyev International Airport. Pegasus Airlines  a Turkish carrier  cancelled its flights to Iran until June 19 and flights to Iraq and Jordan until June 16. The company said in a statement that it will operate flights to Lebanon only during daylight hours. Lufthansa  the largest airline in Germany  suspended all flights to and from Tel Aviv and Tehran until July 31  and to and from Amman  Erbil and Beirut until June 20. In a statement  the company added that it would also avoid “Iranian  Iraqi and Israeli airspace for now”. Air France  the country’s national carrier  suspended flights to and from Tel Aviv “until further notice” following the closure of Israeli airspace. Ita Airways  Italy’s flagship airline  extended the suspension of flights to Tel Aviv until July 31. KLM  a Dutch airline in partnership with Air France  cancelled all flights to Tel Aviv until at least July 1  reported Dutch news agency ANP. Ryanair  a budget Irish airline  cancelled flights to and from Tel Aviv until August 31. SWISS  which is owned by Lufthansa and is Switzerland’s national carrier  suspended its Tel Aviv flights until October 25 while those to Beirut will be suspended until the end of July. Aegean Airlines  Greece’s flag carrier  cancelled all flights to and from Tel Aviv up to and including the early morning flight on July 12  as well as all flights to and from Beirut  Amman  and Erbil through the morning arrivals of June 28. LOT Polish Airlines announced it will not be using Iranian airspace for flights to Asia  a spokesperson told state news agency PAP. Wizz Air  a Hungarian budget airline  suspended flights to Tel Aviv and re-routed flights affected by closed airspace in the region for the next 72 hours  it said in a statement through its Cyprus-based publicist. Tarom  Romania’s flag carrier  suspended all commercial flights to and from Tel Aviv  Beirut and Amman until June 16. AirBaltic  Latvia’s flag carrier  said all flights to and from Tel Aviv until June 23 had been cancelled. Air India  a flag carrier of the subcontinent which overflies Iran for its Europe and North American flights  said several flights were being diverted or returned to their origin  including ones from New York  Vancouver  Chicago and London. Aeroflot  Russia’s flagship airline  cancelled flights between Moscow and Tehran. In a statement  the airline said that flights to Dubai  Abu Dhabi  Doha and the Maldives have been rerouted through Pakistani airspace. Delta Air Lines  a US airline  said it has paused flights to Tel Aviv from New York through August 31. The airline also turned back a New York–Tel Aviv flight mid-air on Thursday  according to Flightradar data. United Airlines  a major US airline  confirmed that Flight UAL84 to Tel Aviv returned to New York after takeoff  while a flight from Newark was also cancelled. The airline has announced it has halted operations in Israel until late August  according to Israeli media. Easyjet  a British low-cost airline  has suspended all flights to Tel Aviv until at least July 31  Israeli media reported. (Al Jazeera) Some countries have also closed their airspace following the attacks. Advertisement Iran’s official news agency IRNA reported that aviation authorities have shut down the country’s airspace until further notice. Early on Friday  Iraq closed its airspace and suspended all traffic at its airports  Iraqi state media reported. Eastern Iraq near the border with Iran contains one of the world’s busiest air corridors  with dozens of flights crossing between Europe and the Gulf  many on routes from Asia to Europe  at any single moment. Jordan’s civil aviation authority has also said it “temporarily” closed Jordanian airspace to all flights “in anticipation of any dangers resulting from the escalation happening in the region”. Last year  some Iranian missiles that targeted Israeli military bases flew over Jordan  which neighbours Israel and Iraq. Source  Al Jazeera and news agencies aj-logo </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/477fd1271d45384c80504b62412fb22f.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/which-airlines-paused-or-cancelled-flights-after-israels-attack-on-iran</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
