<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/12/mapping-us-troops-and-military-bases-in-the-middle-east</field>
<field name="title">Mapping US troops and military bases in the Middle East</field>
<field name="name">Mapping US troops and military bases in the Middle East</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-12T14:18:58Z</field>
<field name="desc">News | Military Mapping US troops and military bases in the Middle East The United States has maintained a military presence in the Middle East for decades  currently stationing between 40 000 and 50 000 troops across at least 19 sites. (Al Jazeera) By Al Jazeera Staff Published On 12 Jun 202512 Jun 2025 The United States announced on Wednesday that it is preparing a partial evacuation of its embassy in Iraq and has authorised “the voluntary departure” of dependants of American personnel from locations across the Middle East  including Bahrain  Kuwait and the United Arab Emirates  as regional security concerns rise. On Wednesday evening  US President Donald Trump explained that the decision to relocate staff was made because the region “could be a dangerous place”. Tensions have been rising recently  fuelled by stalled negotiations between the US and Iran over its nuclear programme  further inflamed by Israel’s repeated statements that it is prepared to launch a strike on Iran. Where are US military bases in the Middle East? The US has operated military bases in the Middle East for decades. According to the Council on Foreign Relations  the US operates a broad network of military sites  both permanent and temporary  across at least 19 locations in the region. Of these  eight are permanent bases  located across Bahrain  Egypt  Iraq  Jordan  Kuwait  Qatar  Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates. (Al Jazeera) How many US troops are in the Middle East? The US’s first deployment of soldiers in the Middle East was in July 1958 when combat troops were sent to Beirut during the Lebanon Crisis. At its height there were almost 15 000 Marines and Army troops in Lebanon. Advertisement As of mid-2025  there are about 40 000 to 50 000 US troops in the Middle East  comprising personnel stationed in both large  permanent bases and smaller forward sites across the region. The countries with the most US troops include Qatar  Bahrain  Kuwait  the United Arab Emirates and Saudi Arabia. These installations serve as critical hubs for air and naval operations  regional logistics  intelligence gathering and force projection. Below are some notable bases in the region. Al Udeid Air Base (Qatar) – The largest US military base in the Middle East  established in 1996. Covering an area of 24 hectares (60 acres)  the base accommodates almost 100 aircraft as well as drones. This base  which houses some 10 000 troops  serves as the forward headquarters for US Central Command (CENTCOM) and has been central to operations in Iraq  Syria and Afghanistan. US President Donald Trump gestures while delivering remarks to US troops during a visit to Al Udeid Air Base in Doha  Qatar  on May 15  2025 [Brian Snyder/Reuters] Naval Support Activity  NSA (Bahrain) – The current US naval base sits on the site of the former British naval installation  HMS Jufair. The base hosts approximately 9 000 Department of Defense personnel  including military and civilian staff. Home to the US Navy’s Fifth Fleet  the base provides security to ships  aircraft  detachments and remote sites in the region. A US Navy Martin UAV drone flies over Gulf waters as Royal Bahraini Naval Force (RBNF) Abdulrahman Al Fadhel takes part in joint naval exercise between US Fifth Fleet Command and Bahraini forces  on October 26  2021 [Mazen Mahdi/AFP] Camp Arifjan (Kuwait) – Camp Arifjan is a major US Army base located about 55km (34 miles) southeast of Kuwait City. Constructed in 1999  it serves as the primary logistics  supply and command hub for US military operations in the Middle East  particularly within the US CENTCOM area of responsibility. Former US President George W Bush greets military personnel in Camp Arifjan  Kuwait [File  Brooks Kraft LLC/Corbis via Getty Images] Al-Dhafra airbase (UAE) – A strategic base focused on reconnaissance  intelligence gathering and supporting combat air operations. The base hosts advanced aircraft such as the F-22 Raptor stealth fighters and various surveillance planes  including drones and AWACS. The F-22 Raptor is a fifth-generation stealth fighter jet used by the US to maintain air superiority and bolster regional deterrence in the Gulf [Wolfgang Rattay/Reuters] Erbil Air Base (Iraq) – Used by US forces for air operations  particularly in northern Iraq and Syria  where troops advise Kurdish and Iraqi forces. Former US Vice President Mike Pence delivers remarks to US troops at a military facility at Erbil International Airport in Erbil  Iraq  on November 23  2019 [Jonathan Ernst/Reuters] Source  Al Jazeera </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/922e207896baf8afe71422db14b4268e.png</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/12/mapping-us-troops-and-military-bases-in-the-middle-east</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
