<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/what-is-behind-israels-decision-to-attack-iran</field>
<field name="title">What is behind Israel’s decision to attack Iran?</field>
<field name="name">What is behind Israel’s decision to attack Iran?</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T17:22:55Z</field>
<field name="desc">News | Conflict What is behind Israel’s decision to attack Iran? Israel believes Iran is a threat to its security despite Iran’s insistence that it doesn’t want nuclear weapons. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announces the launch of air strikes against Iran in this screengrab taken from a video statement on June 13  2025 [Handout/Israeli Government Press Office via AFP] By Simon Speakman Cordall Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 Israel has begun its long-signalled attacks on Iran with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu saying they would continue “as long as necessary”. The attacks   which began early on Friday  appear to have been carefully planned  hitting military and government targets and killing several senior military leaders – including the head of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC)  Hossein Salami  and the chief of staff of the armed forces  Mohammad Bagheri . Prominent Iranian nuclear scientists are also among the dead. Recommended Stories Israel kills nuclear scientists  strikes sites in Iran  Who did it target? end of list The strikes took place despite negotiations between Iran and Israel’s principal ally  the United States  over the future of Tehran’s nuclear programme  leading many to suspect that the threat of Israeli action was a coordinated ploy to bring additional pressure onto Iran. Moments ago  Israel launched Operation “Rising Lion”  a targeted military operation to roll back the Iranian threat to Israel s very survival. This operation will continue for as many days as it takes to remove this threat. Statement by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu  pic.twitter.com/XgUTy90g1S — Benjamin Netanyahu – בנימין נתניהו (@netanyahu) June 13  2025 Advertisement US support remains vital to Israel. As well as serving as the country’s principal armourer  Washington also acts as a permanent shield against criticism of Israel in the United Nations  frequently using its veto in the UN Security Council to halt any official censure of its ally despite allegations of Israel’s repeated breaches of international law. And an attack against Iran – a powerful regional force with allied groups across the Middle East – is ultimately a risky move for Israel  which is expecting an Iranian response  and the US  which has soldiers deployed across the region. So  given the stakes  why would Israel attack Iran and why now? Here’s what we know  Did Iran pose an imminent nuclear threat to Israel? Israel’s military superiority in the Middle East comes not just through its conventional arsenal or the backing of the US  but from the advantage it has that no other country in the region does  nuclear weapons. Israel is widely acknowledged to have nuclear weapons although it has never publicly admitted it. An Iranian nuclear weapon would take away that advantage and is  therefore  a red line for Israel. For years  Israel – and particularly Netanyahu – has insisted that Iran is on the verge of acquiring nuclear weapons  even as Tehran has insisted that its nuclear programme is for peaceful purposes. Justifying the Israeli attack  Netanyahu said Iran could have produced “a nuclear weapon in a very short time – it could be a year  or it could be a few months”. An unnamed Israeli military official was also quoted as saying Iran had “enough fission material for 15 nuclear bombs within days”. Advertisement What is the non-Israeli assessment of Iran’s nuclear capabilities? The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) reported on Thursday that Iran had failed to uphold the obligations it had signed on to as part of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty  an accusation Iran quickly rejected. The IAEA also noted what it believed was a long history of noncooperation between Iran and its inspectors. However  it didn’t say that Iran had developed nuclear weapons. As part of a 2015 deal with the US  other Western countries  China and Russia  Iran agreed to limit its nuclear programme and allow the IAEA to regularly inspect its facilities in return for relief from the crippling sanctions that it was under. However  in 2018  US President Donald Trump – then in his first presidential term – unilaterally withdrew from the deal and reimposed sanctions. The US has  however  not found that Iran is on the verge of acquiring nuclear weapons or attempting to do so. In March  US Director of National Intelligence Tulsi Gabbard said the US “continues to assess that Iran is not building nuclear weapons and Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has not authorised the nuclear weapons programme he suspended in 2003”. Why else would Israel attack Iran? Netanyahu has previously described Iran as “the head of the octopus” with “tentacles all around from the Houthis to Hezbollah to Hamas”. The idea is that Iran is at the head of a network of anti-Israeli groups across the region known as the “axis of resistance”. Advertisement Since starting the war in Gaza in October 2023  Israel has been able to severely weaken both Hamas and Hezbollah  limiting their abilities to attack Israel. The top leaders of both organisations have been almost entirely taken out  including important figures  such as Hezbollah leader Hassan Nasrallah and Hamas leaders Yahya Sinwar and Ismail Haniyeh. The attacks on Hezbollah in particular were not met with the kind of blowback that many in Israel feared  allowing hawks in Israel to argue that their country has an unprecedented opportunity to continue to target its enemies  including Iran  and reshape the entire Middle East. Some may think the opportunity is even there for regime change in Iran – although that would likely require a far longer war than Israel has the capability to conduct. That is despite there being no direct confrontation since last year between Israel  Iran or any of its allies before Friday’s strikes by Israel. Neither had there been any threat of action  other than that of counterstrikes if Israel did attack. Was there a domestic political component to Israel’s strikes on Iran? Many in Israel accuse Netanyahu of making military decisions – including in the war on Gaza  where Israel has killed more than 55 000 Palestinians – on the basis of his own political considerations. In the eyes of his critics  Netanyahu has become dependent upon conflict  both with Iran and in Gaza  to maintain his coalition. The alternative is to risk the collapse of his government and a public reckoning with his own failings ahead of the October 7  2023  Hamas-led attacks on Israel  which killed 1 139 people  as well as a potential prison sentence as a result of the multiple corruption charges he faces. Advertisement “For Netanyahu  the difference between foreign and domestic politics cannot be distinguished ” Israeli political analyst Ori Goldberg said. “There was no imminent threat to Israel. This was not inevitable. The [IAEA] report did not contain anything suggesting Iran posed an existential threat to Israel.” Most politicians in Israel have rallied around the military since the strikes on Iran. On Thursday  Netanyahu’s coalition had only survived a vote to dissolve the parliament and trigger elections after reaching an 11th-hour compromise over the contentious exemption of ultra-Orthodox youth from the draft. But now  Israeli opposition leader Yair Lapid has praised the attacks on Iran  and left-wing politician Yair Golan has also backed the strikes. Netanyahu’s decision to strike at Iran had been borne of the “stress” of his political position and his addiction to blood and force  left-wing Israeli member of parliament Ofer Cassif told Al Jazeera. To Cassif’s regret  however  the move appeared to have won the support of the parliamentary opposition. Has Israel again broken international law in striking Iran? According to some legal experts  yes. Israel has already been accused of breaching countless international laws through its 20-month-long war on Gaza. And the strikes on Iran may mark a new chapter in the country’s breaches of international law  Michael Becker  a professor of international human rights law at Trinity College in Dublin  told Al Jazeera. “Based on publicly available information  Israel’s use of force against Iran does not fit within the inherent right of self-defence enshrined in the UN Charter.” Advertisement “Self-defence requires Israel’s actions to be directed at an ongoing or imminent armed attack by Iran ” added Becker  who has previously worked at the International Court of Justice in The Hague. “There is no indication that an attack by Iran against Israel was imminent  nor is it sufficient under international law for Israel to justify the attack based on its assessment that Iran will soon have a nuclear capability   especially given the ongoing negotiations between the US and Iran.” Source  Al Jazeera </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/c190d448aa7a047549b3d3f9954ead51.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/what-is-behind-israels-decision-to-attack-iran</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
