<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/13/hundreds-of-missiles-launched-at-israel-as-iran-vows-retaliation</field>
<field name="title">Iran launches waves of missiles at Israel in response to attacks</field>
<field name="name">Iran launches waves of missiles at Israel in response to attacks</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-13T19:35:04Z</field>
<field name="desc">News | Nuclear Weapons Iran launches waves of missiles at Israel in response to attacks Iran’s Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei says Tehran’s response to Israel’s attack will not not be ‘half measured’. Smoke rises after a missile attack in Tel Aviv  Israel [Leo Correa/AP] Published On 13 Jun 202513 Jun 2025 Iran says it has launched waves of ballistic missiles towards Israel in retaliation for a major deadly attack on Tehran’s nuclear sites and military leaders. Explosions were heard over Tel Aviv and Jerusalem as sirens sounded across Israel on Friday night. This follows an unprecedented attack by Israel in the early hours of Friday  which targeted Iranian nuclear sites  senior military commanders and scientists. Recommended Stories Projectile hits central Tel Aviv amid warning of Iranian retaliation end of list Iran’s Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei said Israel’s strikes had “initiated a war” and it would not be allowed to do “hit and run” attacks without consequences. “The Zionist regime [Israel] will not remain unscathed from the consequences of its crime. The Iranian nation must be guaranteed that our response will not be half-measured ” Khamenei said in a statement. Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) said Iran “carried out its crushing and precise response against dozens of targets  military centres and airbases” in Israel at the command of Supreme Leader Khamenei. Three separate waves of attacks and hundreds of missiles were launched at Israel on Friday night   Iranian state media said. Advertisement At least one projectile impacted central Tel Aviv  said Al Jazeera’s Nour Odeh  reporting from Amman  Jordan. However  the Israeli military said Iran fired fewer than 100 missiles  most of which were either intercepted or fell short. The United States military also helped Israel shoot down Iranian missiles heading towards the country  the Reuters and Associated Press news agencies reported  citing unnamed US officials. Still  during the barrage  a modern apartment block was hit in central Tel Aviv  and according to live footage from the scene  fires raged inside some of the apartments  with smoke billowing from the building. Another residential building  next to the apartment block  also appeared to have suffered significant damage  with windows blown and pieces of twisted metal hanging from its exterior. At least 40 people were injured during the attack  according to the Israeli news outlet Haaretz  citing emergency services. Earlier  the Israeli ambulance service said two seriously wounded people were trapped in a building in the greater Tel Aviv area. During the attack  residents were told to avoid public places and retreat to “protected spaces”. “This was an extensive volley of ballistic missiles  something that Tel Aviv is not used to ” Odeh said. “Psychologically … the sight of damaged buildings  of emergency service providers trying to get people out of those buildings and out of the shelters  this is quite powerful for the Israeli public.” Following the attack  Iran announced that its airspace would be closed until 2pm local time on Saturday. Advertisement At the same time  air defence systems have been activated in Tehran to intercept new Israeli strikes  Iran’s state news agency IRNA reported. ‘The gates of hell will open’ Israel’s attacks on Iran on Friday killed several top Iranian generals and scientists  including the armed forces chief of staff  Major-General Mohammed Bagheri  and the IRGC chief  Hossein Salami. However  Major-General Mohammed Pakpour was swiftly promoted to replace Salami. Iran’s ambassador to the United Nations  Amir Saeid Iravani  told the UN Security Council that 78 people were killed and more than 320 others injured in Israel’s Friday attacks  including women and children. In a letter to Khamenei read out on state television  Pakpour promised that “the gates of hell will open to the child-killing regime”  referring to Israel. During Israel’s surprise attack  its military said it had struck more than 200 targets across Iran. Before Iran’s retaliatory strikes  Israeli military spokesperson Brigadier-General Effie Defrin told journalists that Israel’s army was “continuing to strike”. “Iran has the ability to significantly harm the Israeli home front”  Defrin told a televised news conference that was cut short due to what the army said was an incoming attack. Defrin added that the army had targeted the nuclear facility in Iran’s Isfahan and that the operation was “still ongoing”. Iran’s atomic energy agency said there was limited damage to the Isfahan nuclear site and the Fordo nuclear site south of Tehran  which was also targeted. Advertisement “The damage was limited to areas that did not cause any urban damage in the case of Fordo … In Isfahan  there were also attacks on several points  which were related to warehouses that caught fire ” said agency spokesperson Behrouz Kamalvandi. He added that “the damage was not extensive and there is no cause for concern in terms of contamination”. Earlier  Israel also attacked the Natanz nuclear enrichment site in Iran. The head of the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA)  Rafael Grossi  said that the attack may have damaged centrifuges and there was radiological and chemical contamination inside the facility  but the contamination was manageable with “appropriate measures”. In a statement earlier on Friday  Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said he expected “several waves of Iranian attacks” in response to Israel’s actions. Later  during Iran’s attack on Friday night  Netanyahu said in a statement directed at Iranian citizens that Israel’s operation was to “thwart the Islamic regime’s nuclear and ballistic missile threat”. “As we achieve our objective  we are also clearing the path for you to achieve your freedom. The regime does not know what hit them  or what will hit them. It has never been weaker. This is your opportunity to stand up and let your voices be heard ” he said. Source  Al Jazeera and news agencies aj-logo </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/beecc5b4264e6fd286864e0d36824954.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/13/hundreds-of-missiles-launched-at-israel-as-iran-vows-retaliation</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
