<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.aljazeera.www:https/news/2025/6/12/trump-promises-unforgettable-military-parade-in-dc-but-who-is-it-for</field>
<field name="title">Trump promises ‘unforgettable’ military parade in DC  but who is it for?</field>
<field name="name">Trump promises ‘unforgettable’ military parade in DC  but who is it for?</field>
<field name="created">2025-06-12T16:15:47Z</field>
<field name="desc">News | Donald Trump Trump promises ‘unforgettable’ military parade in DC  but who is it for? Spectacle marking US Army anniversary – and coinciding with Trump’s birthday – comes amid military response to US protests. Minnesota Governor Tim Walz  right  runs past a US Army Stryker combat vehicle at dawn along the National Mall on June 12  2025  in Washington  DC [Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images via AFP] Published On 12 Jun 202512 Jun 2025 Washington  DC – Tanks are coming to the streets of the United States capital. Twenty-eight 61-tonne Abrams battle tanks  to be exact  as well as a fleet of 56 armoured Stryker and Bradley fighting vehicles  a flock of artillery launchers  6 600 US troops  34 horses – plus two mules. And a dog. Recommended Stories How the Los Angeles protests unfolded  A visual guide end of list It is all part of the military celebration on Saturday that has been kicked into overdrive by the administration of US President Donald Trump in recent weeks. June 14 marks the 250th birthday of the US Army and  conspicuously  Trump’s 79th birthday. The US president has promised a parade of “thundering tanks and breathtaking flyovers will roar through our capital city” that will be simply “unforgettable”. The event comes nearly six months into Trump’s second term  during which he has sought to test the limits of presidential power and his legal authority to employ the military as law enforcement force within the US. That was further exemplified in this week’s deployment of the US National Guard and Marines to protests against his immigration policies in California. Advertisement So  who is the audience for Trump’s military parade? And what message will it send? “Obviously  when so much money and resources are put towards an event like a military parade that coincides with a birthday  it must be for a reason ” Irene Gammel  a professor and historian at the Toronto Metropolitan University  told Al Jazeera. “This will be a grandiose spectacle. It will be choreographed and it will be symbolically charged ” she said. US Army soldiers work on an assortment of M1 Alpha a3 Abrams tanks  Stryker armoured vehicles  and M2 Bradley fighting vehicles at West Potomac Park along the Potomac River on June 11  2025 in Washington  DC [Andrew Harnik/Getty Images via AFP] ‘America loves a parade’ Trump’s desire for a flashy military parade  with US war-fighting hardware on full display  has been well documented. It traces back to his attendance at France’s 2017 Bastille Day procession  after which  he said  “We’re going to have to try and top it.” Various reports have since detailed the first-term pushback from defence officials  who argued such a cavalcade would constitute an uncomfortable merger of partisan politics and military might. One official  then-Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Paul Selva  even directly warned Trump that such parades were “what dictators do”  according to a 2022 book published by Peter Baker and Susan Glasser. To be sure  according to Barbara Perry  a presidential historian at the University of Virginia  parades are hardly a rarity in either US civilian or military culture  regularly planned to mark national holidays  local triumphs or historical events. It’s right from the “American songbook”  she added  pointing to the 1932 Harry Richman classic  I Love a Parade. Advertisement But  in addition to the two mules and dog – present as part of the Army’s cavalry division  the procession planned for Saturday stands apart for several other reasons. While showing off military assets was more common for presidents during the Cold War  the practice has not been regularly performed for decades. Similar parades have been typically planned to mark US victories  or at the very least the end of involvement  in foreign conflicts  Perry noted  as was the case in the most recent comparison commemorating the end of the Gulf War in 1991. Preparations continue for the US Army’s 250th Birthday Celebration and Parade in Washington  DC [Carlos Barria/Reuters] Holding a parade on the president’s birthday  regardless of the overlapping Army anniversary  Perry said  also “tends towards the authoritarian”. “I feel this takes us from a movement of more innocent patriotism to a show of military might that is not only for enemies abroad  but in the minds of the administration  those within ” Perry said. “It further moves towards a cult of personality by having it fall on the president’s birthday ” she added. “I’m sure any president would have celebrated this anniversary of the founding of the US Army  but not in this way.” ‘Personal police force’ Already criticised by some observers  including top Democratic lawmakers and a handful of veterans groups  as a tribute to the “egoist-in-chief”  Trump’s decision this week to deploy the National Guard to the Los Angeles protests without the consent of the state’s governor  and his subsequent move to send the Marines to the city  has cast a long shadow over the upcoming pageantry. Advertisement Trump has  so far  not invoked the Insurrection Act of 1807   which would allow the military to take direct part in domestic law enforcement. But his actions have already sent a message of force that transforms the optics of Saturday’s parade  according to Marjorie Cohn  a professor emerita at Thomas Jefferson School of Law in San Diego and former president of the US National Lawyers Guild. Prior to sending Marines to California  Trump had already tapped the military to support his hardline immigration policies  including sending Marines to the southern border to support federal agents. “Trump considers the US military to be his personal police force  as he seeks to use it to ‘secure’ the southern border and suppress domestic protests against his inhumane policies ” Cohn told Al Jazeera. “He has considered invoking the Insurrection Act  albeit illegally  to facilitate this agenda.” A member of the US Army Golden Knights parachute team jumps during their performance for the Twilight Tattoo ceremony as part of the Army’s 250th Birthday Festival in Washington  DC [Nathan Howard/Reuters] Trump’s approach to the military dovetails with his aggressive stress testing of executive power  which he has sought to use to transform both federal government and civil society  particularly when it comes to education   healthcare  state rights  immigrant civil liberties   and trade with foreign partners. “He is speaking not just to the US  but to the world as well ” Cohn said  framing the parade as part of Trump’s wider mission to cast “himself as the most powerful person in the world”. Advertisement For his part  US Secretary of Defense Pete Hegseth indicated the deployment of National Guard troops in California  which local officials have decried as an unnecessary escalation  could be part of a wider pivot in domestic military strategy. “I think we’re entering another phase  especially under President Trump with his focus on the homeland  where the National Guard and Reserves become a critical component of how we secure that homeland ” Hegseth said during a congressional hearing on Tuesday. Soon after  Trump promised a broad – and muscular – crackdown on planned constitutionally protected protests on the day of the parade. “For those people that want to protest  they’re going to be met with very big force ” Trump told reporters in the Oval Office  as he described those who planned to demonstrate as “people that hate our country”. ‘Seizing on an opportunity’ Amid the criticism  the White House has downplayed the fact that Saturday’s spectacle also falls on Trump’s birthday. The Pentagon has said there are no plans to acknowledge the personal milestone or to sing Happy Birthday to the president. White House official Vince Haley previously said the programme “will be a fitting tribute to the service  sacrifice  and selflessness of the brave men and women who have worn the uniform and devoted their lives to defending the greatest experiment in liberty known to man”. Speaking to Al Jazeera  Mike Lyons  a retired US Army major and military analyst  also sided with the White House’s stance that criticism of the parade has been overblown. US Army soldiers work on military vehicles in West Potomac Park in Washington  DC [Andrew Harnik/Getty Images] “All Trump is doing is seizing on an opportunity to mark 250 years of the Army ” Lyons said. “Whether it’s his birthday or not  that’s just a trolling issue for the people who hate him.” Advertisement Lyons noted that military equipment is regularly put on display at events “inside the wire”  using a term for military bases both in the US and abroad. He drew a distinction between the plans for Saturday and the notorious military parades held in North Korea  often used to unveil otherwise secret military advancements. “It’s not a sign of a dictator trying to project power  because we’re not going to be a North Korea and roll out the latest armed missile  there’s no secret equipment rolling out ” Lyons said. “It’s just a celebration that gives the normal citizen an opportunity to see what this equipment looks like up close.” ‘The message is clear enough’ Trump and his administration have also played down the price tag of the event  estimated to be between $25m and $45m  but subject to rise based on the damage the military equipment causes to the streets of the capital. Officials have characterised the spending as in line with the administration’s ambition of cutting spending on federal civilian services  while surging military funding  including putting forward a historically high $1 trillion defence budget. Trump has dismissed the price tag as “peanuts compared to the value of doing it”. Toronto Metropolitan University’s Gammel also agreed that the parade could have immense value  not in a commemorative capacity  but as a particularly powerful political tool. US President Donald Trump is seen at a tank manufacturing plant in Lima  Ohio  in 2019 [File  Carlos Barria/Reuters] The event is fertile ground to shore up not just Trump’s domestic base  but also one-time supporters on the fence over the divisive first months of his second term  she told Al Jazeera. Advertisement Wrapped in military imagery considered sacrosanct to many segments of the US population  the event will be ready-made for an online audience to hit at a “very emotional level”  Gammel said. Those images will help to “naturalise values not only around military dominance  but also values that conjoin Trump’s personal image with the military and with state power. That  to me  is particularly dangerous in all of this”. “At a time when we have so many controversial elements being dismantled in the democratic system  all Trump needs to do is be present ” she added. “We don’t need to sing Happy Birthday. I think the message is clear enough”. Source  Al Jazeera </field>
<field name="tag">aljazeera</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/aljazeera/2025_Jun/d8cc88157cbc855986b54fec74255396.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/6/12/trump-promises-unforgettable-military-parade-in-dc-but-who-is-it-for</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
