<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/article207161259.html</field>
<field name="title">Duke Energy will use natural gas from pig manure to generate electricity</field>
<field name="name">Duke Energy will use natural gas from pig manure to generate electricity</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 29  2018 11 08 AM Duke Energy is turning to home-grown pig poop to help it comply with state law. The Charlotte-based utility on Thursday said one of its power plants in central North Carolina has begun burning natural gas created from N.C. manure. Duke said it must generate 0.2 percent of its retail electricity sales from pig waste by 2021  under the Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Portfolio Standard law passed in 2007. In the past  Duke has gone outside North Carolina to buy natural gas created from pig waste and burned it in North Carolina to generate electricity  Duke spokesman Randy Wheeless said. But the Smith Energy Complex in Richmond County marks Duke s first plant burning natural gas generated by pig farms in North Carolina  he said. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW The plant began using that natural gas last week. The project involves the capture of methane from hog waste at five farms in Duplin County. The methane is converted to pipeline-quality natural gas that is transported to the Smith plant  where it is used to produce electricity. Meeting the 0.2 percent mandate has been a challenge  in part to difficulties that developers face in bringing such projects online  Wheeless said. Duke is hoping the Duplin project will help spur similar projects  he said. Announced in 2016  the Duplin project is expected to produce about 11 000 megawatt-hours of electricity  enough to power about 1 000 homes  according to Duke. Duke says it has been expanding its reliance on renewable energy sources for electricity generation. In 2005  the company was not generating electricity from renewable sources  according to a report it released this month . By the end of last year  renewable sources made up 5 percent of its overall fuel types  a figure expected to increase to 10 percent by 2030  the report says. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/77e45fe77e2ac3af286122967346b2c9.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/article207161259.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
