<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/latest-news/article207606999.html</field>
<field name="title">Michigan D faces toughest test yet with  Nova for NCAA title | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Michigan D faces toughest test yet with  Nova for NCAA title | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">South Park Magazine Villanova s Omari Spellman 14) shoots a 3-point basket against Kansas during the second half in the semifinals of the Final Four NCAA college basketball tournament  Saturday  March 31  2018  in San Antonio. Villanova s Omari Spellman 14) shoots a 3-point basket against Kansas during the second half in the semifinals of the Final Four NCAA college basketball tournament  Saturday  March 31  2018  in San Antonio. Michigan D faces toughest test yet with  Nova for NCAA title By JOHN MARSHALL AP Basketball Writer April 01  2018 12 36 AM SAN ANTONIO Michigan has shored up the deficiency that always held it back  becoming one of the nation s best defensive teams  not one of its worst. Out-shooting teams  no longer necessary. This new-found stinginess has the Wolverines within reach of their first national title since Glen Rice and Rumeal Robinson rumbled through the bracket in 1989. But their biggest test yet comes on college basketball s brightest stage  Villanova and its squadron of long-range shooters with a national title on the line. Michigan is good on D  but if the Wildcats shot like they did against Kansas in Saturday night s Final Four nightcap  it may not matter what the Wolverines do. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW  I feel bad for Kansas   Villanova coach Jay Wright said.  They re a great team  we just made every shot.  Michigan (33-7) reached the title game by taking away Cinderella s slipper  sending Loyola-Chicago and Sister Jean home a game short of completing their divine run. Villanova bombed its way past a blueblood to get there. The Wildcats (35-4) turned a Final Four showdown with fellow No. 1 seed Kansas into a laugher  dropping in 3-pointers like they were playing pop-a-shot in the 95-79 rout. Villanova made a Final Four-record 18 3s in a record-matching 40 attempts  its second trip to the title game in three seasons never in doubt. That s an NCAA record 442 from the arc this season — and they re still counting.  That s as good a team as we ve played that I can remember   Kansas coach Bill Self said. The third-seeded Wolverines (33-7) had a bit more trouble against the bracket s favorite underdogs  overcoming a frightful first half to send nun-turned-motivator Sister Jean Delores Schmidt headed to the exits early. The Wolverines trailed the bracket-rambling Ramblers by seven at halftime  found the right gear in the second and have a title-game appearance no one outside of Ann Arbor saw coming when they were middling in the Big Ten just a month ago. Now they re done playing the favorite for a night  it s back to the underdog role against Villanova.  The whole villain thing  you guys love to write about it  talk about it  but at the end of the day it s just basketball  you know?  Michigan big man Moe Wagner said.  And we just try to win. That s all we do. Their next task  Find some way to slow Villanova s 3-ball roll. The Wildcats were one of the most proficient 3-point shooting teams during the regular season and upped the 3 ante in the NCAA Tournament  knocking down a record 65 and counting. Villanova broke the Final Four record with 13 in the first half and literally shot the lights out by the second  when some scoreboards and upper-level lights briefly went out and darkened the upper decks.  It was one of those nights where we were able to make shots and that s what the lead looks like   said Villanova s Jalen Brunson  who had 18 points and six assists. Michigan may have a better answer than the Jayhawks had. Tired of watching victories fizzle away through defensive deficiencies  coach John Beilein made a philosophical change  putting an emphasis on that side of the ball. It s worked out well. Michigan had the nation s No. 3 defense efficiency-wise and put Loyola on lockdown in the second half  forcing the Ramblers into a rash of turnovers to race away.  We always talk about getting the domino going   Loyola coach Porter Moser said.  They closed that gap of opportunity in a hurry.  Villanova has a way of doing that  too. The Wolverines may have an answer in Wagner. The German big man carried Michigan through its struggles in the first half by using his size advantage against the smaller Ramblers  snagging five offensive rebounds to notch a double-double by halftime. Wagner finished with 24 points and 15 rebound to join Hakeem Olajuwon and Larry Bird as the only players to have at least 20 points and 15 rebounds in a national semifinal game.  He s unbelievable. He s one of those dynamic scorers from the post  he s a great passer  made some unbelievable passers today with both hands   Villanova assistant coach Ashley Howard said.  He s a guy they can play through. We ll watch tape  try to figure out the best way to approach going into Monday night s game. It s going to be a challenge and we re looking forward to it.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/67bed6dfc8477fdfb091a165e23020bf.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/latest-news/article207606999.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
