<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206386194.html</field>
<field name="title">NASCAR’s young guns not quite ready to overtake veterans</field>
<field name="name">NASCAR’s young guns not quite ready to overtake veterans</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-22T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Other than Truex  whose win catapulted him to the top of the Cup Series standings  there’s the usual cast of veterans atop the NASCAR leaderboard  Kyle Busch  Joey Logano and Brad Keselowski. Respectively  they’re 32  27 and 34. Then there’s the driver who has been the most dominant this season  Kevin Harvick. Harvick is only eighth in the standings thanks to some strange circumstances  but he’s already collected three wins and has proven himself the man to beat in this year’s early goings. And  as you can expect at this point in the story  he’s 42. Now  don’t take all that as bashing on NASCAR’s youth movement. That certainly isn’t the intention here. It’s just ... it seems there were no tempered expectations. It was as if all these younger drivers were suddenly  and without warning  going to usurp all the established veterans on the circuit. That was never going to be the case  so these first few races of 2018 shouldn’t come as a surprise. But because of the accolades we forced onto this young generation ... now we’re all shocked? No  that doesn’t jibe. Really  that expectation-heaping on young drivers is just part of a greater trend across the sports world. College basketball freshman are expected to push their teams to the national championship. Rookies in both the NFL and NBA aren’t only expected to become All-Stars in their inaugural seasons  but to help their teams make a playoff push. Even in more niche sports  such as golf and tennis  our collective focus hinges on the up-and-comer  the shiny new name we haven’t pored over for a decade. NASCAR is just one sport among many experiencing the trend. So what should we hope for out of these young drivers instead? Improvement. Flashes of greatness. Consistent performance would be ideal  but that’s a lot to ask of a 24-year-old making his or her debut among the titans of their respective sports. We should still cheer for Chase Elliott and Ryan Blaney and Bubba Wallace – they are  after all  the future of the sport. And one day  we’ll be talking about them as the regular leaders and group of contenders in the Cup Series. Just not yet. They still have time to grow and much to learn. And that’s perfectly OK. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/c58d9ecc6049331f97d8e41c75b81390.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/m11lyl/picture206386184/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Truex2</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206386194.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
