<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/religion/article207273009.html</field>
<field name="title">Zeiss is leaving Museum of the Bible post  says it s  time to come home  to Charlotte</field>
<field name="name">Zeiss is leaving Museum of the Bible post  says it s  time to come home  to Charlotte</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 29  2018 02 25 PM Tony Zeiss  who led Central Piedmont Community College for 24 years  is leaving his top post at the new Museum of the Bible in Washington to return to Charlotte. Zeiss became executive director of the then-unfinished museum just after retiring from CPCC in December 2016. The 430 000-square foot museum  a short walk from the U.S. Capitol  opened to the public in November 2017. Zeiss has overseen a staff of 175 full-time staffers  50 part-timers and 300 volunteers and docents. Reached Thursday  Zeiss  now 72  said it was his decision to leave after 15 months on the job and that he and wife Beth are looking forward to coming back to Charlotte. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW  My goal was to get the museum open and running smoothly   he told the Observer.  We did it and it s time to come home.  On Thursday  Hobby Lobby president Steve Green  who chairs the Bible museum board  released a statement thanking Zeiss and his wife  for their tremendous efforts . . . during this crucial opening period  and wished them well  as as they embark on their next adventure.  Zeiss declined to use the word retirement for his next chapter in life. He said he preferred  going in new directions.  He still sits on a few boards in Charlotte  and said he will devote more time to them. They include the Charlotte regional board for Novant Hospitals; the John M. Belk Foundation  which awards grants for higher education; and the Trail of History  which plans to build six new statues. Zeiss said he also plans to write another book  this one about what he called spiritual laws.  Most people navigate through life understanding physical laws   he said.  But you have to mine the spiritual laws to find them. Like  We reap what we sow.   During a visit to Charlotte late last year  Zeiss described his job at the museum this way to the Observer   We hire a lot of really good people and we get them trained. Then we focus on operating the museum so that it s the most incredible experience that a visitor could ever have in a museum.  But Zeiss also indicated in a speech during that December visit that he and his wife missed Charlotte and would return.  Our hearts and our home are still in Charlotte   he told a Christian group gathered at Myers Park United Methodist Church   and we ll be back.  The Bible museum  which has attracted 400 000 visitors since its November opening  has grand exhibits on the Hebrew Bible  the New Testament and more. One of the most popular features  Zeiss said last year  was a recreated 1st century village of Nazareth  the place where Jesus grew up  complete with a synagogue  olive press and ancient houses. Historical interpreters in period dress speak to tourists about what they re seeing. North Carolina-born evangelist Billy Graham  who died last month at age 99  is included in the museum s  Bible in America  exhibit. Among the visitors Zeiss met with  The Israeli ambassador to the United States and a group of Roman Catholic nuns. Zeiss said he was pleased that the Bible museum  which hopes to draw 1.6 million visitors during its first full year  has been getting higher ratings from tourists than some other museums in Washington. But the long-time president of CPCC made it clear he and his wife  are excited about coming back to Charlotte and getting back into the community  and in our church (Church of Christ Church at Gold Hill Road) and do more things historical.  The couple is also planning their first vacations in three years -- a Zeiss family reunion in Germany and a Baltic cruise. His last work day at the museum is April 24. His new prayer  Zeiss joked  is   Lord  whatever you want us to do  great  but please don t make it full time.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/45f7e9959a2e9f8ac33ae1b9a8d6c71f.jpeg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/religion/article207273009.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
