<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/national-business/article207638344.html</field>
<field name="title">State releases $26.7 million in grants for local road costs | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">State releases $26.7 million in grants for local road costs | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">State releases $26.7 million in grants for local road costs The Associated Press April 01  2018 04 44 PM HARTFORD  Conn. The state of Connecticut is releasing $26.7 million in grants to cities and towns to help cover the cost of road repairs and snow removal. Office of Policy and Management Secretary Ben Barnes says the state  certainly understands the high costs of transportation infrastructure maintenance and repair  and hopes the release of the funding will help municipalities offset their costs for capital infrastructure projects and prepare for heavier travel in the spring and summer. Connecticut municipalities have called on Democratic Gov. Dannel P. Malloy s administration to release local transportation aid  given the recent spate of snow and ice storms that have hit Connecticut. The funding may be used for everything from sanding to replacing traffic signs. OPM says another round of grants will be released in May. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/national-business/article207638344.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
