<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article201078064.html</field>
<field name="title">What art to see in Charlotte for the week of Feb. 25</field>
<field name="name">What art to see in Charlotte for the week of Feb. 25</field>
<field name="created">2018-02-20T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">February 20  2018 12 43 PM Where to go Travel to South End on  March 2 for its monthly First Fridays event. Hidell Brooks Gallery will open its new exhibition of paintings by Sally King Benedict   whose abstract and colorful paintings are often populated with minimalist faces. At Lark and Key Gallery  visitors will see work by nine artists and three potters in the gallery’s 10th anniversary exhhibition  titled “ Flight .” Who to meet Get to know Charlotte artist Stephen Wilson at both his opening and artist lecture 6-8 p.m. March 2 at New Gallery of Modern Art; it’s his second exhibition with the gallery  titled “Shine a Light When It’s Gray Out.” This new series of 25 pieces is stylistically in line with previous work involving embroidery  and consists of darkly painted backgrounds covered with cascading butterflies. Wilson will speak about his work and upcoming book  “Stephen Wilson  Luscious Threads ” 11 a.m.-12 30 p.m. March 3. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW What to do Take an art history lesson with Adam Justice  assistant curator for contemporary art at the Mint Museum. Justice is fairly new to the Mint and to Charlotte but has become active in the arts community  and we’re looking forward to seeing him produce more good work for the museum along with head Contemporary Art Curator Jonathan Stuhlman. The Friends of the Mint will sponsor a Justice lecture on important moments in art history at 5 30 p.m. Feb. 28. Each week  Grace Cote and Lia Newman offer Observer readers a to-do list on immersing yourself in visual arts around town. Newman is director/curator of the Van Every/Smith Galleries at Davidson College  Cote is senior coordinator at Jerald Melberg Gallery  and they collaborate on the blog HappeningsCLT (happeningsCLT.com). For a seasonlong visual arts calendar  go to  www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article172583126.html . </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e03220359290014fa7679ec54708c9f2.com/entertainment/arts-culture/u5xkvu/picture201078054/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/SKB2018</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article201078064.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
