<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/article207281284.html</field>
<field name="title">Apple draws tech world s eyes to Chicago s Lane Tech with launch event for new school-focused iPad | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Apple draws tech world s eyes to Chicago s Lane Tech with launch event for new school-focused iPad | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Apple draws tech world s eyes to Chicago s Lane Tech with launch event for new school-focused iPad By ALLY MAROTTI Chicago Tribune March 29  2018 04 00 AM CHICAGO While Chicago public schools were on spring break  one company had the power to draw some students back to the classroom. Apple held a product launch event recently at Lane Tech High School in Lakeview  announcing a new iPad with a slew of software and features that cater to students and their teachers. It also announced tools for teachers to better manage their assignments and students  work and a new curriculum to integrate skills like music  photography and drawing into lesson plans. The announcement comes as Apple looks to regain its foothold in U.S. classrooms in the face of strong competition and as Chicago seeks to strengthen its ties to the Cupertino  Calif.-based tech giant. Apple has been working with educators for decades  but it has fallen behind its competitors. New machines running Google software accounted for about 60 percent of what kindergarten-through-12th-grade classrooms received at the end of 2017  according to U.K.-based Futuresource Consulting. Windows software had about 22 percent  Apple iOS had about 12 percent and MacOS had less than 5 percent. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW In a city already working to teach Apple s programming language in classrooms  some of the new tools for teachers are welcome additions.  I ve been waiting on a lot of the teacher apps they talked about   Kenn Freeman  a computer science teacher at Amundsen High School in the Ravenswood neighborhood  said while standing in one of Lane Tech s classrooms during the event. Freeman is planning to spend part of his summer break learning the new Apple offerings. He started teaching Apple s programming language  Swift  to his students in September as part of the company s Everyone Can Code initiative and had been using other software to manage assignments. Apple software will help streamline the process  he said. The city and the tech company announced a partnership in December to teach coding to CPS students. The curriculum is free for teachers  and area companies and nonprofits also joined in by offering internships and mentoring opportunities. That s just one example of how Chicago has been intertwining itself more tightly with Apple in recent months. In October  Apple opened its sleek new flagship store on Michigan Avenue along the Chicago River – the first to implement the company s  town square  retail concept. CEO Tim Cook was in town then  too  for its grand opening. Mayor Rahm Emanuel  who interviewed Cook on his podcast at the time of the store opening  said in January that Chicago would compete for a new campus Apple announced. The company said it would create more than 20 000 jobs at the new campus and existing offices. Regardless of whether Apple expands its presence in the city  Freeman said his students love learning to code. Integrating technology meets them where they are – on their phones – and they can then use the apps they design. Amundsen sophomore Edna Echeverria is still a couple of years from graduation  but she said she s considering how to incorporate coding into a future career.  To be honest  I m not a big school person  but knowing we can incorporate technology into our schooling is better   she said  iPhone in hand. Echeverria had just finished trying out an augmented reality program on one of Apple s new iPads that lets students study paintings in museums around the world. That s one of the new iPad s features  supporting augmented reality  which superimposes computer images on top of the user s view of the real world. Another app lets students digitally dissect a frog. The iPads are available to order at $299 for schools  the same price as the current model and more expensive than many Chromebooks  some of which sell for less than $200. The new iPad model also will support Apple Pencil  which allows teachers to mark up digital homework or students to draw. The company also announced upgrades to its Keynote  Numbers and Pages apps that support Apple Pencil.  I don t know about you  but I want to go back to school   Cook said during the event. Eunice Alpasan  an 18-year-old senior at Lane Tech  said she used a Macbook in her journalism class  but the school isn t Mac-exclusive.  In one of my classes  we do use Chromebooks   she said. Alpasan was there with a few classmates covering the event for the school newspaper  The Warrior. It was an elusive opportunity for a high school journalism student – Apple rarely holds its product announcements outside California. The students spoke with Emanuel and made their way through a wall of camera operators to snap a shot of the mayor and Cook chatting. The new technology Apple announced at the event sounded exciting  Alpasan said  but as a senior  she doubts she ll get a chance to use it. The new curriculum  for example  won t be available until the fall. Still  Alpasan and her classmates felt the impact of Apple s event. Roughly 1 000 people filled the halls of their school  where the smell of cafeteria lunches lingered. For a moment  the eyes of the tech world were fixated on Lane Tech. Alpasan said she wants to go into journalism.  Actually being able to cover an event like this is mind-blowing   she said. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/article207281284.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
