<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/article207277319.html</field>
<field name="title">Young chefs battle it out in salad contest | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Young chefs battle it out in salad contest | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Young chefs battle it out in salad contest By DAVID SHAROS Aurora Beacon-News March 29  2018 04 00 AM AURORA  Ill. Four teams of students from area middle schools battled it out recently at the Prisco Community Center in Aurora during the sixth annual Kane County Top Healthy Chef Competition  sponsored by Sodexo Food Service. Chefs from Waldo  Jefferson and Fischer middle schools in Aurora and Bednarcik in Oswego had 30 minutes to make the healthiest salad possible from a surprise basket of ingredients which included avocado  dragon fruit  and rainbow carrots.  The kids need to use the three ingredients as well as chose one bean – black  kidney or garbanzo beans   explained Jim Pilmer  executive director of the Fox Valley Park District  who served as one of the judges.  These kids are our future and learning to eat properly will affect their lives.  Teams of four were joined by a consulting chef from Sodexo including Chef Michael Rehfeldt  who works for the food service provider at George Williams College in Wisconsin and was part of the competition a year ago. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW  The goal here  I think  is to show how much fun making a salad can be and this is a great opportunity for the team to think through things and problem solve   Rehfeldt said.  You ve got all of these fresh veggies and lettuce and greens grown through hydroponics.  Triple Threat Mentoring Director Sue Natiello brought a  wall  of hydroponic greens including various types of lettuce and also peppers grown at the group s indoor urban farm.  We want to teach kids about growing food and empowering them   she said.  We grow these things without soil and all I can tell you is they taste more  green.    Rehfeldt said his role and that of other chefs supporting the teams would be to do prep work and chopping and to challenge teams on their ingredient choices.  This isn t the dump and drop old-school salad  but if kids want to use  say  a blood orange  they need to go back and see what it tastes like and think if this or that ingredient would pair with it   he said. Previous competitions have included making a sandwich  pizza  snack  and breakfast. The theme for each event  general manager for Sodexo Brandie Jevtik said  is chosen by a Community in Schools committee.  We have committee members from Kane County  Aurora University  Rush Copley (Medical Center)  the Fox Valley Park District  and Waubonsee Community College   Jevtik said.  There is a selection process for kids and some of them are very competitive and practice after school.  Fischer Middle School student Dajah Vance  12  was one of the competitors who said she loves to cook.  I have an older brother that cooks too  and we both do it   Vance explained.  I ve made spaghetti and things like mac-and-cheese and it wasn t out of the box either. I ve cut up the cheese cubes and melted them with milk and cooked the noodles.  Vance said the plan for her team s salad  was to make it colorful  and make sure things  matched up well.  Teammate Jeremiah Jackson  12  said he would not  be the team leader  but was happy to serve as a helper.  I m not sure being in front of all of these people is comfortable  but I want to learn something so I don t have to depend on my mom or some girl and I can cook for myself   he said.  For me  if I want to have people over  I want to know I can cook for them.  Bednarcik Middle School student Nicholas Ramirez  12  said his selection on the team this year was also a matter of luck.  I did this a year ago  and it was fun and I wanted to do it again   Ramirez explained.  You had to sign up and fill out a form. The school wound up putting eight names in a hat and four of us were picked.  Ramirez said he learned a few important lessons a year ago and promised to implement them this time around.  You have to do a number of things at once and everyone needs a job   he said.  We didn t do that last year  and so we didn t finish on time.  The Beacon-News is a Chicago Tribune publication. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/article207277319.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
