<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article183066831.html</field>
<field name="title">Iredell County Home  former poorhouse near Statesville  photos</field>
<field name="name">Iredell County Home  former poorhouse near Statesville  photos</field>
<field name="created">2017-11-07T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story November 07  2017 06 20 AM The site at Barium Springs was a “poorhouse” in the late 1800s  giving support to those in need of basic food and shelter. A new facility (with a much kinder moniker) replaced the poorhouse in 1913 when the the Iredell County Home opened. The home served the sick  insane and those with tuberculosis until it closed in 1963. The optimistic article below was written even after many of the buildings burned in a suspicious fire in 1980. As far as I can tell the facility was never renovated -- but I can’t figure out where the property was/what is on the site now. Was it near the current Barium Springs campus? Update  reader says “As memory serves  the Poorhouse was located behind the Iredell County Fairgrounds  bordering Murdock Road.” (You guys are a wealth of information  thank you!) + + + The author was president of the Historic Iredell Foundation and was a frequent contributor of historic articles. OLD COUNTY HOME COULD BECOME USEFUL AGAIN BRICK BUILDINGS NEED RENOVATION February 17  1988 By Mac Lackey Jr. As early as 1896  the Iredell County Board of Commissioners had been admonished by the courts for failing to properly maintain the county s  poor house   which would later become known as the County Home. Eventually  the board s members were indicted by a grand jury and the County Home was condemned. The commissioners responded by building a new county home to replace the old log-and-frame buildings that were declared unsafe. On Jan. 10  1913  the announcement of a new county home was made on the front page of the local newspaper   The county commissioners in special session yesterday afternoon decided to build a modern county home on the present county home property at Barium  in accordance with plans and specifications to be prepared by Messrs. Wheeler   Stern  Charlotte architects. Mr. Wheeler met with commissioners at Barium yesterday morning and a location for the new home was decided on  after which the party came to Statesville and agreed on the kind of plant to be erected  contracting with the architect for the plans and specifications. The new home will be built on a knoll about 350 yards south of the Barium railway station and will face the railroad. The plant will include several buildings  will be equipped with water and lights and will have a central heating plant. The main building will contain living apartments for the superintendent and about 12 rooms for white inmates. There will be another building for colored inmates  an infirmary for the sick  and separate apartments for the insane. It is estimated that the plant will cost from $25 000 to $30 000.  At their February meeting  the commissioners took formal action toward building the county home by voting to issue bonds in the amount of $30 000 for its construction and furnishings. The plans called for an eventual total of nine buildings  situated on a shady knoll facing the railroad  giving a splendid view of the surrounding country.  The plans called for three large buildings and a few smaller cottages  the infirmary  and a building for the insane. The buildings would all be modern brick construction  up-to-date  and convenient. At the center would be the dining hall. The basement of this building would be equipped with the central heating plant  pump and artesian well  as well as the laundry and storage rooms. Directly in front of the dining hall was a building for the superintendent and white inmates. Most of the inmate rooms were built to accommodate up to four persons per room. All of the residence buildings were to be equipped with lockers  bathrooms and spacious porches. Directly behind the dining hall was another large building exactly like the one just described  this one for black inmates. Both of the buildings were two stories high while the dining hall was one story with the basement as described. The infirmary and the insane asylum faced the dining hall on the north and south. The plans also called for the addition of other cottages that would be set diagonally between the above described buildings  giving the whole layout a wheellike effect with the dining hall being the hub. Other buildings were added as time passed and the operation grew. The farm operation required numerous buildings such as barns and tool sheds. In 1829  the N.C. legislature passed an act enabling the county to acquire property for the construction of the original poorhouse. Until taxation was in place  there was no action taken to build a poorhouse. After the taxes had been established and 200 acres of land acquired in 1841  the construction began. Four log buildings were built for the poor as well as a smokehouse and a caretakers house. All of this construction cost the county $1 200. All of the log buildings had fallen into disrepair and the county  due to their age  had done nothing other than patch work to keep them in use. After the commissioners made their decision to replace the old facilities  work began immediately. The artesian well had been completed at a depth of 200 feet by March 1913. The home provided much of the material for the new buildings. Logs were cut into building timber at a sawmill set up on the property. Firewood was cut  to be used by the brickyard to kiln-dry the bricks used for the buildings. Vacant since 1963  the old county home sits deteriorating and deserted. The brick buildings have suffered much at the hands of vandals  and neglect  but to the surprise of many  those buildings could still be placed back into service. The cost to do that would be much more than the original cost of construction. There is a problem in Iredell County and in many surrounding counties of what to do with the homeless. There is also the need for a permanent winter shelter. Maybe the county commissioners should consider repairing the old county home to serve those people who need shelter and cannot afford it. After all  that is why the county home was built to begin with  way back in 1841. + + + Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/64e8565c26fdfae49999594fd4e5d131.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/x09v3h/picture183066811/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/iredell%20county%20home%20residence%20maybeA</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article183066831.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
