<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article200089914.html</field>
<field name="title">‘Surrounded by Wolves’ depicts a world of bold  flawed women | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">‘Surrounded by Wolves’ depicts a world of bold  flawed women | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-02-14T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">SHARE COPY LINK  Surrounded by Wolves  is an exhibition now at Davidson College of work by N.C. native Jen Ray. Here s a glimpse of a live performance coordinated with the exhibition. Video by Basic Cable. McClatchy  Surrounded by Wolves  is an exhibition now at Davidson College of work by N.C. native Jen Ray. Here s a glimpse of a live performance coordinated with the exhibition. Video by Basic Cable. McClatchy ‘Surrounded by Wolves’ depicts a world of bold  flawed women By Barbara Schreiber Order Reprint of this Story February 14  2018 02 43 PM Jen Ray’s paintings  performances and installations combine bravura technique  brutality and heart. They are filled with women who cannot be controlled. In “Surrounded by Wolves ” at Davidson College Art Galleries through March 3  Ray uses the story of circus performer Patricia Jameson Cuneo as her inspiration. Some works are almost documentary in nature  representing aspects of Pat’s life  while others are trippy  Aubrey Beardsley-esque depictions of dystopias occupied solely by women. Ray  who now lives in New York after a long stint in Berlin  was born in Raleigh. She was a child when she met Pat  who she describes as a mysterious family friend who had retired to the mountains of Western North Carolina with her partner  Myra. In adulthood  Ray became curious about Pat’s past. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Pat was a tough  scary woman. Ray eventually learned about her traumatic childhood in England  helping her father burglarize stores and living through World War II; her escape to the circus  where she started out as a sideshow performer and went on to work with big cats; and her marriage into wealth and the later dissolution of that marriage. Ray likens her work to wrecked stage sets. Whether in performance or painting  she attempts to direct the movements of masses of women who have no interest in being directed. Her large paintings  which in this exhibition are up to 51 by 120 inches  are filled with innumerable tiny details  yielding chaotic scenes that are at war with Ray’s meticulous execution. “Untitled (Double Warriors)” is dominated by two languorous giant women  one smoking a cigarette. They are surrounded by numerous small women whose clothing  props and postures signal various cultures  occupations  and intentions. Books and paperwork are scattered everywhere. This work teems with displays of military-style power and pomp  including weapons and costumes/uniforms. It is also post-apocalyptic  with its obsolete technology (including a tethered phone and boxy TV with a fake wood veneer)  fire  blood  tattered clothing and bandages. “Untitled (Trap)” depicts women warriors in a beautiful hellscape. As in “Untitled (Double Warriors) ” it is filled with symbols of masculinity and domination  including spears  wads of cash and meat. Two signs—“no dumping” and “I don’t like Mondays”—are hilariously ineffectual declarations in the midst of chaos. Axes from Ray’s “Sculpture WEAPON (axe series) ” which she created in collaboration with Meissen Porcelain  are composed entirely of delicate porcelain flowers. They are are succinct and exquisite expressions of female power and lethalness. Ray brings characters from her paintings to life in performances that she conceives and directs  but does not perform in herself. In these insistent  propulsive works  overwhelming women  backed by battalion-like choruses  perform and ultimately claim ownership of misogynistic songs. On view in the gallery are videos of two performances  featuring The Guess Who’s “American Woman” and Black Flag’s “Annihilate This Week.” The title work  an installation  takes up an entire wall. It tells  in episodic fashion  Pat’s story of escape and success; it also explores theatrical deception and the sad reality behind Pat’s glamorous existence. Filled with works on paper  photographs  and objects  it is a beautiful jumble that includes stilettoes  eroticized leopards  confetti  pennants  text snippets (including obits  descriptions of animal circus acts  a gory description of a leopard tearing out a chunk of Pat’s leg  excerpts from her self-published bio and interviews)  makeup  disembodied animal jaws  glamour shots and cigarette butts. In the installation’s audio portion  Pat talks about her career in novelistic detail. As a member of a Glasgow circus  she and another performer  in shifts  portrayed a mysterious South Seas woman who would be brought out of a trance by a “professor” for a few moments a day. The installation includes remnants of the exhibition’s opening-night performance  a hallucinatory take on this aspect of Pat’s career. “Surrounded by Wolves (Marching Pats)” is an array of six identical  tuxedoed and stilettoed Pats. A first glance  Pat appears to be in her glory  but closer examination reveals her grim expression; the balloons and confetti engulfing her are suffocating instead of celebratory. Whether depicting Pat’s world or using it as inspiration for fantastical  dystopian meanderings  Jen Ray explores thrilling  insular environments filled with unsettling ritual. ‘Jen Ray  Surrounded by Wolves’ When  Through March 3. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/24bcd83af5d3d500aa3e2ac4b04cfe01.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article200089914.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
