<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/other-sports/article207648544.html</field>
<field name="title">Charlotte Checkers hockey  Bojangles Coliseum attendance up</field>
<field name="name">Charlotte Checkers hockey  Bojangles Coliseum attendance up</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 07 34 PM The Charlotte Checkers return home this week for four final regular-season games at Bojangles’ Coliseum  and they appear headed to one of their most successful seasons at the box office. Average attendance this season has been 6 411  which is up from last season’s average of 6 179. The Checkers’ best American Hockey League attendance average was their first season in the league – 2012-13 – when they averaged 6 781 at the Spectrum Center (then known as Time Warner Cable Arena). The worst was 2014-15  when the average was 5 822. The Checkers moved from the uptown area to Bojangles’ Coliseum last season. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. Their current average puts them 11th among the 30 teams in the AHL. The league-leader is San Diego  at 9 192. Right behind are Hershey (9 036  a very strong performance for a small-market team) and Cleveland (9 010). The Checkers are home Tuesday  Wednesday  Saturday and Sunday this week. Here’s a summary of where the team stands  Friday  The Checkers got one important point in the standings in a 4-3 overtime loss to the host Rochester Americans. Charlotte led three times in the game  but the Americans battled back. Rochester scored the winning goal on Colin Blackwell’s breakaway tally just 12 seconds into overtime. Trevor Carrick  Julien Gauthier and Greg McKegg scored for the Checkers. Saturday  The Checkers snapped the Syracuse Crunch’s seven-game winning streak  taking a 3-1 triumph in Syracuse. The line of McKegg  Andrew Poturalski and Aleksi Saarela accounted for all the scoring  with McKegg notching two goals and an assist  Poturalski getting three assists  and Saarela scoring a goal and adding two assists. Backup goalie Jeremy Smith made 27 saves. The standings  The Checkers remain in the fourth and final AHL Atlantic Division playoff spot  eight points ahead of fifth-place Bridgeport Sound. They trail second-place Wilkes-Barre/Scranton by four points and third-place Providence by three. The week ahead  The Checkers entertain first-place Lehigh Valley at 7 p.m. Tuesday and Wednesday  then are home against the Hershey Bears at 6 p.m. Saturday and 1 p.m. Sunday. If the season ended today  the Checkers and Lehigh Valley would be first-round playoff foes. Steve Lyttle on Twitter  @slyttle </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/908333a82142523bcc4ea4589211b7d7.com/sports/other-sports/en3dqp/picture207648539/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/CheckersFan</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/other-sports/article207648544.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
