<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/national/article207627839.html</field>
<field name="title">Shark bumps Hawaii man off a stand-up paddleboard  then attacks | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Shark bumps Hawaii man off a stand-up paddleboard  then attacks | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Shark bumps Hawaii man off a stand-up paddleboard  then attacks By Cleve R. Wootson Jr. The Washington Post Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 02 25 PM The scream came from the ocean off the private Kukio Golf and Beach Club on Hawaii’s largest island where  moments before  a man had been stand-up paddleboarding. There’s no lifeguard on the beach at the private community  but there is a “private safety team” that launched a four-person canoe. In the water  they found “a male individual who had been bumped off his paddle board about 100 to 150 yards offshore ” Fire Capt. Michael Grace told Honolulu Fox-affiliate KHON. “They recovered him from the ocean. He had injuries to his right-side extremities.” On the beach  bystanders and staff members tended to the man’s wounds  applying multiple tourniquets before paramedics arrived  Grace said. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Authorities have not identified the man. They said he is a 25-year-old resident of the community at Kukio Golf and Beach Club and had been out paddleboarding with his father. Father and son told rescuers that a shark had bumped the younger man’s board  then tore into him after he lost his balance and fell. The injured man was airlifted to North Hawaii Community hospital with what were described as critical injuries in the first attack on the state’s biggest island since 2015  according to the state’s Department of Land and Natural Resources Between 2007 and 2016  65 people were attacked by sharks in Hawaii  according to the International Shark Attack File. The state is a distant second to Florida for shark attacks in the U.S. Nineteen of those attacks happened near the state’s biggest island  also called Hawaii.   ( Video  Here’s what you need to know about shark attacks and how to fight back if you’re trapped. (Alice Li / The Washington Post) Although shark populations are on the decline  as the global population of humans grows  so does the number of beachgoers splashing into sharks’ natural habitat. As the International Shark Attack File wrote in a report about 2016 shark attacks  “Shark populations are actually declining or holding at greatly reduced levels in many areas of the world as a result of overfishing and habitat loss  theoretically reducing the opportunity for these shark-human interactions. “However  year-to-year variability in local meteorological  oceanographic  and socioeconomic conditions also significantly influences the local abundance of sharks and humans in the water and  therefore  the odds of encountering one another.” Most people who get attacked by sharks survive  nature writer Sy Montgomery told The Washington Post last year. And people who get attacked are probably mistaken for something else by the sharks. Related stories from  Charlotte Observer At the site of Saturday’s attack  officials had posted signs warning visitors about the presence of sharks  according to KHON. They were expected to make a decision early Sunday about whether to reopen the beach. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/ddb823e037651617fc6fbc0b1a6df8a7.com/news/nation-world/national/n71nz8/picture207627834/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Shark</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article207627839.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
