<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/article207619319.html</field>
<field name="title">Near-perfect Paschall gives  Nova another 3-point shooter | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Near-perfect Paschall gives  Nova another 3-point shooter | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">South Park Magazine Villanova s Eric Paschall 4) reacts during the first half in the semifinals of the Final Four NCAA college basketball tournament against Kansas  Saturday  March 31  2018  in San Antonio. Villanova s Eric Paschall 4) reacts during the first half in the semifinals of the Final Four NCAA college basketball tournament against Kansas  Saturday  March 31  2018  in San Antonio. Near-perfect Paschall gives  Nova another 3-point shooter By RALPH D. RUSSO AP College Sports Writer April 01  2018 07 57 PM SAN ANTONIO Eric Paschall was close to perfect in the Final Four. The Villanova forward became the fifth player to go 10 for 11 or better from the floor in a Final Four game as the Wildcats thrashed Kansas 95-79 on Saturday night to advance to the NCAA Tournament championship against Michigan. Paschall  a junior transfer from Fordham  joins a club with some impressive members. Bill Walton set the standard for all Final Four performances  going 21 for 22 in UCLA s 1973 NCAA championship game against Memphis. Jerry Lucas of Ohio State in 1961  Billy Thompson of Louisville in 1986 and Sean May of North Carolina in 2005 all went 10 for 11 like Paschall. The 6-foot-7 junior s career-high 24 points included 4 for 5 from 3-point range. Paschall shot 28 percent from 3 last season  his first playing for the Wildcats after sitting out the 2015-16 championship year  and then he couldn t buy a bucket from deep early this season. He has found the range since and now is yet another 3-point threat for one of the best shooting teams in the country. The Wildcats set a Final Four record with 18 made 3s against Kansas. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW  Just working with coaches   Paschall said.  They did a great job of just staying with me  knowing that I was struggling and I didn t really think about it.  As freshman at Fordham  Paschall was one of the Rams  few weapons. He took a lot of 3-pointers because the team needed that from him  but he made only 31.5 percent. He transferred to Villanova after a coaching change at Fordham.  But as soon as we got him as soon as he came  the year he sat out  he worked really hard   Villanova coach Jay Wright said.  And he really became a pretty good 3-point shooter. And then he just struggled a little bit. And this summer he was a great 3-point shooter. And in the fall  great. And when he started this season it was unbelievable. He couldn t make a shot. And I know people are saying   Why do you let him shoot it?  But we knew  we had seen two years of him shooting the ball extremely well.  So we just said to him   Just keep shooting. We know you re a good shooter.   Paschall came in averaging 10.3 points and 5.3 rebounds per game  but he has stepped it up lately. In the East regional semifinal against West Virginia  he scored 14 points  and in the regional final against Texas Tech  he had 12 points and 14 rebounds.  He s a beast on both ends of the floor   guard Phil Booth said.  He s always been great defensively. Now offensively he s been picking up. It just shows how talented a player he is.  Along Omari Spellman  the 6-foot-9 redshirt freshman  Paschall gives Villanova two players big enough to bang in the paint and skilled enough to fit in the Wildcats  free-flowing offense.  Their size and athleticism really makes it difficult   guard Donte DiVencenzo said.  And their ability to step out and knock down 3s just opens it up for everybody else to get downhill  get in the lane. Get in the lane  make plays for one another and when you have it going like that you can play small and you can play big.  You can play Eric at the 5. Or you can play Eric at the 4 and Omari at the 5 and you don t lose anything.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/f603fc2986f6c437896754733a196342.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/article207619319.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
