<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/food-drink/article207275379.html</field>
<field name="title">Dilworth s Kenilworth Commons loses another small business | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Dilworth s Kenilworth Commons loses another small business | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Dilworth s Kenilworth Commons loses another small business By Kathleen Purvis Order Reprint of this Story March 29  2018 11 39 AM Another small food business has joined the list of places that have closed recently at Kenilworth Commons  the busy shopping center at East Boulevard and Kenilworth Avenue. Just Fresh posted a sign recently saying that its lease had expired after 17 years at the location and that employees would be moved to other Just Fresh locations. It joins a list of shops that have closed at the center  which is owned by Edens. Among those  Middle Eastern restaurant Kabob Grill  the coffee shop Dilworth Espresso (also called Kenilworth Espresso) and the Bag Lady  a small women s boutique. Other businesses at the center remain open  including the Italian restaurant Dolce and the popular doughnut shop  Duck Donuts. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. Edens hasn t returned emails or phone messages requesting information on the plans at the shopping center. Kathleen Purvis; 704-358-5236. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/food-drink/article207275379.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
