<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/state/north-carolina/article207513089.html</field>
<field name="title">Natural birth centers  NC politicians call for investigation  regulation after deaths</field>
<field name="name">Natural birth centers  NC politicians call for investigation  regulation after deaths</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 12 01 PM A leading state lawmaker is calling for a state investigation of a birth center in Cary where three newborns died in the past six months  and others say it s time for North Carolina to start licensing and overseeing the facilities that deliver hundreds of babies each year. Baby+Co. has halted deliveries at its Cary center as it reviews all newborn deaths there since it opened in October 2014. Four newborns its midwives were assisting with have died out of more than 1 200 births  according to the company. Deliveries in Cary will resume as soon as company officials are assured the facility is safe  but Baby+Co. is not obligated to share the details of its internal review with the public. Rep. Nelson Dollar  a Republican representing Wake County  said in an interview late Friday that he will ask the N.C. Department of Health and Human Services to conduct an investigation of the Cary site to assess the causes of the recent deaths and to guarantee public safety. Dollar said he expects Baby+Co. to cooperate even if the state health agency — which oversees hospitals  nursing homes  surgery centers and other facilities — doesn t have explicit legal authority to inspect and review the birthing facility.  This is an incredibly serious matter   said Dollar  who chairs two health care committees in the state House.  We need to have the answers to those questions and we need to have them from some neutral people who have the expertise to get to the bottom.  Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW In a statement emailed to The N O on Sunday  Baby+Co. said   We operate all of our centers to the same high safety and quality standards in every state we operate  many of which have specific birth center regulations in place. All of our centers are accredited with CABC and all of our nurse midwives are board certified. We welcome the opportunity to share our Complete Care approach with lawmakers and state healthcare officials.  Baby+Co.  which operates three birth centers in North Carolina and three others in Tennessee and Colorado  updated customers by email Thursday that its internal review is taking longer than expected. In the meantime  women are being taken to nearby WakeMed Cary hospital for deliveries with the support of Baby+Co. s nurse midwives who have practicing privileges at the hospital.  We are moving this review forward as quickly as possible  but our effort to be thorough means that it will take a little longer   the email said.  We know this is not the news you were hoping to hear  especially for our moms and families who are at term  but the safety of you and your baby is our top priority.  Regulation for midwives Professional organizations for birth centers and midwives say their practices are as safe as hospital deliveries for low-risk pregnancies  result in fewer unnecessary interventions  such as caesarian section deliveries and have the added advantage of costing half as much as a hospital birth. The deaths in Cary are prompting some in the state s medical establishment to rethink the state s hands-off policy toward natural birth centers. North Carolina is one of just eight states that allows natural birth centers to deliver newborns without a state license or state oversight. At the same time the state oversees more than 700 occupational licenses and permits  covering such professions as acupuncture  cosmetology  daycare and funeral services. Greg Griggs  executive vice-president of the N.C. Academy of Family Physicians  suggested that a spike in deaths at one facility seems to meet the definition of a situation that calls for state regulatory intervention.  This is one of the things where we need our regulatory bodies to be able to initiate their own reviews   Griggs said. North Carolina does enforce strict oversight of nurse midwives. The N.C. Board of Nursing licenses only nurse midwives with master s degrees  and does not allow other types of midwives  such as lay midwives  to deliver newborns. North Carolina is one of a handful of states where nurse midwives can t practice without an endorsement from a sponsoring doctor. Nurse practitioners have lobbied over the years to eliminate the sponsorship requirement  especially now that public officials are looking for ways to increase health care providers in underserved rural parts of the state. Still  some doctors remain wary of out-of-hospital births  even through the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists has declared that birth center deliveries with midwives are a safe option for low-risk pregnancies. Nurse midwife Maureen Darcey  who runs the Women s Birth Center in Chapel Hill  fears that the recent developments in Cary could embolden critics to push for stringent regulations that would make it difficult for birth centers to operate here.  It could get so onerous   Darcey said.  It could close me down possibly. Related stories from  Charlotte Observer </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/f8e55d91be432fbb03521734896b95f9.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/state/north-carolina/article207513089.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
