<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/opinion/editorials/article207416749.html</field>
<field name="title">Want to buy the Carolina Panthers? Here s the New Owner Application | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Want to buy the Carolina Panthers? Here s the New Owner Application | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">SHARE COPY LINK Aerial footage of Bank of America Stadium provides a different perspective to the home of the Carolina Panthers football team. Jeff Siner/John D. Simmons jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Aerial footage of Bank of America Stadium provides a different perspective to the home of the Carolina Panthers football team. Jeff Siner/John D. Simmons jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Want to buy the Carolina Panthers? Here s the New Owner Application By Matt Olin - Contributing columnist  Observer editorial board Order Reprint of this Story March 30  2018 08 57 AM While the sale of our Carolina Panthers is imminent  it’s not too late to think hard about what we want in a new owner. We could debate this all day  but perhaps the question is … what are the Panthers looking for? To answer that  I’ve tapped my underworld contacts to obtain a copy of the New Owner Application Form from deep within the Panthers organization. Many Bothan spies died to bring us this information  so let’s make the most of it. If you happen to be pals with the billionaire next door  feel free to print this out or cut it out of the newspaper and slip it under the wiper blade of their Lamborghini Veneno. 1) Legal Name  _______________________ (If your name is Wardell Stephen Curry II  don’t waste time filling this out. Please call 704-358-7000 immediately for bank wiring details. Operators are standing by.) Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. 4) Net Worth  __________ (If less than 2.5B  we’re done here.) 5) Do you desire sole ownership or partnership? _______________ If partnership  is Steph Curry involved? Y N (If yes  follow the instructions on question  1.) 6) What is your experience level with football? Owner | Part-owner | NFL player | Collegiate player | High School | Pop Warner | Madden ‘18 | Fantasy Football (If fantasy  what was your final 2017 ranking?) 7) Do you live in Charlotte? Y N If “No ” you know that Charlotte isn’t Charleston  SC  right? Y N If “No ” you know that Charlotte isn’t Charlottesville  VA  right? Y N 8) The Panthers are to Charlotte as  The Packers are to Green Bay The Rams are to Los Angeles A boat is to an anchor David Lee Roth is to Van Halen 9) What’s the proper way to address a group of people? “Y’all” “Ladies and gentlemen of the jury” 10) Do you practice nepotism? Y N 11) Do you practice reverse nepotism (e.g.  firing one’s own offspring)? Y N 12) Do you consider yourself a micro-manager? Not at all This question is poorly written; let me have a crack at it 13) How do you envision your involvement with the team?  Hands-on   Hands-off   Handsy  14) Please disclose if you maintain a friendship with any of the following individuals  Bill Cosby | Kevin Spacey | Mario Batali | Russell Simmons | Harvey Weinstein 15) Are you proficient with power tools? Y N (For example  could you fashion a makeshift tarp over Bank of America Stadium if Roger Goodell looks our way for the Super Bowl?) 16) Which of the following do you consider “essential”  Oxygen | Food | Luke Kuechly | Water | Thomas Davis | Shelter | Cam Newton 17) How do you feel about tattoos and/or end zone celebrations and/or the general concept of personal freedom of expression? 18) If your players refused to stand during the National Anthem  would you  Kneel with them Criticize them  then kneel with them  then criticize them 19) Please indicate your view on investing in the team’s future  I pay what I must for the future I pay what I must to win right now Who cares? Just raise ticket prices 20) How do you feel about the Carolina Panthers Official Fight Song  “Stand and Cheer”? Full-body dry heave set to music Kinda’ growing on me That cheesy tune is sacred 21) In football and in life  do you consider yourself risk-seeking or risk-averse? I play it safe Hold my beer – Riverboat Ron’s got nothin’ on me 22) What does the phrase “Keep Pounding” mean to you? It’s Miller Time Default assembly instruction for IKEA furniture Please provide 3 Professional References  (Note  as of January 26  2018  we no longer accept Stephen Wynn as a reference.) Email  mattolincreative@gmail.com </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/b66014a5e7f536c8c8dc9231ceff5b03.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/opinion/editorials/article207416749.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
