<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article203736124.html</field>
<field name="title">First Charlotte Observer photographer Jake Houston shot society  sports  and crime.</field>
<field name="name">First Charlotte Observer photographer Jake Houston shot society  sports  and crime.</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-07T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 07  2018 07 00 AM *Slideshow is below text* Jake Houston was the Observer’s first full-time photographer  signing on with the paper in 1929. It sounds like he loved his work and went about it with a twinkle in his eye. Jake spanned the technological gap between news photography done with big  bulky cameras  glass plates and flash powder  and today’s automatic  motorized miniatures. Perhaps more important  he bridged the gap between the news photographer of the 1920s and ‘30s  (who often was caricatured as loud  pushy  unshaven and sometimes uncouth) and the photographer of today  (in general  a vast improvement). - Fellow photographer Jeep Hunter  upon Jake’s passing It seems his first love was capturing sporting events  but Jake’s work filled the pages with all sorts of community happenings. He passed away in 1983 at the age of 80 and left a legacy of snapshots of life in old Charlotte. Today’s blog contains some of his work from the 1930s but there is so much more! I plan to show more of Houston’s work in future posts. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/9e1b6e61d9dc06c954687da5593003fa.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/fi030t/picture203736119/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/houston%2032%20carB</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article203736124.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
