<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article204929769.html</field>
<field name="title">What to do and see in Charlotte’s visual arts for the week of March 18</field>
<field name="name">What to do and see in Charlotte’s visual arts for the week of March 18</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-13T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 13  2018 03 28 PM Where to go Our suggestion for your best bet this week is “Shara Hughes  Bold Suns ” opening at SOCO Gallery 6-8 p.m. March 21. Originally from Atlanta  but currently living in New York  Hughes employs a bold palette and a variety of painterly techniques in her whimsical paintings – imagined landscapes the artist develops and builds as she works. Hughes studied at Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture  received her BFA from Rhode Island School of Design  and was selected for exhibition in the most recent Whitney Biennial. Among the works in “Wrestling the Angel” at the Bechtler  “Departure” by Linda Foard Roberts  2005. Courtesy of the artist Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW What to do Explore the new exhibition at The Bechtler Museum of Art. Curator Jen Edwards has spent years developing her latest curatorial project  “Wrestling the Angel ” an exhibition that examines the role of religion and spirituality in the work of seemingly secular  avant-garde artists. From Marc Chagall and Georges Rouault to contemporary artists – including North Carolina-based artists Thom Thoune and Cristina Cordova – the exhibition is sure to be engaging  thought-provoking and well-researched. Carol Cole’s “Circles in Mass” from the series “The Glass Menagerie for Tennessee Williams ” 1977. Courtesy of the artist Who to meet Meet Carol Cole  Greensboro-based artist  at her artist talk at 4 p.m. March 20 at UNC-Greensboro’s Weatherspoon Museum. “Carol Cole  Cast a Clear Light” is on view at the museum through June 17. For her talk  Cole – as both artist and collector – will share stories about her favorite artists  feminism  Southern literature and more in conversation with George Scheer  director of Elsewhere  and Anna Wallace  a 2018 UNCG MFA candidate in sculpture. While at the Weatherspoon  be sure to check out the exhibition by Sanford Biggers  the Falk Visiting Artist  on view through April 8. Sanford Biggers’ “Shifter ” 2014. Courtesy of the artist and David Castillo Gallery  Miami Each week  Grace Cote and Lia Newman offer Observer readers a to-do list on immersing yourself in visual arts around town. Newman is director/curator of the Van Every/Smith Galleries at Davidson College  Cote is senior coordinator at Jerald Melberg Gallery  and they collaborate on the blog HappeningsCLT (happeningsCLT.com). For a seasonlong visual arts calendar  go to  www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article172583126.html . </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/d86453b5db666b267f7de262c56aa6a3.com/entertainment/arts-culture/m77y33/picture204929764/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/horizartsweek</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article204929769.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
