<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article206848989.html</field>
<field name="title">What’s up this week in Charlotte’s visual arts?</field>
<field name="name">What’s up this week in Charlotte’s visual arts?</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-26T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 26  2018 01 59 PM Where to go We encourage art enthusiasts to travel to the N.C. Museum of Art for the opening of the highly anticipated exhibition “ You Are Here  Light  Color and Sound Experiences  ” opening with a party on April 7. This sensory  participatory  interactive exhibition is sure to impress  20 immersive art installations that range from large-scale light works to sound installations  videos  and more  by 15 contemporary  well-known artists including James Turrell  Olafur Eliasson  Bill Viola  Ragnar Kjartansson  Soo Sunny Park  Mickalene Thomas and Rafael Lozano-Hemmer  to name a few. The museum will host an all-nighter for the opening day  with tons of programming  beginning with a party and silent disco at 8 p.m. Other programs  including artist performances  will begin at midnight and run through 10 a.m. the next day  followed by a lecture by Lozano-Hemmer at 1 30 p.m. In this show  visitors will get a first view of the NCMA’s new acquisition  Yayoi Kusama’s “Light of Life ” a small  more bodily-scaled version of the mirrored “infinity rooms” the artist has become well-known for. Luckily  the work will remain on view permanently long after “You Are Here”closes in July  as Kusama’s works often are accompanied by long queues of curious visitors. “The Crossing ” 1996  Bill Viola; video and sound installation. Photo by Alessandro Moggi; courtesy of the Fondazione Palazzo Strozzi Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW What to do If you are an artist looking for an opportunity to exhibition your work in the area  apply for a 2019 exhibition at the Dalton Gallery at The Arts Council in Rock Hill. Your written proposal  10 hi-res images  corresponding caption list  resume  artist statement and $20 application fee are due by 5 p.m. Friday  April 6. The Arts Council has made the process easy by allowing artists to email  mail or hand-deliver their submissions. Learn more by visiting The Arts Council’s website at www.yorkcountyarts.org/2019daltoncall . Who to meet The South End Gallery Crawl on April 6 is a great time to meet artists  including those at C3Lab during their Art Open House from 7-11 p.m. (Note  the Gallery Crawl takes place from 5-9 p.m. at most venues.) With music from the John Brown Jazz Combo  and all alcohol proceeds benefiting Charlotte Community Toolbank  the event is an opportunity to see many different artists – among them  Linda Luise Brown  Mark Doepker  Micah Cash and Sharon Dowell – in their creative space. Each week  Grace Cote and Lia Newman offer Observer readers a to-do list on immersing yourself in visual arts around town. Newman is director/curator of the Van Every/Smith Galleries at Davidson College  Cote is senior coordinator at Jerald Melberg Gallery  and they collaborate on the blog HappeningsCLT (happeningsCLT.com). For a seasonlong visual arts calendar  go to  www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article172583126.html . </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/52f8353ee38e0d74f81828131babdb9d.com/entertainment/arts-culture/fin5ug/picture206848979/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Lozano-Hemmer,%201984x1984,%20view%201</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article206848989.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
