<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/national-business/article207629044.html</field>
<field name="title">Mexican front-runner  ruling party candidate start campaigns | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Mexican front-runner  ruling party candidate start campaigns | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">South Park Magazine Presidential candidate Jose Antonio Meade  with the Institutional Revolutionary Party PRI)  and his wife Juana Cuevas waves to supporters during a campaign rally in Merida  Mexico  Sunday  April 1  2018. Mexico will hold general elections on July 1. Presidential candidate Jose Antonio Meade  with the Institutional Revolutionary Party PRI)  and his wife Juana Cuevas waves to supporters during a campaign rally in Merida  Mexico  Sunday  April 1  2018. Mexico will hold general elections on July 1. Mexican front-runner  ruling party candidate start campaigns By MARK STEVENSON Associated Press April 01  2018 06 25 PM MEXICO CITY The front-running candidate for Mexico s July 1 presidential election formally opened his campaign Sunday in Ciudad Juarez  the border city that launched some of the country s key resistance struggles. Leftist Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador depicts his third run for the presidency as a historic battle against corruption and entrenched elites  on a par with the resistance to the French invasion of 1862-1867 and the 1910-1917 revolution. Ciudad Juarez served as a base in both struggles. Governing party candidate Jose Antonio Meade also launched his campaign Sunday in the colonial city of Merida  the capital of Yucatan state  one of the few governorships that his Institutional Revolutionary Party hopes to retain among the nine statehouses that will be at stake in the July elections. Meade is running third in the polls. He alluded to Lopez Obrador  saying   Don t let them take away the future of our children with false promises.  Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Still  Lopez Obrador seemed to dominate the other candidates  attention. The third major-party candidate  Ricardo Anaya of a left-right coalition  announced that he will hold news conferences at 7 a.m. every day of the campaign — a move that echoes the morning meetings with journalists that Lopez Obrador held daily when he was mayor of Mexico City in the early 2000s. A fourth candidate  former first lady Margarita Zavala  is running as an independent. While he has been accused of being a populist and a radical  Lopez Obrador has moved to the center and gave an opening campaign speech that could have played well in the Rust Belt of the United States.  Those who defend the current economic model talk about modernity  but they don t mention that this  modernity  is a synonym for the economy of the elite  one that benefits only a minority and excludes the majority   Lopez Obrador said.  They tend to put up the supposed benefits of NAFTA as an example  but the few benefits have come at an extremely high cost.  Like U.S. President Donald Trump  Lopez Obrador expresses some skepticism about the North American Free Trade Agreement. The candidate vowed that  we are going to be very respectful of the U.S. government  but we are going to demand they respect us Mexicans. Neither Mexico nor its people will be treated like a piñata by any foreign government.   We are not going to rule out the possibility of convincing Donald Trump that his foreign policy and  in particular  his contemptuous attitude toward Mexicans are wrong   Lopez Obrador said. He stressed that his main campaign promise is to end corruption. Echoing his favorite president  Benito Juarez  whose 1857 reform movement established secular government in Mexico  Lopez Obrador said   Just as Juarez separated the church and state  now we are going to separate economic power from political power.  He pledged to cut the country s value-added tax from 15 percent to 8 percent and double pensions for the elderly. Meade is trying to shake the image of corruption  low growth and high inflation and debt that saddles the PRI. His campaign logo doesn t even include the party symbol  and instead uses a series of three colored arrows or triangles representing the PRI and two tiny parties that are running in coalition. Meade promised equal pay for women  easier access to credit and more scholarships to study abroad. He made several other campaign promises  focusing on education  health care and public safety  and also pledged to  get corruption out of politics.  Meade has said in the past that Mexico should do more to stop U.S. guns from being smuggled into Mexico.  We are going to keep the weapons and money from reaching the criminals   he said. Mexico is suffering an upsurge in violence that seems to defy most solutions so far  and none of the major candidates has submitted a detailed plan on how to handle it. Meade proposed largely technical solutions to Mexico s problems  depicting himself as the future and Lopez Obrador as someone obsessed with the policies of the past.  This election boils down to a choice between two things  move forward together  or retreat   Meade said.  My proposal is to move forward ... that is why I am asking for the votes of people who want to build  not tear down  who want to unite  not divide  to advance  not retreat.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/c35120faf40e6d36fc23924ba5df62a6.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/national-business/article207629044.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
