<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/national/article207624149.html</field>
<field name="title">Oklahoma boy adopts cat with cleft lip  rare eye condition</field>
<field name="name">Oklahoma boy adopts cat with cleft lip  rare eye condition</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 01 22 PM Seven-year-old Madden Humphreys of Oklahoma was born with two rare conditions — different-colored eyes and a bilateral cleft lip. And he hasn t had it easy. Madden previously went viral for his anti-bullying video that his mom  Christina Humphreys  inspired him to make after he was bullied on the school bus. “Don’t be mean to other people that are different   he said in the video that was published in June 2017.  We’ve already been through a lot of hard stuff. Show everybody kindness! You’re missing out on a lot of awesome people if you’re being a poophead to them. Don t be a poophead! ... cause the most unlovable people need love the most.  Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. Now about 10 months later  Madden has a new best friend who helps him feel less alone  his mom said on Facebook last week.   A post shared by @ maddenandmoon on Mar 26  2018 at 3 18pm PDT Madden s mom told LoveWhatMatters that one of her friends had posted an image of a cat with eyes just like Madden — one hazel and one blue — in a cleft moms group. The kitty was at a Minnesota rescue group. But this cat didn t just have the same rare eye condition  known as complete heterochromia iridum. He was also born with a cleft lip  just like Madden.  We knew immediately that this kitty was meant to be part of our family   Humphrey told LoveWhatMatters.   ... we knew they were destined to be best friends.  Friends and strangers alike helped fund a road trip  so that we could adopt this sweet fur baby   she posted on Facebook.  We’re usually not spontaneous people  but we knew that we were meant to love this kitty   Humphrey told LoveWhatMatters.  Moon  the kitty  and Madden are the perfect companions for each other. In a word full of bullies and hateful words  we will choose to chase love. I think it’s safe to say that this kitty is love  and was certainly meant to be part of our journey and Madden’s journey.  Humphrey told Fox News that she didn t expect this story to go viral  but Madden and Moon have received national attention.  It started out as fun for the family and friends who knew Madden’s story  but if it can raise awareness for clefts  and maybe even spread a bit of kindness and positivity  we think that’s a good thing   she told Fox News. You can follow Madden and Moon s adventures on Instagram by following @maddenandmoon . </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/370a52559527ae2da0c919d355474590.JPG</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article207624149.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
