<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206827439.html</field>
<field name="title">Clint Bowyer wins at Martinsville</field>
<field name="name">Clint Bowyer wins at Martinsville</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-26T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 26  2018 08 13 PM Martinsville  Va. His car had just crossed the finish line  and yet there Clint Bowyer already was  driving backward. OK  so that’s a slight exaggeration. Even for as dominant as Bowyer was on Monday  winning his first NASCAR Cup Series race in over five years  nobody can really drive backward. Truth be told  it was more like this  Bowyer saw the checkered flag  crossed the finished line  and started celebrating right then  right there in the driver’s seat. His No. 14 car swerved and skidded and spun around and ... well  freaked out  just like Bowyer did. Just like Bowyer should have. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Why? Because Bowyer had been waiting a long time for this victory – and while we’re at it  let’s just get all these damning statistics out of the way at once. Bowyer’s previous NASCAR Cup Series victory came more than five years ago  back at Charlotte Motor Speedway on Oct. 13  2012. That’s 1 990 days ago  after a snow delay postponed this race until Monday. More than five years  190 races  six second-place finishes. All with nothing to show. Oh  and one more thing about that Charlotte victory – it was Bowyer’s third victory of the 2012 season  his most in any one year. The man was at the peak of his professional career ... and then  poof. All the winning went away. Until now. “You start to question if you can get it done or not ” Bowyer said. “It was just time.” But enough of the statistics  and talk of streak-snapping and drought-ending. That’s in the past now. What matters now is how Bowyer won (dominantly) and how he celebrated (epically  at least if the beginning was any indication). Bowyer was in contention from the onset of Monday’s race  finishing fifth in Stage 1 and second in Stage 2. But almost as soon as the third and final stage began  Bowyer burst to the front of the field. Various challengers – mainly Ryan Blaney and Kyle Busch – nipped at his rear bumper  but no one could ever fully catch him. Speaking of that rear bumper  and really Bowyer’s entire car  it was practically unscathed when it did finally cross the finish line. Bowyer led 215 laps Monday  more than he has the past four years combined  largely because nobody was ever really close to him. Or at least it was unscathed until Bowyer’s antics after the checkered flag. Then the spinning  the twirling ... at that point  Bowyer’s car was like a drunk ballerina  as wild to watch as it was beautiful. At one point  Bowyer almost wrecked into the wall  and the next he was standing on his roof  smoke pouring out of the hood  pumping his fists with the crowd. “Something just felt right about today ” Bowyer said. “That’s that burden that’s been haunting me for a long time. It’s finally off your back  and you can finally have confidence knowing that you’re a winner again.” It was then that Bowyer  whose personality is practically unrivaled among the top NASCAR drivers  got his long overdue moment in the spotlight. He bowed with the checkered flag. He high-fived dozens of other crew members and drivers who congratulated him. Heck  he even signaled for a beer from the crowd (although sadly  nobody tossed one down for him). And then  Bowyer looked down the track and saw a tiny blond-haired boy running toward him – Cash  his 3-year-old son. Bowyer stopped any partying  any celebrating  and took off like a sprinter to his boy. He scooped Cash up into his arms and hugged him  tight. Then he handed his son the checkered flag that had so long eluded them both. “He told me he wanted a checkered flag ” Bowyer said of his son and their conversation before the race. “I told him this morning  I was like  ‘We’ve got to get our picture in Victory Lane.’ “One thing that’s always missing is a picture with him  you know ... really it’s the one thing that I don’t have. ... You start to think about what really matters in life  and the one thing that I didn’t want him to go through life as is not to know what this was all about.” As Bowyer finished up his post-race interviews  Cash never left his side. He waved his – yes  it’s his now – checkered flag and sat smiling on his daddy’s lap. He sucked on his fingers. And while his dad sucked down a tall boy and joked with reporters  photographers clicked pictures to capture it all. Someone just make sure the Bowyers get a copy. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/3c7dbd6b00b00ab637e2ab849bc2e803.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/q3sod5/picture206925024/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Nascar2</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206827439.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
