<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/national-business/article207633174.html</field>
<field name="title">Community fights over downtown demolition  revitalization | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Community fights over downtown demolition  revitalization | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Community fights over downtown demolition  revitalization The Associated Press April 01  2018 07 03 PM RENO  Nev. A controversial demolition of a series of aging motels is proving to be a focal point in an evolving fight over downtown Reno s future. Elected officials and some business owners hope for the revitalization of a part of town many people think is gross and scary  while historic preservationists fear an out-of-state developer s vague redevelopment plans will destroy homes and Reno s history  the Reno Gazette-Journal reported . Colorado-based gambling and hospitality company Jacobs Entertainment started buying and demolishing properties last year on six downtown city blocks to pave the way for a new  Fountain District.  Jacobs plans to revitalize the area to include fountains  retail  parking garages and eventually housing to accompany existing casinos  Jacobs told the Gazette-Journal last year. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW The El Ray Motel  Keno and Star of Reno motels on Fourth Street all were demolished. The surrounding Mardi Gras  In-Town  City Center and Keno 2 motels and several houses are all next  according to permits filed with the city of Reno.  And for all the naysayers regarding Jacobs Entertainment and the progress and demolition of these places; you haven t lived it  you haven t been there holding a young teenager as she has been held captive in the sex trade   Farrah Reed posted on Facebook after last week s demolition.  You haven t witnessed an overdose death of a neighborhood regular.  Reed managed the El Ray  Keno and Star of Reno motels before Jacobs bought them this year. Now she manages the Townhouse Motor Lodge.  I m happy to see change in the city of Reno because it s stagnant   Reed said.  It s at the stage where it s going to be vibrant and it s breathing new life into the downtown area. I absolutely believe in (Jacobs ) vision and I believe it ll be the best for Reno. I love Reno  it s my hometown  it s my place  it s my roots.  Local historic preservationists  who call themselves the Motel Team  and the Society for Commercial Archaeology decried the destruction of the midcentury architecture and Reno s tourism origin story when they learned of the plans to take down more buildings at a quick pace.  Last week we lost the majority of the Block  which was not retained but went to a local landfill   Corri Jimenez  leader of the Motel Team and a preservation professor  wrote in a Facebook group. The Motel Team calls the block of motels behind 3rd Street Flats  the Block.  Other history enthusiasts are rallying to protect other midcentury motels that Jacobs plans to raze. Neon preservationist Will Durham wants to save the motels  neon signs  which represent a particular style of design unique to the time period when the motels were an integral part of Reno s commerce. Because of Nevada property laws  Jacobs Entertainment doesn t have to show anyone its plans until it files a planning application with the city. In the absence of information  people on social media have started making up their own ideas for what Jacobs will or won t do. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/national-business/article207633174.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
