<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/article207165194.html</field>
<field name="title">Family Dollar agrees to pay $45 million to settle long-running gender bias lawsuit | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Family Dollar agrees to pay $45 million to settle long-running gender bias lawsuit | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-28T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">South Park Magazine Matthews discount retailer Family Dollar  owned by Dollar Tree  has agreed to pay $45 million to settle a gender bias lawsuit that dates back to 2002. Observer file photo Matthews discount retailer Family Dollar  owned by Dollar Tree  has agreed to pay $45 million to settle a gender bias lawsuit that dates back to 2002. Observer file photo Family Dollar agrees to pay $45 million to settle long-running gender bias lawsuit By Katherine Peralta Order Reprint of this Story March 28  2018 04 22 PM Matthews discount retailer Family Dollar has agreed to pay $45 million to settle a gender bias lawsuit that dates to July 2002. According to the settlement   37 000 female managers of Family Dollar stores allege that they were paid less than their male counterparts for doing the same job  a violation of Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and the Equal Pay Act of 1963. The settlement pertains to compensation paid to affected store managers from July 2002-November 2017. The settlement did not spell out the exact pay disparity. According to details in the settlement  49 female store managers and their counsel filed Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) charges which alleged a pattern and practice of discriminatory wages paid to women as a class at Family Dollar since July 2  2002. U.S. District Judge Max Cogburn in Asheville signed off on the settlement March 14. He said the deal is reasonable and would help avoid further litigation  according to Reuters. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. Family Dollar denied any wrongdoing  saying that contends that it  has treated all employees fairly with regard to salaries and other compensation at all times  regardless of sex.  Virginia-based Dollar Tree  which bought Family Dollar in July 2015  declined to comment on the settlement. In addition to the $45 million settlement  the retailer also agreed to a review of its process for setting starting salaries for managers  according to a notice of the class action lawsuit. To do so  the company said it will consult with experts in fields such as labor economics and industrial/organizational psychology. Family Dollar operates over 8 000 stores throughout the country. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/ae3b9fb3305f1626d3bb824bf83cdcbf.JPG_2_1_0T583PCO_L139406905%20(2)</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/article207165194.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
