<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article162073333.html</field>
<field name="title">Urban renewal in Charlotte NCs historic First Ward in photos.</field>
<field name="name">Urban renewal in Charlotte NCs historic First Ward in photos.</field>
<field name="created">2017-07-19T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story July 19  2017 07 00 AM Fed up with urban renewal that left people with nowhere to go  a group of First Ward residents in the ‘70s sued the city and won. In part  the city agreed to relocate several old houses to Eighth Street and make them available to low-income Charlotteans. But time marched on and by 2005 the houses were about to be replaced by new construction as discussed in this editorial. See slideshow for photos of the houses being readied to go on the market in 1979  as well as a recent photo of the homes there now. An Observer editorial  January 18  2005 Relics of Past Wrongs  First Ward houses have history city might prefer to forget A casual visitor to uptown s First Ward neighborhood might overlook the nine small houses along Eighth Street. If they were noticed  the visitor might wonder how they came to be there. They re older than the new development around them  and they re oddly suburban  with large grassy lawns in an area of small  city-sized lots. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Developer Bobby Drakeford wants to demolish four of the century-old houses to make room for a 16-unit condominium project. Some  but not all  of the neighbors object. The city s planning staff favors the development. The city-county historic landmarks commission  which last year studied uptown properties  didn t think the houses were worth designating as historic properties. But those humble houses tell a story  one the city and its leaders should not be allowed to forget. They are there because of the City of Charlotte s years of bulldozing black neighborhoods and its callous indifference to the housing needs of its poorest residents. They are there because some First Ward residents finally got fed up with the city s brutal urban renewal of the 1960s and 1970s. They took the city to court. They won. The city lost. The houses are proof. In the 1950s and  60s  the city had plunged eagerly into so-called  urban renewal    using federal money to bulldoze the black Brooklyn neighborhood in uptown s Second Ward. In his  Sorting Out the New South City    Charlotte historian Tom Hanchett wrote that the demolitions displaced 1 007 Brooklyn families.  Not a single new housing unit went up to replace the 1 480 structures that fell to the bulldozer    he wrote. By the  60s  federal officials threatened to cut off the funding spigot unless the city built housing to replace what it was destroying in Brooklyn and predominantly black First Ward. Thus was born in First Ward  in 1967  Earle Village  a large public housing complex redeveloped in the 1990s. The First Ward residents  1972 lawsuit pointed out that cities using federal urban renewal money were required to relocate displaced residents into affordable units that met the housing code. Charlotte hadn t done that. U.S. District Judge James McMillan ordered the city to comply. The city dragged its heels. More and more of First Ward was being demolished. Waiting lists for public housing grew. The suit lingered for a decade. Eventually  the judge stopped all First Ward demolitions until the city met his orders. By 1979  the city had agreed  among other things  to build apartments and to move some houses onto Eighth Street  mostly from elsewhere in First Ward. It is some of those houses that Mr. Drakeford s proposal would demolish. Mr. Drakeford s project should move ahead. First Ward s destiny is  eventually  to be an urban environment. Even today  one street of small houses on large lots looks odd  in the context. But it would be good if at least one or two of those little houses survived. They serve as reminders of the city s once-shameful legacy of urban renewal - and as monuments to the courage of those who challenged that legacy and won. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/07c1866edd6e24f2f62ba2cad27ddeac.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/m4dib4/picture162073318/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/8%20viewA</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article162073333.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
