<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/opinion/op-ed/article207510404.html</field>
<field name="title">Don’t be misled by hoopla in Charlotte anesthesiologists dispute</field>
<field name="name">Don’t be misled by hoopla in Charlotte anesthesiologists dispute</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">My take on who pays for Atrium’s losses In response to “Changes at Atrium Health won’t compromise your safety” (March 28 Opinion)  Atrium Health claims to absorb $5.1 million of healthcare expenses daily. It occurs largely because by law they can’t turn anyone away at the ER. Such a daily loss should quickly render Atrium terminally bankrupt  but you and I provide the financial remedy that keeps it alive. The loss is factored into our health insurance premiums  or in dumbed-down service at inflated prices. Various governmental departments also provide funds  which is a distribution of the taxes we pay. The Obamacare tax on those who chose not to buy insurance paid for up to half of what Atrium loses. Voiding that tax let the leaches return the burden to our backs with premium hikes  higher co-pays  and reduced service. William J. Powers  Waxhaw I expect action from Wells on guns  NRA Wells Fargo CEO Tim Sloan asks if we really want banks making gun policy. In a perfect world  no  but we live in a nation where corporations are people and money equals speech. Most Americans favor common sense gun laws  yet the NRA has effectively blocked all such efforts. As the NRA’s banker  Wells Fargo has a golden opportunity to repair its damaged reputation by exercising its influence over them and any other gun-related organizations opposing sensible regulations. My wife and I will pull our money if Wells does not take meaningful action. That alone won’t make them change  but if enough fed-up Americans do so  it might. Nothing else has worked. Bob Thomason  Charlotte Outraged by white America’s silence In response to “Emotions run high at funeral for man shot by police” (March 30)  When will we stop criminalizing and stigmatizing our citizens based on the pigmentation of their skin? I am an outraged white woman – outraged at the lack of accountability we demand from law enforcers  outraged that yet another young black man’s death is likely to become yet another statistic. But mostly I am outraged at the deafening silence coming from my own white community. Our silence does bestow our consent. Call the Sacramento District Attorney’s office. Demand justice for Stephon Clark! Debbie Snowdon  Denver  N.C. Way I see it  Bolton favors endless war In response to “John Bolton is a great addition to the White House” (March 26 Opinion)  If John Bolton is such a smart guy  why are we still in endless wars in Iraq and Afghanistan? Why didn’t he fix the North Korea mess when he was in power? Bolton’s “full range of options” only includes nuclear wars  conventional wars  endless wars  unwinnable wars  and pointless wars. Anybody else see the pattern? If you were already afraid of the fact that Donald Trump has control over “the button ” now we have a top adviser telling him to use it. Bill Reeside  Fort Mill Red-light cameras protect pedestrians The City of Charlotte received a National Planning Achievement Award last week for its Charlotte WALKS plan. Anyone who has walked the broken sidewalks of midtown and uptown Charlotte has witnessed the large percentage of distracted drivers who simply feel no need to stop at a red light and who seem oblivious to what a pedestrian crosswalk is actually for. Police enforcement is almost nonexistent. That combined with numerous sidewalks closed due to never-ending construction projects makes it an extremely unfriendly place for any pedestrian. Bringing back much needed red-light cameras would be a good start. Bill Whitesides  Lincolnton </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/opinion/op-ed/article207510404.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
