<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article206068519.html</field>
<field name="title">What’s up this week in Charlotte’s visual arts?</field>
<field name="name">What’s up this week in Charlotte’s visual arts?</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-20T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 20  2018 04 07 PM Where to go The Light Factory’s 10th Juried Annuale opens March 29 from 6 30-8 30 p.m. in its Plaza Midwood exhibition space. Jurors Nate Larson and Marni Shindelman chose five winners from a record-breaking 225 applicants  Owens Daniels (Winston  N.C.)  William Douglas III (Chesapeake  Va.)  Leah Edelman-Brier (St. Paul  Minn.)  Luther Konadu (Winnipeg  Manitoba) and Christine Zuercher (Dayton  Ohio). The two jurors are a collaborative team who investigate “the data tracks we amass through networked communication through photography and video installation.” This bodes well for a diverse and interesting exhibition. What to do Elder Gallery of Contemporary Art’s Millenial Art Program will host Wendy Hickey at 6 p.m. March 28 for a lecture about her successful ArtPop Street Gallery program. The initiative to put art on billboards began in 2014 and since then she has provided a platform for 97 artists in Charlotte  and art billboards in 13 other cities. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/d7f2c01a5886b41c97417202221c4195.com/entertainment/arts-culture/uviy7c/picture206068504/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Owens%20Daniels_Father%20and%20Son</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article206068519.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
