<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article207464209.html</field>
<field name="title">1996  Judge  Let  Angels  play  Controversial work opens to street protests | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">1996  Judge  Let  Angels  play  Controversial work opens to street protests | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 30  2018 05 15 PM This story was originally published on March 21  1996. For the next 10 days the curtain will rise on  Angels in America  without risk of Charlotte authorities stopping the performance  forcing changes or arresting the actor who strips nude during a hospital scene. A last-minute court order Wednesday secured opening night for the tense cast and crew of the Pulitzer Prize-winning epic  which played without protest in city after city until it reached Charlotte. A group of Christian conservatives tried blocking the show over scenes of nudity  profanity and simulated sex. Even after the legal victory  some expected an outburst during the nude scene  but when Charlotte actor Alan Poindexter dropped his blue slacks and for seven seconds faced the audience naked  no one said or did a thing. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW In the hours leading up to the show  Charlotte Repertory Theatre and a cadre of lawyers led by the flamboyant Bill Diehl scrambled to sue a long list of people with the power to interfere with the long-awaited performance at the North Carolina Blumenthal Performing Arts Center. Protesters march along North Tryon Street in front of the Performing Arts Center on March 21  1996. A last-minute court order secured the 10-day run of the show. Observer file photo by GARY O BRIEN  We got this case at 12 30 and put together nothing short of a miracle   Diehl said triumphantly at the courthouse  waving a copy of the temporary restraining order Superior Court Judge Marvin Gray signed just before 5 p.m. The order prevents interference from Charlotte-Mecklenburg police  the district attorney  the sheriff  state alcohol commissioners and others  including the uptown Performing Arts Center itself  which is Charlotte Repertory s landlord and whose threats triggered Wednesday s lawsuit. The Performing Arts Center said it would not allow the play to go on unless the theater promised not to violate the state s indecent-exposure law - or unless it obtained a court order banning authorities from enforcing the law. The showdown pitted two of the city s most prominent arts groups against one another. This round ended with Charlotte Rep winning on grounds that restrictions amounted to censorship and violated the theater s constitutional right to free speech. Citing U.S. Supreme Court rulings that nudity in an artistic setting is protected by the First Amendment  Gray wrote in his order   The play is an artistic presentation. Nudity . . . in the play appears to constitute artistic expression.  The order eased the rising tension surrounding the play s immediate future  Would the production feel forced to  tone down  the content as Mayor Pat McCrory suggested? Would the district attorney prosecute under the state s indecent exposure laws? Would the show go on at all? Victory in hand  Charlotte Rep s managing director  Keith Martin  hastily assembled a news conference at sundown  and paraphrased the last line of Part 1 of the play   The messenger has arrived. Let the great work begin.  As actors took the stage at 7 30 Wednesday night  two sets of protesters marched outside in the biting wind with homemade signs  some scribbled right there on the redbrick sidewalk. Pro- Angels  marchers (about 100) far outnumbered the anti (about 30) but the anti- Angels  leader  the Rev. Joseph Chambers  said   I don t think the number has anything to do with the strength. I have the support of the city council  most of the county commissioners. We have widespread support.  On March 21  1996  after an opposing group of demonstrators left  the Rev. Joseph Chambers led his group in prayer on the sidewalk in front of the Performing Arts Center. Observer file photo by GARY O BRIEN Some protesters chanted  others didn t; their signs said it all   Don t Tarnish the Queen City.   World Class? Try BACKWATER.   Homosexuality Is Not Art.   Move Along  It s Just a Penis.  Backstage  the cast  steeped in a week s worth of anxiety  got a chins-up fax from the play s New York author  Tony Kushner    . . . In times such as these I chant Martin Luther King s great statement  as a kind of protective mantra  The arc of the moral universe is long  but it bends towards justice.  Be splendid tonight  be focused  have fun  make theater  That s our way of repudiating the bullies  the killjoys  the busybodies and blowhards.   Angels  author Tony Kushner was guest of honor at a  Meet the Cast  champagne and dessert reception after the March 26  1996  performance. Guests Andreas Bechtler (left) and Dianne Hoover (right) were among the 400 people who attended the event. Observer file photo Kushner plans to be in Charlotte on Friday and Saturday for an AIDS benefit and a speech. Given the week s ruckus  he said Wednesday he wouldn t miss it.  I got to see this place with my own two eyes.  With the threat of Charlotte shutting down the play that has been hailed as the best this decade  the eyes of the city and nation watched  but only the 440 people who paid between $16 and $21 for seats inside the Booth Theater were privy to what the fuss is all about. The two-part play depicts  80s gay life in New York.  It s only just now that I m realizing what s been going on   said Steve Umberger  Charlotte Rep s artistic director.  This battle has got to be fought for Charlotte to get to the next artistic level.  The controversy is over a nude scene deep into Part I in which an AIDS patient slips out of his pants so a nurse can count his lesions. Facing the audience without a shred of clothing is vital to symbolize the character s vulnerability  Umberger said. It s trash  says Chambers  whose protest of  Angels  forced this week s confrontation. Chambers launched the protest in the name of the anti-pornography group Concerned Charlotteans.  I don t believe homosexuality is an art   said  Angels  opponent Dot Townsend.  It s a lifestyle that people choose  and it s wrong.  She has children and grandchildren.  I want to try to protect them from the evils of the world. I want them to grow up in a wholesome world.  Charlotte s longtime voice of moral outrage  Chambers has led the attack on  Angels   but Wednesday s legal maneuvers were prompted by the Performing Arts Center s actions. In a letter Wednesday to Charlotte Rep  Blumenthal Chairman James Thompson and President Judith Allen said the theater has been aware for months of the potential problems involving nudity and that the theater had  represented  to District Attorney Peter Gilchrist that it would try to produce the play in a way that would not violate the law. Thompson and Allen wrote that at a meeting on Monday  police and the district attorney advised them the play violates North Carolina s indecent-exposure statute.  You and your board of directors were urged to consider relative minor modifications of the scene in order to avoid violation of the statute   the letter said. Thompson and Allen then wrote   We urge you to provide us written assurances  satisfactory to us  that the scenes in question will be modified to avoid violation of the indecent exposure statute or to seek and obtain judicial relief enjoining enforcement of the statute.  The theater  Thompson and Allen added  had until 5 p.m. Wednesday to provide them with those assurances or get the court order. If they couldn t  Thompson and Allen said the Performing Arts Center s executive committee had told them to notify the theater that it would be violating its lease agreement  that the agreement would be terminated and no performances permitted. At 4 48 p.m.  Diehl sued. Keith Martin (left) of the Charlotte Repertory Theatre  and attorney Bill Diehl hold a news conference in March 1996 after the ruling on  Angels in America  was announced. Observer file photo by L. MUELLER  It s a great day to be a lawyer   said Diehl  of the law firm James McElroy   Diehl and well-known as the colorful bulldog of Charlotte s legal community. Hours later  inside the nearly packed theater  the 3-1/2-hour performance unfolded without a titter. The controversial scene happened around 10 30 p.m.  early in the third act  when AIDS patient Prior Walter  played by Poindexter  is in the hospital for a checkup. A low buzz moved through the audience. The actor took off his black turtleneck so the nurse could check for lesions.  Pants   the nurse said. Poindexter unbuckled his belt and pulled down his slacks. He was naked for seven seconds. The nurse finished checking. Poindexter pulled his pants back up. The scene went on. No one left. No one cheered either. In the audience sat some of those who had argued against this scene. Allen and Thompson  who tried to change the play or shut it down  sat together. They declined comment. Louis Bracken of Charlotte  in Wednesday s audience  had this to say   I think this has all been a good thing. We ve been talking about this a lot in our family. Even though some people oppose it  I think we ve been able to understand everybody s position a little better. I m just glad they let the play go on.  The restraining order expires in 10 days. But a week from today  Charlotte Repertory will go before Gray to fight for a preliminary injunction  which would protect the play until the lawsuit goes to trial. Part 2 of the play opens next month. Staff writers TED MELLNIK and TOMMY TOMLINSON contributed to this article. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/a81b9731624e4fab5f83ba8f62a7dcd1.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article207464209.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
