<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article207505484.html</field>
<field name="title">1996   Angels  is heavenly  Kudos to Charlotte Rep for tackling the work | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">1996   Angels  is heavenly  Kudos to Charlotte Rep for tackling the work | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 30  2018 05 16 PM This review was originally published on March 22  1996. If you go only by the headlines  the struggle over producing  Angels in America  in the North Carolina Blumenthal Performing Arts Center took place in demonstrations  lawyers  offices and a judge s chamber. Those of us who saw the opening performance of the Charlotte Repertory Theatre production Wednesday know better. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW We know that the real struggle took place over months as a group of theater professionals worked long hours to produce an amazing piece of art that deepens our understanding of ourselves.  Millennium Approaches   Part 1 of this Pulitzer Prize-winning  seven-hour epic  runs this weekend and next week. Part 2   Perestroika   opens in April. Both parts will be done together on the final weekend. Charlotte is believed to be the smallest city to produce its own  Angels ; many larger cities settled for the national tour. Be proud of Charlotte Rep. It not only won both struggles  it did so with grace  guts and dramatic flourish. Believing in Tony Kushner s work was the easy part. First performed in 1990 and taken to Broadway three years later  it has justifiably been called the play of decade.  Millennium Approaches  magically deals with cosmic issues of mortality  apocalyptic history and personal responsibility while staying focused on the individual lives of its main characters  A gay couple  one with AIDS and the other unable to deal with it; a married Mormon couple  she a Valium addict who hallucinates trips to Antarctica and he just acknowledging he is gay; and Roy Cohn  based on the real-life anti-communist who died of AIDS in 1986 still in denial about his homosexuality. The world they live in is New York in 1985-86  a time when AIDS began its devastating toll and when the Reagan presidency sought to roll back civil rights. Kushner s characters are funny even as they limp through the tortures that haunt their lives. At a funeral  a rabbi says America is  the melting pot where nothing melted.  A psychotic street person in the Bronx says   In the new century  I think we will all be insane.  When the Mormon says he is  going to hell  for his homosexual longings  his new gay friend asks   You think it could be any worse than New York City?  Kushner s sensibilities are on the left of center  but you cannot call the play s issues black-and-white. The  good guys  do things they are not proud of. The  bad guy   Roy Cohn  is portrayed as a human being. This play began at a very small theater in San Francisco. On Broadway  it acquired high-tech trappings that at times overshadowed its intimacy. It s nice to have  Angels  back in the regional theater. And few in this country s network of regional theaters are better at bringing together a play s threads of intimacy than Charlotte Rep director Steve Umberger. In his hands   Millennium  returns to its roots of palpable pain  infectious laughter  face-to-face coping. Like the small production at London s Royal National Theatre  Umberger and set designer Joe Gardner use platforms pushed on and off by stagehands to handle Kushner s dense piling-on of scenes. Eric Winkenwerder s deft lighting helps us navigate through scenes that occur simultaneously on different parts of the stage. Gardner  with help from Sandra Gray  uses an arch of crumbling stone and panels that simulate chain-link fence to give the play an architectural  gritty and urban feel. Winkenwerder s lights make the ultimate scene  where an angel crashes through the roof  a strobe-light revelation. Hans Stegmeir s costumes are full of fancy; his snow-bunny outfit for the Antarctic hallucination must be seen to be fully appreciated. But this production excels best in its portrayals of the characters. Graham Smith  Charlotte s best actor  is a slender  quietly burning Roy Cohn. He is not as sputtering and saliva-spewing as were the Cohns in New York and London productions. He is just as rabid  but in a more controlled  smoldering and believably human way. As Prior Walter  the young man with AIDS  Alan Poindexter for the first time brings together the two elements that have made his work so memorable in the past. He does the outlandish  cross-dressed  drag-queen thing  but he is also a serious actor whose character s pain and wonder cannot be ignored. Scott Helm  formerly a boy wonder with a Jimmy Stewart face  becomes a man with his conscientious  considered Joe Pitt  the tortured Mormon. Opposite him  New Yorker Tamara Scott does hallucinating Harper Pitt as sometimes almost invisible and lighter-than-air and at others burdened with all the weight of the world on her back. Winston-Salem playwright and actor Angus MacLachlan wears a little sneer on his lip and carries an intellectual chip on his shoulder as Louis Ironson  Prior s lover. His nonstop verbal diarrhea is hysterical; his frustrated tenderness so human. Mary Lucy Bivins takes on four roles (including two male parts and a spectral Ethel Rosenberg  the convicted spy whom Cohn succeeded in sending to the electric chair)  as does Barbi Van Schaick (including the Angel and her hauntingly beautiful voice). New Yorker Kevin Free switches seamlessly from former drag queen Belize to Harper s imaginary travel agent  Mr. Lies. The production is not flawless. A scene depicting a random sex act in a park needs sharpening so the actors don t anticipate each other; the scene in which Poindexter disrobes for a medical examination is rushed and lacks the emotional impact it could have; the middle of three acts is sometimes flaccid; the angel takes too long to crash through the ceiling; when she finally does  her costume is postmodern ridiculous. This theater company deserves two standing ovations every night. One at the opening curtain for being brave enough to put  Angels  on. And another at the closing curtain for doing it right. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/811bcf5321bf20f0d782951a7be9fa74.com/entertainment/arts-culture/cdh29m/picture207513489/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/angelsalan</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article207505484.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
