<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article205055854.html</field>
<field name="title"> Waitress  in Blumenthal s Broadway Lights series</field>
<field name="name"> Waitress  in Blumenthal s Broadway Lights series</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-14T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 14  2018 11 24 AM What are little girls made of? Sugar  butter and flour  according to the opening words of the stage musical “Waitress” – sugar for sweetness  butter (perhaps) because they make the elements of life blend together smoothly  flour for the salt-of-the-earth quality that lets them adapt to any situation. Those ingredients (and memories of mother’s love and recipes) combine in the emotional core of the title character. If you have seen the 2007 movie of the same name  you know Jenna’s story. She’s coping with an unwanted pregnancy  a no-longer-wanted husband who controls her  a too-much-wanted gynecologist with whom she’s having an affair  and the dream of opening a long-wanted pie shop. “Waitress ” now at Belk Theater for a week on its Broadway Lights tour  has been billed as a feminist show. Never before had a group of women occupied the four key roles in creating a Broadway musical  composer (Sara Bareilles)  director (Diane Paulus)  choreographer (Lorin Latarro) and librettist (Jessie Nelson  adhering closely to the story Adrienne Shelly wrote for the film). The three main characters – Jenna and her waitress pals  shy Dawn and ribald Becky – take the last bows and get the only character development. Yet the men aren’t quite stereotyped as villains  Pie shop manager Cal has a beneficent side beneath his boorishness  mean-spirited husband Earl clings to Jenna partly from desperation  and gawky Dr. Pomatter seems as foolishly overwhelmed by passion as Jenna when they meet during an examination. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. Desi Oakley and Spartanburg native Larry Marshall in “Waitress.” Joan Marcus The story’s about finding your place in the world  more than finding it in a relationship  As faux-curmudgeon Joe reminds Jenna  your dream need not be focused on another person. The pie shop owner’s even cuddlier here than in the movie version  which says something about the softening of the material; Spartanburg native Larry Marshall  an indelible Sportin’ Life in “Porgy and Bess” 40 years ago  sings Joe’s “Take it From an Old Man” in a resonant tenor. That number’s a memorable exception in a score where almost half the important songs are “This is who I am” proclamations. Becky (Charity Angel Dawson) has a moment of glory revealing her unseen sexual side in “I Didn’t Plan It.” OCD oddball Ogie (Jeremy Morse) steals the first act – as he’s meant to do – with madcap dancing in “Never Getting Rid of Me.” Dawn (Lenne Klingaman) expresses her lonely dreaminess in “When He Sees Me ” never imagining she and Ogie will be soulmates. Jenna has many such numbers  from her longing for past independence in “She Used to Be Mine” to her philosophy about piemaking in “What Baking Can Do.” Desi Oakley  sometimes plaintive and sometimes powerfully heartbroken  sings these ballads beautifully. (If anything does make this a feminist musical  it’s that none of the men has a “This is who I am” song except Ogie  the least masculine character.) Director Paulus last came here with a spectacular if shallow “Pippin.” She has taken her main strength in that show – an ability to keep a three-ring circus moving at all times – and  with contributions from choreographer Latarro  made it work here. The action flows around the stage  almost as if characters were on unseen roller skates  while members of the chorus whirl among the principals to hand over props or snatch them away. Paulus and the ensemble make sure these unnamed characters have lives  too  Look anywhere  and you’ll see every person fully invested in what’s going on. Even the musicians in the onstage six-piece band  conducted from the piano by Jenny Cartney  become silent participants in the narrative. That’s why the two-hour-and-45-minute show feels long only when Bareilles stops to repeat a musical point she’s already made  never when the characters swing into action again. ‘Waitress’ When  7 30 p.m. Wednesday-Thursday  8 p.m. Friday  2 and 8 p.m. Saturday  1 30 and 7 p.m. Sunday. Where  Belk Theater  130 N. Tryon St. Running time  165 minutes. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article205055854.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
