<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/opinion/article207419239.html</field>
<field name="title">Charlotte s got a lot  but it needs a new slogan | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Charlotte s got a lot  but it needs a new slogan | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Can Charlotte improve on this slogan? Can Charlotte improve on this slogan? Charlotte s got a lot  but it needs a new slogan By Mark Washburn - Contributing columnist  Observer editorial board March 30  2018 05 11 PM This is harder than you might think. It s time to retire our tourism slogan   Charlotte s Got A Lot.  It s time for something new to magnetize the town. I ve been struggling. Paris or Key West might be easier. But here are a few suggestions  ▪ Not as boring as Raleigh. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. ▪ Where Kemba Walker watches the NBA playoffs. ▪ Building a better airport since 1983. ▪ Only hours from everything! ▪ You can drive south from the city without getting stuck on a stupid tollway. ▪ Where America comes to build apartments. ▪ See our TV forecasters go apoplectic about thunderstorms. ▪ Make yourself at home. Toss your bike anywhere. ▪ No medical or law schools to mar your view. ▪ We have several nice parks. ▪ Frequent trains to the airport (freights). ▪ Site of a really big convention in 2012. ▪ Where the traffic barrel was invented. ▪ Not flat like Indianapolis and easier to spell than Cincinnati. ▪ Three PBS stations  and we don t watch any of them. ▪ Poke around - it s possible there s still some gold somewhere. ▪ Our taxes are so low we can t afford to build highways. ▪ Convenient to historic Salisbury. You see what we re up against here. Fact is  we re a nice place  but nothing spectacular. Bombastic Atlanta is a like sparkling painted lady. We re like her sweet little sister who sells Mary Kay. Charlotte s got a little - of everything. We re low hassle  high satisfaction. We ve got good museums for everything from aviation to stock cars  a dynamic core  pro teams that break our loyal hearts and we get just a little bigger and better each day. Progress has always been the biggest word in our lexicon. So  maybe this  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/3634a7437118b1a7ccdcbacd515185de.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/opinion/article207419239.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
