<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/latest-news/article206825829.html</field>
<field name="title">Charles Frazier  Cold Mountain author talks about new novel  Varina</field>
<field name="name">Charles Frazier  Cold Mountain author talks about new novel  Varina</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Friends remember Quail Ridge Books owner Nancy Olson  She was just delighted to be sitting there at the table   he said.  It was one of the most wonderful things that happened to her.  Frazier  in a recent telephone interview from his Florida home  talks about what intrigued him about Varina Davis and his writing process. Fact versus fiction Q  How much of Varina Davis’ story is based on facts versus fiction? How much creative license did you take? A  I took a lot  but the framework is factual. The thing that caught my attention  I had no intention of ever writing about the Civil War era again  I had zero interest in her husband. But the first thing I read was that shortly after (Jefferson Davis) died  she moved from Natchez  Mississippi  to live in New York City. At age 60  she went up there to be writer for newspapers  one of the Pulitzer papers. And made part of her living as a writer. Charles Frazier s fourth novel  Varina.  Ecco The other thing that caught my interest is that she and Julia Grant  Ulysses S. Grant’s widow  became friends. They purposefully did things together in public  where they would be seen. They felt like that was a symbol of reconciliation…. Then she said  and this made some Southern newspapers mad  she said publicly that the right side won. It really intrigued me that this woman — who had benefitted so greatly from the slave economy  slavery  and the plantation in Mississippi — was still evolving in her thinking in 1906. She would have days when she would say something incredibly retrograde  and then she would say something so positive and progressive. She was struggling with what had become of her life  being on the wrong side of history. … It’s only the greatest heroes in history  who are able totally rise above the values of their culture. She certainly wasn’t. But she was trying. How to Build a Novel Q  What’s your process of structuring and shaping a big novel? Do you have a model you use? A  Not really a model. Usually  I get an image or more than one image. It was really simple in  Cold Mountain.  (The character of) Inman was a straight line. Ada was a circle. It was kind of built around those two basic shapes. This one  the first picture I had of what the shape of the book could be is when she says those days after the Civil War  when she was fleeing with the kids  and Jefferson was back to doing what he was doing…she goes from being the first lady to a fugitive on the road. She says in the book   That’s the axle of my life.  Everything turns around that. I need to keep coming back to that part of the story  where the life she thought she had collapses in a matter of weeks. And the other thing  I didn’t want it to be chronological. It covers 70 years or more  but I wanted it more driven by memory than by the calendar. Right or wrong side of history Q  What insight does this novel provide in educating modern day readers about the Civil War? A  I hope some of the complexity of the years building up to the war  I hope that comes across. Country by country  slavery was being abolished  all over the Western Hemisphere. You name a country in South America other than Brazil  and they had abolished slavery. The writing was on the wall  but those slave owners who had the power refused to see this is coming to an end. We can be on the right side or the wrong side  and they chose what they chose. I wanted to show some of that. The strangeness of some of that odd plantation that Joseph (Davis’ older brother) and Jefferson Davis had in Mississippi  like that stuff about wanting to incorporate ideas ... about fairness to employees developed in factories from Scotland and England to a slave economy seems bizarre beyond belief. The friendship of bookstore owner Nancy Olson Q  Why did you dedicate the book to Nancy Olson? A  She was so supportive of me from the start  well before  Cold Mountain.  We were living close to the original location… I’d published a short story of mine in an anthology and a travel book for Sierra Club Books. When she found that out  she stocked those in the store. She included me in the community of the store.  ... She was there in New York for the National Book Award  at the table with me. She was such a positive supportive figure in my life. Guilty Pleasures Q  What are your guilty pleasures? A  What would that be? I don’t feel guilty about it. But I do spend time out in the woods  especially when I’m working on a book. If I’m in Asheville  a good chunk of the day  I’m out in the woods. The guy at the bike store…was introducing me to a customer and he said   This is what Charles does  he goes into the woods to think about his books.  No  that’s where I go not to think about what I’m working on. Bridgette A. Lacy is a freelance writer and the author of “Sunday Dinner  A Savor the South cookbook” by UNC Press of Chapel Hill. Reach her at bridgettelacy@att.net . Details Charles Frazier will talk about his novel  “Varina ” (Ecco  $27.99) at the following events. ▪ April 17  7 p.m. Quail Ridge Books  4209-100 Lassiter Mill Road  in North Hills Shopping Center in Raleigh. Reserve a signing line ticket with purchase. ▪ April 18  7 p.m. Flyleaf Books  752 Martin Luther King Jr. Blvd.  Chapel Hill ▪ April 19  6 30 p.m. Bookmarcs  634 W. 4th St.   110  Winston-Salem ▪ April 23  7 p.m. Books-A-Million  300 S. Firestone St.   200A  Gastonia Varina and Fuquay-Varina Triangle readers may wonder  Is the title of the book related to Fuquay-Varina  the town in southwest Wake County? Varina  the titular character in the book  is Varina Davis  the second wife of President Jefferson Davis. She is the first and only first lady of the Confederate States of America. She died in 1906 at the age of 80. Fuquay-Varina once was two separate towns  Fuquay Springs and Varina  which merged in 1963. Varina  the town  is named for the wife of a soldier named J.D.  Squire  Ballentine  according to Fuquay-Varina s website. A woman named Virginia Avery wrote Ballentine while he fought for the Confederate Army  and she signed those morale-boosting letters to him  Varina.  They fell in love  and later when Ballentine became the town s postmaster  he named the post office and a store after her. The Fuquay-Varina entry on Wikipedia speculates that Avery s signature is  an homage to the wife of Jefferson Davis.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/d4823258430f3fd0d125641bf36ea738.com/latest-news/amjg2o/picture207191314/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/RAL_%20Charles%20Frazier%20author</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/latest-news/article206825829.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
