<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/article206924669.html</field>
<field name="title">Gallery  Charlotte Knights vs Chicago White Sox | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Gallery  Charlotte Knights vs Chicago White Sox | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-26T20:10:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Email The skyline of Charlotte  NC is reflected in a Chicago White Sox batting helmet at BB T BallPark on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Charlotte Knights manager Mark Grudzielanek  left  reaches out to hug Chicago White Sox Rick Renteria  right  during batting pratice at BB T BallPark on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com The Charlotte Knights and Chicago White Sox pose together at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox Nicky Delmonico  right  signs autographs for fans at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Members of the Chicago White Sox run at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com The Chicago White Sox take batting practice at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox Tyler Saladino walks past the shadows of fans waiting for autographs at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox first baseman Jose Abreu smiles as he talks with passerby along the team s dugout at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox right fielder Avisail Garcia  right  congratulates centerfielder Adam Engel  left  after Engel scored a run against the Charlotte Knights at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox right fielder Avisail Garcia  left  is congratulated second baseman Yoan Moncada  right  after Garcia hit a two-run home run against the Charlotte Knights at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Former Chicago White Sox pitcher Jack McDowell  waves to the team dugout prior to throwing out the first pitch at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Former Chicago White Sox pitcher Jack McDowell  throws the first pitch at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox second baseman Yoan Moncada smiles as he prepares to step into the batters box against Charlotte Knights either Donn Roach at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox third baseman Yolmer Sanchez  right  congratulates second baseman Yoan Moncada after Moncada scored a run against the Charlotte Knights at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox pitcher Reynaldo Lopez throws a pitch to a Charlotte Knights batter at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox shortstop Tyler Saladino  left  tags Charlotte Knights runner Jose Rondon  right  out in a run down at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Members of the Chicago White Sox enjoy their teammates play against the Charlotte Knights at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox second baseman Yoan Moncada  left  breaks back to first base ahead of a throw to Charlotte Knights first baseman Casey Gillespie  right  at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Chicago White Sox right fielder Avail Garcia  right  runs the bases after hitting a two-run home run as Charlotte Knights third baseman Patrick Leonard  left  looks on at BB T BallPark in Charlotte  NC on Monday  March 26  2018. The Charlotte Knights hosted the Chicago White Sox their parent club in baseball action. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com 1 of 19 </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e4bba7d32121c76090a51866b60fd3b2.com/sports/rf3lcw/picture206924574/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/WHITESOX_KNIGHTS_01</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/article206924669.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
