<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article200520714.html</field>
<field name="title">Elder Gallery s  Art of Struggle  highlights Charlotte artists Charles Farrar  MyLoan Dinh  Susan Brenner</field>
<field name="name">Elder Gallery s  Art of Struggle  highlights Charlotte artists Charles Farrar  MyLoan Dinh  Susan Brenner</field>
<field name="created">2018-02-16T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">February 16  2018 12 47 PM Uncomfortable questions  complex feelings  alternative perspectives? Bring them all on for “The Art of Struggle.” The exhibition now at Elder Gallery of Contemporary Art features three Charlotte-area artists – MyLoan Dinh  Charles Farrar and Susan Brenner –and the show is the passion project of Sonya Pfeiffer  the gallery’s relatively new owner and a full-time civil rights and criminal defense lawyer with Rudolf Widenhouse in Charlotte . Her goal  “Use art as a vehicle for discussion.” So the three submitted and created pieces for the exhibition with the stated goal of addressing “the consequences of our complex unresolved history around race and gender.” Each spoke in a panel discussion Feb. 13; the show is on view until Feb. 28. Here’s a look at four key players of “The Art of Struggle”  Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. “One Nation ... For All” by MyLoan Dinh. Courtesy of Elder Gallery of Contemporary Art MyLoan Dinh Dinh’s multimedia pieces in the exhibition are inspired  she said  by modern-day movements like  MeToo and Black Lives Matter  as well as her experience leaving Saigon as it fell in 1975 and coming to the United States as a refugee. Enter the gallery and you’re met with one of her large works  to the left  titled “One Nation ... For All.” It’s an American flag constructed from life jackets  symbolic of her family’s escape on the last Navy ship before the city fell  she said. During the discussion Tuesday  she spoke of being at sea with tens of thousands of people who “couldn’t go anywhere because no one wanted us.” A U.S. Navy ship awaited word from Washington on what to do about the refugees crowded onto boats  she said  but the wait stretched on. Ultimately  Dinh said  the Navy helped refugees by lowering the Vietnamese flags on their boats – which were deterring help from other nations – and raising American ones. “It’s only because people felt that life  dignity and compassion were more important than politics and policy that I’m here ” Dinh said. “That’s what it means  One nation ... for all.” Charles Farrar’s “Homage to Sharecroppers.” Courtesy of Elder Gallery of Contemporary Art Charles Farrar Woodturner Farrar said he was inspired for this exhibition by the struggle his parents faced as he was growing up  and that of his ancestors who were slaves brought to “cultivate the earth.” He noted that each of his turned wood pieces  exhibited from Charlotte to the White House  contains a personal piece of his ancestry. (One example  A family wedding-gift vessel  atop which he placed as a finial a tiny piece of wood from a plow an ancestor had owned.) In the exhibition  his “Homage to Sharecroppers” was made with spalted maple wood and rings from the hub of a wagon wheel his parents used on their farm. Growing up  Farrar witnessed the unfair treatment of his parents as they worked to make a living off the farm in southern Virginia due to their race  he recounted  in an array of ways – like having to find someone to bid on farm property for them  because if they placed the bids themselves  they were likely to be “passed over” or ignored. Farrar  based in Concord  also thought about by the creative and industrious way his parents survived despite adversity  and finds it an honor to pay tribute to them and his ancestors who may have often felt the “struggle was for naught ” he said. “I understand in telling my story I have to try not to appear ungrateful  but it’s important to me to tell the stories of those who cannot tell it themselves.” And he applauded the exhibition concept  He laughed about his initial hesitation about a Dinh collaborative idea – a photographic work created for the show – but decided to go along  because “Already  in its infancy almost  this gallery evokes respect.” Susan Brenner Brenner’s work in the exhibition is unique in that the majority of it was created in 1990-91  but she said she found it deeply and newly relevant to modern struggles with gender roles and feminism. Brenner  a painter who also works with photography  digital imaging  drawing and installation  was raised by a single mother and is no stranger to these issues  she said. “It does amaze me how relevant they are now. They seem relevant in ways I couldn’t have imagined.” “Susanna and The Elders” is the first image you see when you enter the gallery  a complex painting that draws from the portrayal of women in marketing and media as well as from an addition to the Book of Daniel . She hopes her pieces evoke emotion and offer new perspectives  she said  “Things have to be made strange... to make you stop and think and see.” Sonya Pfeiffer Pfeiffer came into possession of the gallery last year after she and her husband  David Rudolf  had dinner with longtime friend and former owner Larry Elder. When he mentioned he was retiring and selling the space  the couple shared one look  she said  and knew they wanted to be the next owners. She asked Elder to continue working under the previous name  tweaking it slightly to Elder Gallery of Contemporary Art. She’d like to show both commercial art and exhibitions that speak to relevant and at times controversial issues  she said  Because she works on wrongful convictions cases  she’d like to explore many of the issues she sees people dealing with at work  in a non-threatening way – art. And she’d like to get people talking about it. Pfeiffer says she’s still learning as she goes  but she plans to have a section of activist art in the gallery somewhere at all times during commercial shows  and every few months will do a larger-scale activist show like “The Art of Struggle.” The next socially charged exhibition she’s planning will happen this November and explore veterans’ issues. She’s not ruling out any shows or ideas that might pop up as the months come. “We’ll see ” she said  shrugging and smiling. “We’ll see how the world turns.” </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/bb4d941c3c70d83f8832985c954a77f4.com/entertainment/arts-culture/tnf2z5/picture200520709/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Susan%20Brenner%27s,%20Susanna%20and%20the%20Elder%27s</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article200520714.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
