<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article151198557.html</field>
<field name="title">Gallery  Catwalk for a Cause | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Gallery  Catwalk for a Cause | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2017-05-18T00:59:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Email Amy Earnhardt  left with husband Dale Earnhardt Jr.  center  walk the catwalk during the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport with Camden  right  on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Sherry Pollex  left and boyfriend Martin Truex Jr.  right  hosted a Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Pollex is a caner survivor. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Aric Almirola  center and his wife  Janice Almirola  right  walk the red carpet to the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Joey Logano  center/left  laughs with his wife  Brittany Baca  right/back to camera share a laugh as they wait to enter the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR drivers Ricky Stenhouse Jr.  left and Jamie McMurray  right  wait on the red carpet to enter the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Brian Kelley  left and Tyler Hubbard  right  of the group Florida Georgia Line pose for photographs with an autographed helmet they received as a gift from NASCAR driver Martin Truex Jr. prior to entering the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR drivers Ricky Stenhouse Jr.  left and Danica Patrick  right  walk the red carpet to enter the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Aric Almirola speaks to members of the media on the red carpet to the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Sherry Pollex  left and boyfriend Martin Truex Jr.  right  host a Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Pollex is a caner survivor. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR drivers Danica Patrick  left and boyfriend Ricky Stenhouse Jr.  right  wait to be interviewed prior to entering the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Florida Georgia Line members Brian Kelley  front/left and Tyler Hubbard  back/blocked speak with NASCAR driver Martin Truex Jr.  back/right and his girlfriend Sherry Pollex  right/front  prior to entering the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Pollex is a cancer survivor. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Sherry Pollex  left and her boyfriend NASCAR driver Martin Truex Jr.  right pose for photographs prior to entering the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Pollex is a cancer survivor. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR drivers Danica Patrick  left and Ricky Stenhouse Jr.  right  smile while being interviewed prior to entering the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com A ice sculpture for Catwalk for a Cause is one of the centerpieces during the casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com A woman is silhouetted behind a screen as she dances during the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Sherry Pollex  left and her boyfriend NASCAR driver Martin Truex Jr.  welcome guests to the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Amy Earnhardt  left with husband Dale Earnhardt Jr.  center  walk the catwalk during the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport with Camden  right/back to camera  on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Danica Patrick  left  waves to spectators as she carries Kingston  right  down the catwalk during the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport with Camden  right  on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Janice Almirola  left  Devin  center and NASCAR driver Aric Almirola  right  strike a pose as they walk the Catwalk for a Cause catwalk during the casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Sherry Pollex  right  is embraced on the red carpet prior to the Catwalk for a Cause casino night and charity event at the Statesville Municipal Airport on Wednesday  May 18  2017. The proceeds are going toward cancer research. Pollex is a caner survivor. She and boyfriend NASCAR driver Martin Truex Jr.  hosted the event. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com 1 of 20 </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/9bd1f28304731ccf5259efe0e1d4694e.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/r70mej/picture151198457/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/NASCAR_CATWALK_17</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article151198557.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
