<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/state/north-carolina/article207448554.html</field>
<field name="title">Bathroom bill  HB2 replacement still draws fire on anniversary</field>
<field name="name">Bathroom bill  HB2 replacement still draws fire on anniversary</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 30  2018 01 07 PM RALEIGH It has been exactly one year since the N.C. General Assembly passed its compromise to repeal House Bill 2  commonly referred to as the  bathroom bill   which required residents to use the bathroom in public facilities that matched the gender on their birth certificate. The partial repeal bill — House Bill 142 — was passed in a single day  after lawmakers had negotiated throughout the week with Gov. Roy Cooper. The days leading up to the repeal were emotional for some lawmakers  including Rep. Deb Butler  a New Hanover County Democrat who was just weeks into her appointment and at that time one of only two openly LGBT members of the General Assembly.  I remember thinking this was a fine welcome   Butler said this week.  It was trial by fire for me as a freshman legislator. I had to get over any other apprehension I had about speaking on the floor and speaking to the press.  Butler and Rep. Cecil Brockman  a Guilford County Democrat — who is bisexual — both gave floor speeches on March 30  2017  opposing the repeal. Brockman noted that no LGBTQ residents or activists were involved in crafting the compromise bill. Butler at that time noted that  this is so much bigger than basketball   referencing the fact that when the bill was crafted  North Carolina was under a deadline from the NCAA to repeal HB2 or be out of the running to host future sports championship games. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SHARE COPY LINK Senate leader Phil Berger  R-Rockingham  calls the HB2 repeal passed by the Senate on Thursday a compromise that accomplishes a pre-HB2 reset while still protecting North Carolinians.  Compromises are ofttimes difficult to get to  and sometimes di Video by Clifton Dowell  Photo by Chris SewardNCInsider.com House Bill 142 as written effectively repealed the law enacted in 2016 and left bathroom regulation up to the state  while also enacting a moratorium on local nondiscrimination ordinances that  among other things  allow transgender individuals to use the restroom corresponding with their gender identity. That moratorium remains in place until Dec. 1  2020. But there s still a lot that is unknown about what the bill actually means for members of the LGBTQ community. Matt Hirschy  interim executive director of Equality N.C.  said he still gets calls from businesses asking about what HB 142 does. But one thing is certain  he said  Since the repeal passed  members of the LGBTQ community  do not know who their champions are.   I think the replacement for HB2 sent a clear signal that basketball meant more than the well-being of the community   Hirschy said. He noted there is a continual lack of understanding of which lawmakers members of the LGBTQ community can trust and look to for leadership. Many Democrats (and even a few Republicans) campaigned on needing to repeal HB2. Hirschy said some of those members who campaigned on HB2 repeal voted for HB142  but  they re not exactly the same thing.  HB 142 isn t considered a  clean repeal  since it contained other provisions like the moratorium. SHARE COPY LINK Gov. Roy Cooper hosted a press conference after signing a compromise bill passed by he General Assembly on Thursday that replaces House Bill 2 but restricts anti-discrimination ordinances in cities and counties. Travis Longtlong@newsobserver.com Last year  when the repeal was passed  Cooper caught a lot of flak for not including members of the LGBTQ community in the negotiations for the repeal. Hirschy said he believes Cooper is a good man who believes in LGBTQ equality but that Cooper  fails to consistently consult the community  when it comes to issues directly impacting them.  What the governor is lacking is a member of his direct staff  a member of his leadership team that is a consistent champion on these issues that he believes himself to be.  Butler said she is  absolutely clear  that Cooper respects and includes the LGBTQ community  but the situation last year was  moving quickly  and she doesn t believe the exclusion of any community stakeholders from the negotiations was willful. Progressive groups aren t the only ones who are still unsatisfied with how HB142 came about.  HB142 is not an acceptable or permanent solution  because the repeal of HB2 left the state without a clear  unequivocal policy ensuring privacy and safety in public bathrooms and showers   Tami Fitzgerald  executive director of the N.C. Values Coalition  said in a statement.  If Governor Cooper is not willing to protect the freedom  privacy  and safety of women and children of North Carolina in multi-stall facilities  he should provide funding in his budget for construction of single-facility bathrooms and showers for public buildings.  SHARE COPY LINK Rev. Mark Creech of the conservative Christian Action League explains why he s disappointed in the House Bill 2 replacement that many Republicans voted for Thursday. Colin Campbellccampbell@newsobserver.com The movement for repeal came amid economic pressures as companies were boycotting the state or pulling out of deals to bring new jobs. During an event on Thursday  Cooper said if it wasn t for the repeal of HB2  Amazon wouldn t be considering having its second headquarters located in North Carolina. Also this week  PayPal CEO Dan Schulman discussed why his company spoke out against HB2 and pulled the company s planned expansion out of the state. SHARE COPY LINK Chris Sgro  Equality North Carolina director  says the HB2 replacement bill is terrible legislation that doubles down on discrimination. Travis Longtlong@newsobserver.com  [W]hen we made the announcement to go into North Carolina  we were obviously with the governor announcing an expansion  putting in an operations center there where we were going to hire at least 400 people. But shortly thereafter HB2 came out. I read through that bill front to back personally  met with members of my senior team  and from my perspective that bill allowed for the discrimination or the potential discrimination of somebody because of their sexual identity  their sexual orientation   Schulman said on Harvard Business Review s HBR IdeaCast podcast.  And from my perspective we could not just have these values be something that were hanging up on a wall  but we had to act upon them.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/14da900705ab44e45a79ccb7e3efa075.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/state/north-carolina/article207448554.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
