<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article204320339.html</field>
<field name="title"> Lion  Witch  Wardrobe  at Children s Theatre of Charlotte</field>
<field name="name"> Lion  Witch  Wardrobe  at Children s Theatre of Charlotte</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-09T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 09  2018 12 46 PM Actors usually know they’ve got a grip on audiences when they hear noise  laughter in the right places  involuntary responses of joy or anguish  bursts of applause. With kids  you measure success by silence. They rarely clap until the end; even then  they may be responding to the urging of a teacher or a parent. If you hear nothing – especially the nothing that comes when they stop wriggling and giggling and start listening – you’re a hit. So the pin-drop quiet during a school performance of “The Lion  The Witch and the Wardrobe” bodes well for Children’s Theatre of Charlotte. Youngsters needed to work their imaginations full-out for an hour to envision C.S. Lewis’ Narnia  aided only by two actors and half a dozen significant props on Tim Parati’s unfussy set. They did so easily. The script by South African actress Le Clanché du Rand opens in a room with a hat rack  a couple of trunks  a hobbyhorse and the iconic wardrobe  portal to a land outside human time. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW The adult Peter and Lucy (Mark Sutton and Leslie Giles) revisit the house where their adventures began  telling us the story and playing all the parts  Not only Edmund and Susan  their siblings  but timid Mr. Tumnus  optimistic Mr. Beaver  the power-mad White Witch and the saintly lion Aslan  Lewis’ Christ figure. (Lewis wrote the book in the late 1940s  in a Europe still recovering from Nazism; people sometimes think the Witch  who turns her world to a winter where Christmas never comes  represents Hitler.) CTC artistic director Adam Burke took the helm for this show and makes minimalism pay off. When the children pass through the wardrobe into Narnia for the first time  David Fillmore’s lighting illuminates a backdrop with a few pine trees and wisps of falling snow. Characters change quickly and simply  Peter becomes snivelly Edmund by donning glasses and rounding his shoulders  while Lucy converts to the older Susan by shoving her hands in her pockets and dropping her voice. Sutton and Giles snap into characters quickly and smoothly  so the young audience never gets lost. Things that may sound ridiculous in print don’t raise a laugh onstage. Narrator Peter embodies Aslan by adding resonance to his voice (with help from sound designer Jason Romney) and holding aloft a sofa pillow bearing the face of a lion. When the siblings re-enact a swordfight with umbrellas  Romney adds metallic clangs to make the battle seem less like childish hijinks. Completists will fidget at du Rand’s condensation. It eliminates Professor Kirke and all the battles and gives short shrift to Susan  who might have been cut entirely from this version without being missed. The death of Aslan inspires no pathos in a story told so swiftly  He’s slain  he’s resurrected  we move along. Yet the author develops all of Lewis’ important themes  The need for quarreling allies to unite in the face of a monstrous enemy  the sacrifices necessary to defeat evil  the presence of a power greater than humanity that can change the fate of the world. If you want to pack those ideas into a cheerful and uplifting tale that lasts only an hour – just about the length a young audience can observe respectfully – this is the way to go. ‘The Lion  the Witch and the Wardrobe’ WHEN  Through April 15  mostly at 7 30 p.m. Friday  11 a.m. and 3 p.m. Saturday  2 and 4 p.m. Sunday. Sensory-friendly performance March 17 at 11 a.m. ASL sign-interpreted performance March 24 at 3 p.m. WHERE  Wells Fargo Playhouse  ImaginOn  300 E. Seventh St . RUNNING TIME  60 minutes without intermission. TICKETS  $12-$28. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/194465a08eed67bfe534eac60503c4a4.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article204320339.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
