<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article200166344.html</field>
<field name="title">‘The government called her work subversive; now it’s in museums. What has she learned? | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">‘The government called her work subversive; now it’s in museums. What has she learned? | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-02-14T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">SHARE COPY LINK Sonia Handelman Meyer  who recently turned 98  recounts her photographic journey as a street photographer in New York City and offers advice for those just getting behind the camera. John D. Simmons jsimmons@charlotteobserver.com Sonia Handelman Meyer  who recently turned 98  recounts her photographic journey as a street photographer in New York City and offers advice for those just getting behind the camera. John D. Simmons jsimmons@charlotteobserver.com ‘The government called her work subversive; now it’s in museums. What has she learned? By Lisa Rab Order Reprint of this Story February 14  2018 06 46 PM On the living room wall of her Park Road apartment  Sonia Handelman Meyer keeps a framed black-and-white photo of elderly women huddled together outside the Hebrew Immigration Aid Society in Manhattan. She shot the image with a Rolliecord camera in the late 1940s  after World War II ended and New Yorkers were recovering from the Depression. Meyer slipped inside an open gate to find the Jewish refugees waiting in line at the aid society. She also captured images of African-American children playing in the dirt in Harlem  and volunteered to shoot pictures of the city’s first interracial hospital. “Children  Harlem” by by Sonia Handelman Meyer. Sonia Handelman Meyer Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Meyer was a member of the Photo League   a group of  artists who set up a school  darkroom  gallery and salon in Manhattan to produce work that was both aesthetically beautiful and politically potent. Their members included Lewis Hine  whose photos of children working in factories helped prompt the U.S. government to enact child-labor laws. “Tax Booth at Jehovah s Witness Rally” by Sonia Handelman Meyer. Sonia Handelman Meyer In 1947  the U.S. Attorney General blacklisted the Photo League as a “subversive” organization. The FBI later accused League co-founder Sid Grossman of being a Communist  and the fallout led the League to shut down in 1951. Meyer  who had recently married  began spending time in the foothills of the Catskill Mountains  where her family was building a house. She had children and drifted away from her camera. Her photographs were packed up and largely forgotten for decades. “That’s been one of the wonderful things in the last few years ” says Meyer. “At the exhibits  people of all ages and of all backgrounds have come over to me and talked about the pictures  and been grateful for them.” John D. Simmons jsimmons@charlotteobserver.com But her son  Joe  wouldn’t let them stay buried. He started sharing her prints with friends in the art world in Charlotte  and in 2007  Hodges Taylor Gallery mounted a show of Meyer’s work called “Into the Light.” National attention and exhibitions followed. Meyer now has images in the permanent collections of the Jewish Museum in New York  the Metropolitan Museum of Art and Bank of America. “I was shy about it ” says Sonia Handelman Meyer  now 98  reflected here in her circa-1940s photograph “Girl on Stoop  Spanish Harlem.” Her work  with the Photo League in New York  is now in museums. To other photographers  she offers this advice  “Open yourself up.” John D. Simmons jsimmons@charlotteobserver.com This winter  just before her 98th birthday  she shared her thoughts about photography  social justice  and the importance of believing in yourself. The following has been edited for brevity and clarity. “The war ended the Depression but there [were] still difficulties of getting jobs. And it was harder for women to get jobs. Some of our women [at the League] began to make a name. I didn’t  I never pursued it.” “I was shy about it. I never had very much confidence. … I was given an entree to one of the Life editors  one of the photography editors at Life. And it was pretty early on. I took my work up to show her  and she liked it very much. And she said  ‘Come back in one year and I’ll see more of your work.’ And I never went back.” (Meyer pauses  then chastises herself. “Stupid.”) “I’m not a technical photographer. I’m an emotional photographer.” (She laughs). “I saw something that hit me  and I’d shoot it and go. Because if you stuck around  you became involved in it. I saw what I wanted  I saw what I felt. That was it.” “Once  three little boys kept following me  saying. ‘Take my picture  take my picture.’ And I wouldn’t do it because I didn’t like to pose them. Finally  after several blocks of this I said  ‘OK  OK.’ I took it and they posed themselves.” (This became the photograph titled “Boys  Spanish Harlem.” ) “Boys  Spanish Harlem” by Sonia Handelman Meyer. Sonia Handelman Meyer “I was secretary [at the League] at the time we got the notice that we were on the attorney general’s list. One of the newspapers called  I don’t remember anymore which one. And they told me that the Photo League had been put on the attorney general’s subversive list. And I said  ‘Heavens to Betsy  what have we done now?’ And he [the reporter] thought that was very funny. I thought it was funny too  but I didn’t realize how serious it was.” “When Sid Grossman was named as a Communist  everybody got really frightened. People were losing their passports  losing their jobs  and they had to leave. And that destroyed the Photo League. It was a great tragedy.” “After the Photo League stopped  our family was changing. For one thing  my family was building a house up in the mountains in New York state. And I discovered nature. It was nice. And I started to shoot in color  I have a lot of color slides – some of them are good  not all. And I learned a lot about flowers and trees and weeds. That was a whole new kind of life that I found important and beautiful and I liked. Really part of the same thing  isn’t it?” “I think what happened to the Photo League really destroyed some of my feeling about photography. It was so unjust  it was so cruel  so destructive. I really think that had something to do with my backing off from it.” “I regret not having continued to shoot. I would be interested in what I did.” (She laughs). “I regret that I didn’t try to do more in the early days – showing my stuff around. It was such a surprise to me here when that first exhibit in 2007 came  ‘Into the Light.’ It really was a surprise to me. A very happy one. … That’s been one of the wonderful things in the last few years  At the exhibits  people of all ages and of all backgrounds have come over to me and talked about the pictures  and been grateful for them and liked them – loved them.” “I wish I had known that I had this talent.” Lisa Rab is a Charlotte-based journalist whose work has appeared in Harper’s and Politico Magazine. Reach her at lisarab.com. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/28e1744474e19979b8576e44029edf58.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article200166344.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
