<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/education/article207441949.html</field>
<field name="title">Charlotte police chief wants gun scanners at all CMS schools</field>
<field name="name">Charlotte police chief wants gun scanners at all CMS schools</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-31T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 31  2018 02 17 PM All Charlotte-Mecklenburg schools should restrict entry to one point and  wand  all who enter  whether students or adults  Police Chief Kerr Putney told concerned parents Thursday. Putney  who has been meeting with Superintendent Clayton Wilcox about school safety in the wake of a Feb. 14 mass shooting  acknowledged the change will be costly and inconvenient. But he called it essential to keeping guns out of schools.  You re going to have to give up some level of freedom to get this right   the Charlotte-Mecklenburg police chief said at a town hall meeting at Steele Creek AME Zion Church on Thursday night. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. CMPD Chief Kerr Putney Diedra Laird dlaird@charlotteobserver.com Parents repeatedly questioned Putney about how to protect schools against shooters. Students and others concerned about school safety have staged walkouts and marches since a gunman in Parkland  Fla.  killed 17 students and faculty at Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School. Putney said he is working with CMS to provide better  active shooter  training at all schools  with specifics tailored to each campus. Wilcox has yet to release details of his plans to bolster school safety. While Putney repeatedly praised Wilcox s work on the matter  it seems unlikely that Putney s vision of airport-style screening at every campus will materialize soon. Consider  for instance  West Charlotte High  which has 15 buildings and multiple parking lots on a sprawling campus. Last year voters approved a bond package that will replace that setting with a single modern building  the kind Putney says is much easier to secure against intrusion. The West Charlotte project is budgeted for $110 million   with completion in 2022. Now consider that CMS has 176 schools  and dozens include multiple buildings and/or mobile classrooms. That means students  staff and volunteers are coming and going throughout the school day. And the largest schools have more than 3 000 students  which would create a bottleneck if all were scanned at the start of the day.  We re going to have to make a lot of structural adjustments   Putney said Thursday.  It s not as simple as I would like. It s not as quick as I would like.  Wilcox recently said he plans to ask the county for about $9 million for physical improvements to fortify schools  such as fencing  surveillance and doors. He acknowledged that s a small fraction of what it would take to bring all schools up to ideal safety standards. His operating budget  which will be presented to the school board in April  is likely to include additional spending for staff to enhance safety  such as school psychologists and CMS police officers. Read More </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/d576fa77639cd3118784e84f1de6a1af.com/opinion/letters-to-the-editor/naup4l/picture207448964/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/SchoolMetalDetector%20CLT%200330</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/education/article207441949.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
