<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article207551864.html</field>
<field name="title">How to fix NASCAR? 8 legends offer opinions to repair racing</field>
<field name="name">How to fix NASCAR? 8 legends offer opinions to repair racing</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-31T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">▪ Rick Hendrick   Team owner and 2017 NASCAR Hall of Fame inductee. ▪ Bill Elliott   Former Cup Series champion  the 16-time winner of NASCAR’s Most Popular Driver award and father of current NASCAR driver Chase Elliott . ▪ Jeff Gordon   Four-time Cup Series champion and television broadcaster . ▪ Jimmy Bruns  Senior vice president of client services at GMR Marketing   with 14 years of NASCAR marketing experience. ▪ Kevin Harvick   2014 Cup Series champion and three-time Cup race winner  in 2018. ▪ Steve Phelps   NASCAR executive vice president  global sales and marketing officer. Discussions mostly fell into five areas – the quality of the racing  young drivers  the next generation of fans  television issues and NASCAR’s schedule. Those are the areas they saw as the most encouraging and the most challenging for NASCAR’s future. We divided the five into the following 20 categories  to start a conversation about NASCAR’s future. SHARE COPY LINK Former NASCAR driver and Hall of Fame member Richard Petty says that the biggest challenge NASCAR faces is getting new fans. Petty  known as The King for his 200 career wins and seven championships  believes that all sports are suffering for enter Jeff Sinerjsiner@charlotteobserver.com And they begin with the most basic suggestion  The racing needs to be less boring. In basketball  the pace of scoring can be furious. In football  a touchdown every few minutes. Even in baseball  there are innings where you’ll see back-to-back-to-back home runs. But in NASCAR? Well ... it can be 500 miles of follow the leader. One point that came up repeatedly in  the interviews was that the actual racing has to be better. More exciting  more entertaining. “Nothing is more important than the competition – how much passing you’ve got on the track  what kind of close finishes you have at the race  and the quality of entertainment that the race produces ” Wheeler said. “In my opinion  that’s first on the list because that is what’s going to eventually either keep people away from the grandstands or put them back in.” Wheeler said he thinks NASCAR’s rules changes in recent years have led to decreased passing  especially for the lead. That  he and several others said  is what fans care about. Watching four or five guys all battle for the lead  as was the case at the end of this year’s Daytona 500  creates drama and excitement – and rivalries  if those guys get tangled up. Close finishes and late passes for the lead  as was the case at the end of 2018 Daytona 500  make for exciting racing that NASCAR needs consistently. David Graham AP ... But it depends who you ask. Wheeler’s longing for the “good ol’ days” of racing isn’t universal. Harvick  who has three dominant victories so far in 2018  said the racing in NASCAR has never been more competitive – and therefore captivating – than it is now. “When you look at it from a realistic standpoint  the racing today is much better than it was in 1990 ” Harvick said. “It might not be talked about that way  but when you look at how competitive it is from front to back  it’s as competitive as it’s ever been. “It was kind of the the wild  Wild West (back then). Almost like it wasn’t really a professional sport up until you got into the 1990s.” And while Harvick’s status as a current driver influences his perspective  other panelists feel that way  too. “I think the racing’s exciting ” team owner Rick Hendrick said. “It feels like all the things the sport’s doing are exciting.” A common thread remains  The quality of racing still matters  even as the importance of at-track entertainment and social media surges. For that reason  NASCAR keeps tinkering with its rules – trying like any business to refine its product. SHARE Johnson is suddenly the senior statesman of the Hendrick team Davie Hinshawdhinshaw@charlotteobserver.com The best new rule? Stage racing. NASCAR introduced  stage racing – splitting the races into points-paying segments – last season. Before that  fans only needed to tune in for the last 25 laps to see everything that mattered. Likewise  drivers didn’t have to lead all day to be in contention at the end. Now  since points are awarded throughout the race  there’s added incentive for fans to tune in early. “When I’m in the booth I feel like I’m a fan  so I kind of look at it that way ” Gordon said. “I really was encouraged last year by the stages and the excitement – how it broke up the racing and the excitement  the competitiveness it added.” Harvick also said stage racing “has changed the sport in a direction unlike anything we’ve recently ever had ” because it encourages drivers to run their hardest for the duration of a race. Panelists said Bubba Wallace  a rookie in NASCAR’s Cup Series  has the personality and talent to become one of racing’s next superstars. John Raoux AP Basically  whatever NASCAR does  it has to be exciting. Stage racing seemingly is a positive step. Passes for the lead and rivalries among drivers help  too. The key  our panel agreed  is keeping things interesting. Long lulls are damaging; if a fan is bored at any point  other options can easily pull them away. “I firmly believe that NASCAR is the best racing on the planet and our product on the track is better now than it has ever been ” Phelps said. “Close  side-by-side racing is creating even more dramatic moments  fueling incredible performances and stoking intense new rivalries. “Our drivers learned just how important those stage points became at playoff time  and we are expecting an even more competitive 2018 season.” In short  idealizing the past serves no purpose. Instead  NASCAR must continue enhancing its product with rule changes that encourage close racing  bumping and the type of entertainment any casual fan would enjoy. “That’s what people think whenever they turn on the TV ” Wheeler said  “or decide to go to the race – is there going to be some exciting racing out there? “And if there’s not  then it’s dullsville  and things just keep going south.” Young NASCAR drivers such as Kyle Larson  from left  and Ryan Blaney are one of the most encouraging things the sport has going for it now  our panel said. Rick Scuteri AP Young drivers are the best thing NASCAR has going for it. There was no unanimous opinion among these eight NASCAR names ... except this one. All eight agreed the most encouraging thing in the sport is the influx of young drivers. “The youth coming into the sport  I think they’re changing the dynamics of where NASCAR is going ” Bill Elliott said. Elliott knows about that youth better than most  considering his son Chase  22  is part of the youth movement. Other promising young talents at the Cup level  Ryan Blaney (24)  Bubba Wallace (24)  William Byron (20)  Alex Bowman (24) and Erik Jones (21). But his point wasn’t just that there are  talented drivers under the age of 25. It’s that in a time when NASCAR’s most popular veterans are rapidly leaving the sport  the next generation is getting real opportunities to compete in top equipment. “There’s been plenty of young  talented drivers come into the sport  but they just don’t get highlighted because they’re not with a team that can showcase their talents ” Gordon said. “It’s not a Penske or a Hendrick or a Gibbs. “(But) that’s what we’re seeing right now ... that’s the unique thing.” SHARE COPY LINK NASCAR Cup Series driver Alex Bowman  has more starts than Hendrick Motorsports teammates Chase Elliott and William Byron. Davie Hinshawdhinshaw@charlotteobserver.com Opportunities exist for young drivers  but it takes more than talent. While these young drivers are good for NASCAR’s on-track product  there’s still work for them to do. “The reality is  we’ve been working for several years now and building the next group of young stars in our sport  and you saw many of them take that next step last year ” Phelps said. “The sport is in great hands  and it’s going to be exciting to watch these drivers develop into stars both on and off the track over the next 10-15 years.” “The biggest thing we need right now  the single biggest thing  is a dramatic new personality ” said Humpy Wheeler  former president of Charlotte Motor Speedway. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Winning  obviously  would help. But the other element  Phelps said  is showcasing their personalities. Wheeler agreed. “The biggest thing we need right now  the single biggest thing  is a dramatic new personality ” Wheeler said. “It’s just like when the PGA was floundering – then Tiger Woods pops up and bam ! If he didn’t play a tournament  nobody came or watched.” Does NASCAR’s next generation have a Tiger Woods? “That’s what we need ” Wheeler said. “Big time.” Who has that Tiger Woods-like potential? The two young drivers with the skill and personality to become a transcendent star? Blaney and Wallace stood out to our panel. Both are prominent on social media  where they paint themselves as regular young adults . And they openly show their emotions  such as when Wallace cried after finishing second in the Daytona 500 . Our panel also said Chase Elliott  with his name and demeanor  could end up as one the sport’s biggest stars. “The interesting thing about this young crop of drivers ” Bruns said  “is they’re the first digitally native group of drivers that have been on social media their entire life and have had that opportunity to showcase their personalities.” Gordon  a longtime teammate of Dale Earnhardt Jr.  said fan access to a driver’s personality was what helped Earnhardt win so many Most Popular Driver awards. Social media only provides fans with more behind-the-scenes access. “That’s why Dale Earnhardt Jr. was so popular ” Gordon said. “Besides knowing his name  people felt like  ‘I can relate to this guy. I want to go have a beer with this guy.’ And then  ‘I want him to be my friend.’ And the only way you can do that is for somebody to show that personal side.” It’s that personable factor that elevates a talented young driver to a young star. NASCAR needs someone – or a few someones – to make that jump. Of course  that raises another question. SHARE COPY LINK NASCAR driver Bubba Wallace was asked by a reporter following the Daytona 500 on Sunday  Feb. 18  2018 if he is always so emotional. Wallace responded understandably that when you have family and run a good race it tugs at your heartstrings. Walla Jeff Sinerjsiner@charlotteobserver.com Which matters more? Winning  or personality? Both matter  but ... “Winning trumps all ” Harvick said. “Danica (Patrick) is the best example of that. The marketing and the mystique behind that marketing tool only lasts for so long. “You can get a couple of years out of that  but before long  the sponsors want to see their car on TV. They want to see some improvement  see some progression.” Patrick didn’t produce that – finishing in the top 10 just seven times in 191 Cup races – and left NASCAR after February’s Daytona 500. Still  Danica Patrick overcame the biggest worry for team owners. Despite often struggling on the track  Patrick did manage to bring new fans to NASCAR as the sport’s only female driver . Where do those new fans come from now? “Our biggest challenge is getting fans ” Petty said. “As we go through generations of people  there’s so much more competition out there for the entertainment dollar. “How do we get new fans?” Bill Elliott  former NASCAR Cup Series champion and the father of current NASCAR driver Chase Elliott  addresses the audience after receiving his Hall of Fame ring during his 2015 induction ceremony. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com There’s no easy answer for any sport  but ... In the struggle for fans  NASCAR’s problem is unique. NASCAR’s existing fan base is among the oldest of any American sports league  and the most rapidly aging bunch  too. A 2017 report from the Sports Business Journal found that NASCAR’s average TV viewer was 58 years old  third-oldest among measured sports behind golf and tennis. But the age of NASCAR’s average fan has also gone up by nine years over the past decade  easily the most of any major sport. Some of that  Hendrick said  is cultural. “You don’t see the love affair with the car in young kids the way you used to ” he said. “They’ve got so many things that can occupy them  Football  basketball  baseball  they’re in video games and social media and all these things. “The closer we can get to them that way  and these young (drivers) coming up  that’s what we need to energize this young crowd.” Of course  other sports face the same hurdles as NASCAR. They’re all competing against one another for the same market of untapped (young) fans. The trick is differentiating themselves. How can NASCAR differentiate itself? Part of being different comes from a more entertaining product. Part of it comes from relatable  younger drivers. But part of it also comes from what’s happening off the track – in fantasy sports. More than 20 percent of Americans play fantasy sports  primarily fantasy football and basketball. According to the Fantasy Sports Trade Association   fantasy sports participants report both watching more live sports and reading more about the sports they are engaged in. If NASCAR could refine – and improve – its fantasy presence and dip into that market  it would go a long way toward building the sport’s next generation of fans. “Right now (fantasy leagues) have not been able to adapt to stage points and racing throughout the events into how you do your driver alliance  and I’d like to see that ” Gordon said. “We know how much that digital side of things plays out for the younger fans.” Even Earnhardt  speaking before the Daytona 500  was asked about his fantasy NASCAR lineup. “I always enjoyed fantasy ” Earnhardt said then  “so I think (growing fantasy NASCAR) is a good match.” Kevin Harvick said he doesn’t think of NASCAR races as races anymore  but rather as events. Fan shows and concerts  such as Rascal Flatts’ performance at the Daytona 500  should be just as much of a draw for fans  Harvick said. Phelan M. Ebenhack AP Is it time to stop calling them races? Fantasy sports alone won’t draw a new generation of fans  of course. But everything else that happens at NASCAR tracks – the concerts  the fan fests  the meet-and-greets with drivers – could distinguish NASCAR races from many other sporting events. “I personally don’t believe that races should be called races ” Harvick said. “I believe that these are events.” And that  Harvick said  makes attendance about more than the racing. “When you go to an event – whether it be a football game  a basketball game  a soccer game – they’re not always close ” Harvick said. “They’re not always a good game.” But that doesn’t mean they weren’t worth attending  even if it was just for the tailgating. “When you go to a race personally  the race should almost be an added bonus to everything that’s happening and the events there are to do at the racetrack ” Harvick said. “Every race is not going to be good. That’s just the nature of sports.” The move from game to event is part of a shifting sports entertainment landscape  Bruns said. “No sport can really go along with just the on-court or on-track action ” he said. “It is hard to compete for those entertainment dollars  so the more you can do to add to the value of it  the better. And that’s what people are coming to expect.” “I personally don’t believe that races should be called races ” driver Kevin Harvick  2014 Cup Series champion  said. “I believe that these are events.” Ralph Freso AP Is viewership more problematic than attendance? The television viewing numbers for the 2018 Daytona 500 were the lowest in the history of The Great American Race. That  objectively  is not good. It’s even worse when you consider how dependent NASCAR is on television revenue. “If you continue going down in the ratings  it’s going to be a really  really tough deal ” Wheeler said. “If you could hold on even to what you have now in this environment  it might be all right  but right now TV is carrying racing  carrying these major public companies as far as their revenue is concerned. “Revenue coming from the grandstands isn’t there like it once was  and that revenue includes tickets  concessions. … When you lose a customer  you’ve lost at least 10 dollars profit in concessions. You’ve lost a souvenir  which aren’t what they were. “So how do you get all those back? You get it back by having an exciting sport where more viewers will want to come forward.” NASCAR’s current television contracts with FOX and NBC both expire after the 2024 season. Jointly  those contracts account for roughly $820 million per year in revenue  an increase from the previous deal NASCAR had with FOX  Turner Sports and ESPN. But with Nielsen viewership numbers falling (something that is also happening in other sports)  it could be tough for NASCAR to get a similar television deal when the current contracts expire. “TV is extremely important ” Gordon said. “The good news is  live sporting events are very important to the TV broadcasters  and NASCAR has a very loyal following and puts up very consistent numbers.” Richard Petty  seven-time NASCAR Cup Series champion and team owner of Richard Petty Motorsports JEFF SINER Shrinking TV numbers don’t tell the whole story. While traditional television numbers for NASCAR might be on the decline  that’s a somewhat deceptive measurement – largely because of NASCAR’s surging streaming  digital and app-based viewership numbers. An example  The Daytona 500 drew 9.3 million television viewers  but FOX announced that the race had 18.1 million viewers across all platforms. Streaming viewership saw a 28 percent increase from 2017 (primarily in the 18-34 demographic)  which is indicative of how younger fans watch races. “I don’t know about you  but I don’t know many people that have a Nielsen box in their house ” Gordon said. “I don’t know if that’s really the fairest assessment of how many people are actually viewing the races. “I truly believe there’s more eyes on the sport now than there’s ever been. But every time you have TV viewership and Nielsen ratings that come out on a Monday or Tuesday  it’s always being measured up against our past.” Essentially  TV isn’t all that matters anymore. NASCAR is looking to that streaming future as it adjusts to the changing media landscape. “What we look at is fan engagement  whether that be television  attending a race  digital  social  fantasy  esports or radio ” Phelps said. “We arguably have the highest fan engagement in our history due to many dynamic platforms. “The world has shifted from analog to digital  and our fans are consuming our sport 365 days across multiple platforms  wherever and whenever they want.” Jeff Gordon  now a broadcaster  celebrates after winning the NASCAR Brickyard 400 auto race at Indianapolis Motor Speedway in 2014. At left is team owner Rick Hendrick. At right are Gordon s wife  Ingrid Vandebosch  and their children  Ella Sofia and Leo Benjamin. R Brent Smith AP File Photo Doug Pearlman  the CEO of Sports Media Advisors who helped negotiate NASCAR’s current television deals  said modern media partners and corporations don’t solely focus on television numbers anymore. “A lot of times  people focus on TV ratings too much. That’s only one piece of the puzzle ” Pearlman said. “Most people in the business would talk more in terms of engagement across all platforms. ... For whatever reason  in certain places folks still continue to focus on old-fashioned areas.” So  what does Pearlman expect for the value of the next contract? Is NASCAR destined for a drop there  too? “It’s hard to predict that far out  but I can definitely see things continue to rise going forward ” Pearlman said. “These major sports are going to continue to do well. The business model may look a little different. The metrics may look a little different. But any sport with the kind of audience NASCAR has – that size  that passion – I think will do very well.” There is a downside to streaming. All these new digital options focus on ways to watch races  not attend them. “There’s too much technology to bring it into your living room ” Bill Elliott said  “and then there’s not as many people who are showing up to the speedways.” Striking the balance between increased viewership without cutting attendance is difficult  but one thing remains clear  Television (and the revenue it accounts for) remains dominant. “Television is and will remain to be a huge piece of the puzzle for years to come ” Phelps said. “Our job over the next decade is to ensure that our sport is positioned for growth across all platforms.” But there is one thing that might need to shrink. Is the NASCAR season too long? There are 36 points races each season  plus special events on two other weekends  in Daytona and Charlotte. That stretches the season from the Daytona 500 in the middle of February until the championship at Homestead in the middle of November – or about 10 months. It wears on everyone involved. “The biggest challenge is just the pace ” Hendrick said. “The number of races  getting to and from  it’s a long season. And that is what it is. “I don’t know that that won’t change in the years to come  races maybe sometimes in the middle of the week.” Alex Bowman  right  is driving the No. 88 Chevrolet for team owner Rick Hendrick  left  after Dale Earnhardt Jr.’s retirement. John Raoux AP That has been discussed  including at this year’s preseason media day in Charlotte. “You take NASCAR  and it definitely has a very strong place in the (TV) lineup ” Gordon said. “But at the same time  the second half of our season cuts into the NFL season and we know how strong the NFL is. ... In Daytona (in 2018)  we’re up against the Winter Olympics. That’s only every four years  but those are definitely challenges.” Petty had the same worry. “There’s so much competition ” he said. “Baseball  football  there’s the X Games and all this kind of stuff. ... Nobody’s really figured it out.” Should (and could) NASCAR make major schedule adjustments? What Hendrick and others proposed is trying to double up on races in certain weeks. For example  when the Major League Baseball All-Star break comes each summer  run two or three races in one week to capitalize on the lack of competition. But tracks are independently operated  meaning NASCAR alone can’t dictate its desired schedule. Plus  jamming two races into a week deprives a track of a week’s worth of festivities. Likewise  it takes away a week’s worth of occupied hotel rooms and tourist revenue near the tracks. The same issue makes it difficult to cut a race altogether. So if that’s not possible  is there another way to shake up the schedule? To combat NASCAR’s pace problems  the panel suggested alternating the schedule  including moving the Cup Series All-Star race away from Charlotte Motor Speedway. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Could some of the premier events move? The season always starts with the Daytona 500. It always ends with the championship at Homestead. And in between  things are mostly the same year to year. They shouldn’t be  if you ask Harvick. “Mix up the schedule every year ” Harvick said. “I’m a firm believer in the fact that the championship race should rotate. The playoff races should never look the same year to year.” Harvick even proposed the idea of rotating NASCAR’s All-Star race  held annually at Charlotte Motor Speedway  along with the championship race. “Everybody’s going to beat me up in Charlotte over the All-Star race  but imagine if you were in the mix to hold the championship race?” Harvick  who lives in Charlotte  said. “Imagine what that would be like here. You give up the All-Star race  but you’re going to get the finale in Charlotte one of these years. “To me  that’s a big deal.” Of course  economic and contractual issues make schedule changes difficult. But NASCAR has taken steps in this direction already  adjusting the first round of the 2018 playoffs to include Las Vegas and the new Charlotte ‘Roval’ course. Further changes are possible. So what was the purpose of all this  anyway? NASCAR is in a state of flux  as many of the top American sports leagues are. Its fan base is changing  it’s business model is changing and the rules on the track are changing. All of that warrants a broader look at the sport and where it is headed. “I feel like it’s a lot happening  a lot of change ” Hendrick said  “but it’s a lot of good that’s happening.” </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/c17aa6ce7e8c721003d39891a9b9da07.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/2r1qdx/picture207551849/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/fans(2)</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article207551864.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
