<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article205479029.html</field>
<field name="title">Charlotte Ballet does contemporary family ballet   Most Incredible Thing  to music of Pet Shop Boys</field>
<field name="name">Charlotte Ballet does contemporary family ballet   Most Incredible Thing  to music of Pet Shop Boys</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-16T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 16  2018 10 27 AM Before the Knight Theater curtain rises on “The Most Incredible Thing ” we face a backdrop of drab simplicity  Three dark  quasi-rectangular panels  roughly forming an arch and edged in a lighter hue. It’s the last simple thing we’ll see. Though Charlotte Ballet’s production cancelled its first two performances because of mechanical difficulties  this whirligig of a show now works like … well  clockwork. The adaptation of Hans Christian Andersen’s brief fairy tale delivers an hour of extraordinary variety  visual panache and theatrical coups. If the shorter second act seems bland  that’s because the first-act finale – the creation of a timepiece whose hours are linked to Nature and myths – leaves the brain reeling. Josh Hall  surrounded by Three Muses. Jeff Cravotta Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW London-based choreographer Javier de Frutos pays witty tribute to inspiring predecessors while coming up with amusing pas de deux for the two leads  first rhapsodic and then giddy. The Pet Shop Boys’ electronic/symphonic score sets the heart racing but slows down for romance or pathos. The performers must not only dance but act  I have never seen Josh Hall  who plays clock-builder Leo  inhabit a character so completely  from bliss to impotent rage. A king (James Kopecky  who doesn’t get much to do) offers his daughter’s hand and half his kingdom to the person who designs the most incredible thing. Leo’s clock impresses the judges in a parody of “Britain’s Got Talent ” but vicious Karl (steadily malevolent Anson Zwingelberg) destroys it – which  in turn  forces the judges to admit the destruction of art and beauty is even more incredible than its creation. In Andersen’s story  the clock pieces regroup to kill the villain; here  more tamely  scissors-wielding Fates cut the thread of Karl’s life  and Leo gets the Princess (Chelsea Dumas  the picture of innocence ruined and then redeemed). Katrina Lindsay’s wildly inventive set drops us first into a factory that could come from a German expressionist film  Workers move through dull tasks (a la “Metropolis”)  while black-clad Karl (made up to look like the murderous sleepwalker from “The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari”) stands in an unsettlingly crooked doorway. The Soviet-style poster in his office  where Karl relaxes by punching henchmen in the gut  tells us not to get attached to one time period or locale. That’s a good idea  because de Frutos swings through a century of dance. Three Muses  hitting poses from George Balanchine’s “Apollo ” inspire Leo to build the clock. When that marvel strikes the hour of seven  the Seven Deadly Sins appear – leaning over a dance barre like the hookers in “Sweet Charity ” corralled by a Bob Fosse figure with derby  cigarette and white gloves. Anton Zwingelberg in rehearsal  with choreographer Javier de Frutos (also a current artist-in-residence at McColl Center) in middle chair. MIKE BELLEME NYT/MIKE BELLEME Charlotte Ballet artistic director Hope Muir has praised de Frutos by saying he can take a few moves and turn them into a full piece by varying them at length. That’s true of his “Elsa Canasta ” which the company did in its Fall Works concert  and true in “Incredible Thing” when he’s not spoofing or paying homage. He doesn’t let ideas linger overlong  except for a repetitive factory sequence in Act 2. (It’s inserted  perhaps  to prevent the act from appearing dwarfish next to its giant predecessor.) Tal Rosner’s films and animation contribute to the tsunami of images  and a series of shadow plays (shot with the help of Pilobolus) really do make the talent contest incredible; at one point  the profile of a purse-lipped woman breaks down into six dancers. Rosner’s images reach their apex when projected above dancers embodying the clock hours  A pregnant woman illustrates “nine ” while an ultrasound of a baby hovers over her. I couldn’t figure out what every hour meant  How did three people dressed in masks and dark bodysuits represent “eight”? But then came Moses to deliver the Ten Commandments to disciples who fell backward and  seen from an overhead camera  formed Busby Berkeley-style floral patterns with their bodies. Whatever that’s about  Charlotte needs more of it. ‘The Most Incredible Thing’ </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/d1ac22c0ffecc786b9a46ea16cfbf9fc.com/entertainment/arts-culture/fp3lsl/picture205479014/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Charlotte%20Ballet_%201718%20The%20Most%20Incredible%20Thing_%20Javier%20De%20Frutos%20and%20The%20P</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article205479029.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
