<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article207248499.html</field>
<field name="title">NASCAR  What’s wrong with Hendrick Motorsports race teams?</field>
<field name="name">NASCAR  What’s wrong with Hendrick Motorsports race teams?</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 29  2018 09 05 AM The accolades speak for themselves. Those 16 NASCAR championships  including 12 in the Cup Series. Hundreds of wins. All the notable names – Dale Earnhardt Jr.   Jeff Gordon  Jimmie Johnson – and all their notable accomplishments. It’s what made Hendrick Motorsports  at least for much of the past two decades  arguably NASCAR’s premier team. So what the heck is wrong with them now? Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW We’re only six races into the 2018 NASCAR season  and already the alarms have been sounded over at Hendrick. The team’s current four drivers – Alex Bowman  Johnson  Chase Elliottand rookie William Byron – have collected only one Top 5 finish altogether (Elliott at Phoenix). They are  respectively  14th  17th  18th and 20th in the NASCAR standings. And Johnson just lost the only sponsor he’s ever known   Lowe’s  beyond this season. None of that is up to the Hendrick standards. Not even close. So what happened? What caused one of NASCAR’s best teams to nosedive like it has? First off  talk like that. Hendrick isn’t nosediving or spiraling or disintegrating anytime soon. It’s still one of the most reputable organizations in NASCAR with some of the best equipment available. And did everyone forget about the seven-time Cup champion on staff? No  the reality is that Hendrick’s problems are temporary. They’re also not entirely on Hendrick. For example  the new Chevy Camaro . Hendrick is one of the teams driving it this season. So too is Chip Ganassi Racing  Richard Childress Racing and a handful of other smaller teams. What do they all have in common? They’ve largely struggled in the early going this season (even though Chevy driver Austin Dillon won the Daytona 500). The only Top 10 Chevy driver in the standings now is Kyle Larson in ninth . But we expected that sort of beginning. Toyota drivers had the same troubles with their new car at the start of last season  and didn’t that turn out just fine ? There’s an adjustment period for all the Chevy drivers right now  including those at Hendrick. Then there’s the turnover factor. Gone are Earnhardt and Kasey Kahne  replaced this time by Bowman and Byron. It’s Byron’s first-ever Cup season and Bowman’s first full season on a decent team. Anyone who expected those two to come out scoring Top 5’s from the get-go was unrealistic. If anything  it’s impressive that they’re both not farther back in the standings. Now  Johnson’s performance drop-off has been somewhat of a cause for concern  but Lowe’s leaving the sport is much more indicative of NASCAR’s overall health than Johnson’s driving capabilities. Those seven rings say a lot  but so too does the fact that even in what he calls his worst pro season in 2017  he had three wins and almost made the championship race. He’s more than earned the benefit of the doubt. Of course if Hendrick’s problems endure  this whole conversation changes. If  by summer the team is still devoid of wins and quality finishes  if the new guys still haven’t assimilated  then we can talk seriously about what’s going wrong at Hendrick. But for now? These first six races are more of a speed bump than a pothole – as it always has been at Hendrick  things will be fine. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/9e86f0e27537974dd953f76483cba8c1.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/hwxv2y/picture207248494/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/hendrick</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article207248499.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
