<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/national/article207645274.html</field>
<field name="title">Condom challenge  5 things to know about viral fad</field>
<field name="name">Condom challenge  5 things to know about viral fad</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 06 20 PM While it sounds like an April Fool’s joke  educators are warning about a “condom challenge” being spread online by YouTube videos and social media. Also known as the “snorting condom challenge” or “condom-snorting challenge ” the fad actually dates back several years but has recently gone viral again  educators say. “Because these days our teens are doing everything for likes  views and subscribers  ” Stephen Enriquez  a state education specialist  told KPMH. “As graphic as it is  we have to show parents because teens are going online looking for challenges and recreating them.” Here’s the lowdown  Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW 1. Wait. Snorting condoms? The challenge involves snorting an unwrapped condom up one nostril  then pulling the condom from the throat out the mouth  reported Newsweek. Participants typically then post a video of the completed challenge to YouTube.   A different “condom challenge” made the rounds back in 2015  involving videos of water-filled condoms being dropped on people’s heads  drenching them  reported The Debrief. 2. Going viral The challenge has gone viral  particularly on YouTube  where thousands of videos of people – mostly teens but also some young adults who host channels on the site – snorting condoms have been posted. 3. It’s not new One of the first condom-snorting challenge videos was posted by YouTube star Savannah Strong in 2013  according to ABC News. That video  and others dating back at least 2007  have been since been removed by YouTube for violating the site’s policy on harmful or dangerous content. Stories on the “bizarre viral trend” appeared on The Huffington Post in 2013 and in The New York Daily News in 2015  among others. 4. Not the best idea Snorting a condom up your nose not only poses a choking hazard but also puts you at risk for allergic reactions and infections  reports Forbes. The publication also cites two cases reviewed in medical journals in which women accidentally swallowed condoms  developing ailments ranging from pneumonia to appendicitis. “Even if you manage to successfully pull the condom out through your mouth  inhaling a condom up your nose would be very uncomfortable and potentially quite painful ” writes Bruce Y. Lee  an associated professor at Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health  in the Forbes report. “Would it really be worth all that just to get more likes and views?” 5. Only the latest fad The condom snorting challenge may eclipse the most recent viral video fad among teenagers  which involved eating brightly colored Tide Pods   reported The Washington Post. Tide and the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission both issued warnings against eating detergent. What should Tide PODs be used for? DOING LAUNDRY. Nothing else. Eating a Tide POD is a BAD IDEA  and we asked our friend @robgronkowski to help explain. pic.twitter.com/0JnFdhnsWZ Some past video challenges  such as the “ice-bucket challenge ” have helped raise money for charity  but others  such as “bath salt challenge” can be dangerous  The Washington Post reported. SHARE COPY LINK Even though it started as a meme in social media  teens all over the country started recreating it by eating Tide Pods as in this new YouTube challenge. Esther MedinaMcClatchy </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/35524c19e2cfc269dfa89b1a72819150.com/news/nation-world/national/rmjfv5/picture207645269/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/condom</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article207645274.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
