<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/national/article207632559.html</field>
<field name="title">Drugs  weapons in bra found on school bus  South Carolina police say</field>
<field name="name">Drugs  weapons in bra found on school bus  South Carolina police say</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">April 01  2018 03 31 PM COLLETON COUNTY  SC An incident that started with a middle school bus driver smelling marijuana resulted in the discovery of drugs worth thousands of dollars of drugs  weapons concealed in a bra and the arrest of three students — including two juveniles  authorities say. The incident occurred around 7 45 a.m. March 29  when the driver of a Colleton County school bus was completing her morning run to the middle school and high school when she noticed the  overwhelming odor of marijuana  on the bus  according to an incident report from the Colleton County Sheriff s Office. The driver notified school administrators  including two school resource officers  who were waiting when the bus arrived at the middle school  and removed the students from the bus while instructing them to leave their belongings on the seats to be searched  according to the incident report. By the time Colleton County sheriff s deputies arrived  three ounces of suspected marijuana was found in baggies and pill bottles in one headphone case  while another ounce was discovered in a jacket lying on the next seat  according to the incident report. When surveillance determined which students possessed these articles  they were separated and it was discovered one of the juveniles had a bulge in his pants. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW The juvenile ultimately removed a large plastic baggie from his pants  which contained 59 grams of suspected marijuana  according to the incident report. In all  sheriff s deputies and school administrators found more than half a pound (9.28 ounces) of suspected marijuana in the search. If the suspected marijuana was broken down and sold as gram bags  it could have a street value of $3 900  according to the sheriff s office. The two juveniles were taken to the Colleton County Sheriff s Office Annex. They were interviewed and released to their parents pending prosecution in a juvenile court of law. But they were not the only students to get in trouble with law enforcement because of the incident. Phoenix Brown Colleton County Sheriff s Office After being removed from the bus  Colleton County High School student Phoenix Tmia-Danielle Brown  18  was ordered to stop talking on her phone after interfering with the investigation  according to the incident report. Brown became uncooperative and refused to comply with authorities  they said  and was taken into custody for disturbing a school. After searching Brown  authorities found a taser (rated in excess of six-million volts) and a can of pepper spray inside Brown s bra  according to the incident report. Brown was charged with disturbing a school and possession of a weapon on school grounds. She was taken to the Colleton County Detention Center  where her bond was set at $1 000 for disturbing a school and $5 000 for carrying a weapon on school property. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/8efa35779c8b6f71ab4600d4af4b98e2.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article207632559.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
