<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/national/article207631694.html</field>
<field name="title">Death after fall from speeding SUV prompts lifesaving kidney donation</field>
<field name="name">Death after fall from speeding SUV prompts lifesaving kidney donation</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 03 18 PM The 2005 Buick Rendezvous careened through a Cranberry  Penn.  neighborhood Friday afternoon as Ryan Minett  27  hung off the side  clinging to a luggage rack and screaming for help while his girlfriend repeatedly bounced the SUV off curbs  police told The Pittsburgh Post-Gazette. “Call 911  call the police ” Minett shouted to stunned neighbors as the SUV roared past  police told the newspaper. After a half-mile  Minett lost his grip and fell  his body flying 53 feet until it struck a light post   the publication reported. Minett  who died Saturday  had reportedly been trying to stop his girlfriend  Jessica Ann Royall  28  from driving drunk to pick up her children  police say. Royall now faces charges including drunken driving and felony assault  and will be charged with homicide by vehicle  Cranberry Police Chief Kevin Meyer told The Post-Gazette. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW But Minett’s death – and a generous decision by his father  Eric Minett – means a new life for his childhood best friend  Andrew Dietz  27  of New Brighton  Penn. As he considered whether to take his son off life support Saturday  Eric remembered that Andrew desperately needed a kidney transplant   according to WPXI. Ryan and Andrew grew up together  and Andrew still lives across the street from Eric. Their blood types matched  immediately moving Andrew to the top of the list for one of Ryan’s kidneys. Andrew’s father  Rob Dietz  told KDKA it was “truly amazing  the most difficult decision of your life  and you’re thinking of your neighbor   you’re thinking of a kid who’s in need.” Andrew  who suffers from a rare kidney disease  had been waiting for a transplant for 10 months. He’s recovering after receiving one of Ryan’s kidneys Saturday night. When Rob told Andrew who had donated his new kidney  his son “was pretty devastated ” Rob told WPXI. “When I told him there was silence on the other end of the phone.” Eric told KDKA that he believes Ryan would have wanted things this way  adding that while his son was far from perfect  “he did his greatest thing in death.” Now Eric will see his son “live on through Drew ” Rob told the station. “Every time I see him  I’m going to see part of my son  so … ” Eric told the station. “I’m just … I just couldn’t believe how everything worked out.” Royall told police that she’d had an argument at home with Ryan Minett  then left to pick up her children  according to The Pittsburgh Post-Gazette. He confronted her in the driveway  then grabbed onto her vehicle and refused to let go  she reportedly told police. Witnesses told police they heard tires squealing and officers found evidence that Royall had bounced off at least three curbs as she drove through the neighborhood with Ryan Minett hanging on. After Ryan Minett lost his grip – sliding  tumbling and rolling down the street until he hit the light post – Royall drove off  police told the publication. She returned as neighbors tried to render aid  police told the publication  then left again. Officers arrested Royall at her home a short time later  police said. SHARE </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/15a75455c012302f83f6a9488a372f2c.com/news/nation-world/national/d08n4y/picture207631684/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/kidne_fitted</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article207631694.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
