<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article201311834.html</field>
<field name="title">Billy Graham revival crusade in Charlotte  NC in 1947</field>
<field name="name">Billy Graham revival crusade in Charlotte  NC in 1947</field>
<field name="created">2018-02-21T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">February 21  2018 11 41 AM *Slideshow is below the story* More than 60 000 people experienced Billy Graham’s 1947 Charlotte crusade  and the Charlotte Observer reported that the two-week revival resulted in more than 1200 conversions. Here’s a recap of the event as Charlotte’s favorite son returned home. 9 000 Hear Billy Graham in Closing Revival Services  Great Results Brought About During Series November 24  1947 Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW The Billy Graham revival of two weeks in Charlotte  ending last night at Armory Auditorium with an attendance of 9 000 for two services  and a total of approximately 60 000 for the series  resulted in more than 1 200 conversion and 50 additional Christian workers who dedicated their full time to religious work. The first four meetings were held in the First Baptist Church  starting  November 9  and the remainder  with one Saturday night exception  were held in Armory Auditorium. The afternoon service yesterday totaled 4 000 with hundreds turned away  and with extra seats installed last night  the attendance ran up to 5 000  it was reported by the ushers. There were 18 services  including two children’s rallies  and two services on the two Sundays of the revival. “It was  I believe  the most successful revival ever held in Charlotte ” said Vernon Patterson  chairman of the revival committee. “We had virtually 100 percent co-operation from the ministers of Charlotte  and nearly 50 churches gave us their full assistance. Billy Graham preached one of the most profound and dynamic series of sermons I have ever heard. We in Charlotte are proud of him  because he is Charlotte’s own son.” Concerning the revival  Billy Graham said  “Cliff Barrows and I prayed that in my home town we should have a successful and soul-stirring revival. I have been thrilled with the way God has blessed our meetings. I have been happy indeed with the hospitality showered upon me and my associates. We asked God to give us a great time. He has answered our prayers. What happened in Britain during our meetings there -- a great awakening of the spirit of Christ -- has happened here.” GOES TO GREENVILLE Billy Graham came to Charlotte from a successful revival in Portland  Ore. He will leave early today for Bob Jones university in Greenville  S.C.  where he will speak today and tomorrow. On Wednesday  November 26  he will talk to the ministers of all the churches at Augusta  Ga. Thursday  November 27  he will go to St. Petersburg  Fla.  to address a mass meeting  and on Friday  November 28  he will speak at the First Baptist church in Miami  Fla. On Saturday  November 29  he will address a mass meeting in West Palm Beach  Fla. His itinerary from December 1 until Christmas will comprise a series of meetings in Alabama  Mississippi  Louisiana  and Texas. His next big revival is scheduled to begin in Augusta  Ga.  February 8  1948. Later in the Spring he will go to Toronto  Canada  and thence to Amsterdam  Holland  and then back to the United States. Cliff Barrows  of Los Angeles  Calif.  his song leader  will accompany him after he leaves Charlotte. The Charlotte revival was outstanding for the number of notables that participated in the meetings  mainly music stars. First came Beverly Shea  of radio fame; next Adora Norlander  of Minneapolis  noted woman gospel singer; then Gene Jordan  the famous marimbist; and Warren Zorn  brilliant young Chicago pianist. Billie Barrows  who is Mrs. Cliff Barrows  had spots on the program. Gil Dodds  holder of the world’s indoor mile record  participated last Friday  running a footrace in the auditorium. Dr. Harry D. Clarke who was with Billy Sunday the last eight years of that evangelist’s life  participated in one of the meetings. Robert G. LeTourneau  millionaire evangelist and industrialist  was in Charlotte to attend the dinner when plans for the Billy Graham revival were completed. Prayer meetings were held daily at Second Presbyterian church  and Mr. Patterson’s committee met daily at Thacker’s. The campaign was heralded through the press  radio  and various forms of outdoor advertising  as well as being announced from the pulpit of Charlotte’s churches. The Charlotte Hymn Singers  of 100 voices  participated as well as a massed Salvation Army band. Musical groups from Bob Jones university were on several programs. Rev. Grady Wilson  born in Charlotte  and himself an eminent evangelist  conducted all outside meetings  and assisted Cliff Barrows in arranging each day’s program. Scores of Charlotte ministers participated daily in the services in one capacity or another. T.W. Aldred organized a group of ushers who were at all services  and J. Clyde White assisted in the musical programs. The Boy Scouts also served as ushers during the crowded days near the close of the revival. + + + </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/9a667c4258fc2650526487ce8d788e31.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/dwh6ra/picture201311829/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/bg%20start%20nov%209%20ad</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article201311834.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
