<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206827544.html</field>
<field name="title">NASCAR results for Martinsville won by Clint Bowyer</field>
<field name="name">NASCAR results for Martinsville won by Clint Bowyer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-26T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 26  2018 07 37 PM Martinsville  Va. Clint Bowyer won the STP 500 on Monday  his first win in 190 races  but there are other implications from the race as well. Here are the three biggest takeaways from Monday’s race  1. We have our first (sort of) surprising playoff driver this season. Not that Bowyer is a bad driver by any means – he has finished in the top 10 in half of this season’s races so far – but he was far from a lock to win a race this season. The guy hasn’t won since 2012  you know? But now Bowyer has another victory under his belt and he’s into the 2018 playoffs. Bowyer’s victory could prove to be a sign of more to come in 2018  or it could turn out to be a fluke. Either way  his slot in the playoffs is all but guaranteed. Last year  Austin Dillon won the Coca-Cola 600 to sneak into the playoffs. Are there more drivers waiting to steal victories? We’ll see  but for the time being  Bowyer’s inclusion in the playoffs has to come as a bit of a surprise. 2. One team has risen above the rest. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW So much for the titans at Hendrick Motorsports or Joe Gibbs Racing (or really  most of the top teams in NASCAR’s Cup Series). So far this season  Stewart-Haas Racing has proven far and away the best team in racing’s best division. Kevin Harvick has three victories  and now Bowyer has one  too. Add in that Aric Almirola was a half lap away from winning the Daytona 500  and it was feasible for SHR to take home five of the first six trophies. Those three and Kurt Busch are all in the top 11 of the standings  and it doesn’t seem like Stewart-Haas will drop off anytime soon. If anything  SHR is only getting started on what could be a runaway year. 3. The manufacturers are starting to fall more in line with expectations. Before the year began  the general consensus was that the Toyotas would continue their dominance  the new Chevy would take time to break in  and the Fords would ... well  the Fords were the wild card. And after a crazy first few weeks  the manufacturers standings are finally starting to fall in line with everyone’s expectations. Two Toyotas are atop the charts in Kyle Busch and Martin Truex Jr.  followed by three Fords and then another Toyota. The best Chevy is Kyle Larson in ninth. Now  will those standings hold up all season? Probably not. But for now  it’s somewhat reassuring that things are working out as anticipated. NASCAR Monster Energy STP 500 Monday at Martinsville Speedway </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/fbac18c14e6889822c8e1c05b9d78237.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/8czyvr/picture206921549/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/NASCAR%20Martinsville%20Auto%20Racing</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206827544.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
