<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article206823339.html</field>
<field name="title">Sensoria is CPCC’s 10-day festival of literature and the arts in Charlotte.</field>
<field name="name">Sensoria is CPCC’s 10-day festival of literature and the arts in Charlotte.</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-27T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 27  2018 12 56 PM Sensoria — which began as a literary festival in 1993 — now sports almost 90 events that celebrate the written word  visual art  opera  dance  theater  food and wine at Central Piedmont Community College. (And last year’s featured speaker provided a killer quote for this year’s guide  The April 6-15 festival is “one of the very best of its kind in the world ” according to George Saunders  of long-term short-story fame and recent “Lincoln in the Bardo” success.) Woven throughout is a unique educational component; indeed  many offerings spring directly from classroom curricula. Sensoria brings art alive through discussions and demonstrations between the audience and the artists  who range from national luminaries to local treasures. “Our students deserve the absolute best ” says Amy Bagwell  co-chair of literary events. “We want to get as many students as we can into galleries and auditoriums to experience something connected to the curriculum  and we want our community to experience those same things.” Many of the productions are collaborations with other art institutions across the county. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Hours after Tracy K. Smith was named U.S. Poet Laureate  the brain trust behind Sensoria sought and landed her presence as the Irene Blair Honeycutt Distinguished Lecturer. Smith  who will read from her work and lead the audience in discussion (general admission and free)  won the 2012 Pulitzer Prize for her collection “Life on Mars.” (Watch her read a poem called “Wade in the Water ” which she dedicated to the Geechee Gullah Ring Shouters   here .) In addition to elaborate stage productions  here’s a random sample of distinctive offerings   The New Annotated Frankenstein   by Mary Shelley  with notes by Leslie Klinger. Attend a special effects make-up workshop by red-carpet make-up artist Kymm McLean. Hear goldsmith Charles Lewton-Brain discuss the new system of metal working he invented called Fold-Forming. Celebrate the 200th anniversary of Mary Shelley’s “Frankenstein ” with Dr. Leslie Klinger  editor of the “New Annotated Frankenstein.” Local literature is represented by novelist and UNC Charlotte professor Bryn Chancellor  who will read from her novel “Sycamore.” Virginian Jon Pineda  the featured regional writer  has published three poetry collections  two novels  and a memoir. Children book illustrator Matt Myers  whose most recent book is “BB-8 on the Run ” will read at the Harris campus. Large stage productions include seven performances of the heart-tugger “On Golden Pond ” by CPCC Theatre. “L’elisir d’amore” is the Italian title of Gaetano Donizetti’s comedic opera  “The Elixir of Love ” a premiere for CPCC’s Opera Theatre. First performed in Milan in 1832  the opera is lauded for its humor and character development  and as an excellent representation of the bel canto tradition. It will be sung in English with “supertitles.” Among the most ambitious performances is Benjamin Britten’s haunting “War Requiem ” originally commissioned for the reconsecration of England’s Coventry Cathedral  which was bombed by the Luftwaffe on Nov. 14  1940. The chorale and orchestral work integrates World War I poems written by English soldier Wilfred Owen with texts from the traditional Latin Requiem  or Mass for the Dead. More than 150 performers are featured in this collaboration between CPCC Music and the College of Arts and Architecture at UNC Charlotte. Felicia van Bork s  How to Stand Up.  Courtesy of Jerald Melberg Gallery Visual artist Felicia van Bork will lecture about her collage and painting exhibition  color + color = space   and show a time-lapse video of a mural she created with students at the CPCC Levine campus. Exhibiting artist Jeremy Pelt will hand out wax markers for attendees to draw on the walls of the Gorelick Gallery. In celebration of delicious things to eat and drink  Piedmont Culinary Guild is partnering with CPCC Culinary Arts to offer a Food   Wine Festival  where 11 local chefs will create locally sourced dishes and pair each with a wine from North Carolina. The four-hour event includes the option to attend any of six hour-long classes (Chocolate and Wine  anyone?). Proceeds will go toward culinary scholarships. “What is exciting to me about all the arts is they are alive and relevant ” says Bagwell. “They are a mechanism to sustain us and to show us through things. “Tracy Smith is so accomplished  and she wants to talk about how we are in this divided place  and about how does language help us with that ” says Bagwell. And “Frankenstein ” written centuries ago  is thematically applicable here and now as we debate the ethics of cloning and genetic testing. “There are tools in these pieces of literature   says Bagwell   that we can use to help us live today.” The full schedule is available at sensoria.cpcc.edu/events/ . </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/2f07d407d2f26f890c80e840e6acfe1f.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article206823339.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
