<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/health-family/article207555374.html</field>
<field name="title">Moms Gear  Comfy  massaging bed rest hits the spot | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Moms Gear  Comfy  massaging bed rest hits the spot | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 30  2018 04 00 AM The Nap Shiatsu Massaging Bed Rest  from Brookstone  could become a high-demand item in any household. This foldable bed rest provides back support for anyone working on a laptop or reading a book from their bed or even a spot on the floor. Not only is it soft and cushy all over  but it also provides a deep  rolling massage to the lower back when powered on. Be aware that this massage is not light. Two dual-heads run for 20 minutes  massaging the lower back at a fairly intense depth. Fortunately  a cloth flap with a pillow folds over the center of the rest  putting some cushioning between the massaging nodes and the lower back. Also  the power button can be pushed at any time to reverse the direction of the massaging nodes. The entire bed rest is made of the same fabric as the cloth flap – a type of nap material that is extremely soft. A cup holder on the left armrest provides room for a drink  although the cup holder is not deep enough to do any cup justice. Pockets run along the exterior side of both armrests  providing room to stash a book  a notepad or a remote. To use the backrest  simply unfold the center piece of the rest to an upright position. Plug the adaptor into the right arm  hit the power button  and sit back and relax. When it s time to put the rest away  just fold the center part down between the two arms and tuck the entire rest away. In fact  the bed rest condenses to eight inches in height. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/health-family/article207555374.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
