<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/world/article207616564.html</field>
<field name="title">Idaho man creates scholarships for poor students in Peru</field>
<field name="name">Idaho man creates scholarships for poor students in Peru</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">April 01  2018 10 26 AM GARDEN CITY  IDAHO When he talks about his life and where he’s come from  Kent Johnson begins with a startling comparison to Adolf Hitler. And then the apostle Paul  who was legendary in his persecution of Christians  before his conversion. And then  he refers to himself. “I was like both of those guys ” he says. “I hated Latinos as much as Paul hated Christians and Hitler hated Jews.” The seeds of his racism and hatred were sown growing up in the 1960s during the Los Angeles Watts riots. When he moved to Caldwell at 18 years old  he was victim to thefts and burglaries. “Those seeds got watered and fertilized even more ” he says. “I just assumed all Latinos were carjackers  thieves and bums. That’s the way racism is  and it’s not very selective.” Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW He had a lot of experiences with “them ” and he developed a sincere hatred for “that group of people.” “I always thought Spanish was a language given to them as a system of sounds for people not capable of learning a real language. …That’s what I thought  but ignorance is that way.” And then  he laughs. “It’s like the good Lord has a sense of humor. “Just as Paul had a conversion experience  so did I. (The good book) says  ‘I will take that heart of stone out of you and I will replace it with one of flesh.’” He pauses. “I had that transplant.” Kent Johnson’s house is a showroom of fine carpets. “If you’re going to have a habit  it might as well be a good one ” he laughs. His passion for rugs — his habit — has become a means to an end  Each rug he sells goes directly to fund college scholarships for young adults in Lima  Peru. Katherine Jones kjones@idahostatesman.com Now  his best friends don’t even speak English; and he is  in fact  fluent in Spanish. Johnson spends half of his year living in the slums of Lima  Peru  mentoring young adults. The other half of the year  he runs a business in Garden City called Rarity Rugs — where all the proceeds fund scholarships for about 30 young Peruvians to learn a trade and get started in a career of their choice. “I wouldn’t trade the last 10 years for the previous 60 ” he says. “Because there’s an intensity and purpose now that I didn’t have before.” Big ... and empty For most of his life  Johnson was a workaholic. He started  built and sold a number of profitable businesses  from lumber to construction to granite. Success came with his work  and in the late 1980s  he built an enormous showcase home in Meridian and thought he had it made. “Ten thousand feet of ‘it’s as good as it gets ’ ” he says. “And there I am  sitting in my rosewood paneled library thinking  wow. I have got everything. “But I felt so empty.” He was commissioned to build a bed and breakfast in New Zealand  where he struck up a friendship with a Maori couple. They lived  simply and humbly  in a one-room  dirt-floor house that was half the size of his dining room. At the time  New Zealand was thinking about beginning a national lottery  so Johnson asked them what they’d do if they won $100 million. They weren’t sure. They listed their assets  They had each other  God  their health  family that loved them  an iron roof that didn’t leak  a refrigerator that always had enough in it. “She said  ‘So if you can tell us what we are lacking  that’s what I’d buy with the lottery money  but I think we already have everything.’ And that was a defining moment for me. “Because I realized  Here I am  living in one of the great houses on the planet and they’re living in one of the poorer houses on the planet – and they were richer than me. “That never went away.” That was a different kind of seed planted in Johnson’s life. He didn’t realize it at the time  because first  his life fell apart. He and his wife divorced; he had to sell his mansion because he couldn’t afford the taxes. There are other things he won’t speak of  but he calls them “the fuse on a big bomb that went off.” “The American dream  which for me became the American nightmare. … I don’t want to dream that dream anymore.” In the midst of that turmoil  he reluctantly went with a church group to build a medical clinic in Mexico. “I didn’t really want to – racism doesn’t go away overnight; hate doesn’t go away instantly ” he says. But in Mexico  he met a kindred spirit. A kindred spirit who was Mexican. “I couldn’t speak a word to him  but he was a magician with his hands in terms of working concrete and construction  which was also my background ” says Johnson. “So we hit it off really well. … I had a real affinity for that guy and a few other people I met. … “By the time I (left)  a lot of that huge brick wall that I had spent my lifetime building was starting to come down.” That was the first trip to Mexico. And then there was a second and a third – he’s lost count. Then he built an orphanage in Guatemala. Along the way  he started writing pen pals in Lima that he’d met online to practice his Spanish; back to Boise  he started an immersion Spanish school. The diagnosis And then there was the hospital he built in Cuenca  Ecuador. That’s where he was diagnosed with cancer in 2009. He could tell by the look on the doctor’s face that the news wasn’t good  Late-stage colon cancer. “All of a sudden everything that mattered to me didn’t matter  and all the stuff that did matter – now mattered ” Johnson says. “It caused me to start living life with an immense intensity  because it felt like I had spent a lot of my life chasing dollars  chasing work. And I realized  none of it mattered. “Was I going to leave a pile of money? Was I going to leave properties? “Or was I going to leave a legacy?” Suddenly  everything fell into place. Looking for the best return on his investment took on a whole different meaning. “To invest in a kid’s life and put him in school  and see him graduate and become a freshly minted architect  or a world-level chef …” says Johnson. “That far exceeds acquiring another house or another $100 000 in the 401(k).” He started his scholarship fund by accident  when he was visiting a pastor in one of the “slumdog millionaire kind of neighborhoods of Lima.” A young man fell in love with the pastor’s daughter  but didn’t have the means to finish his education. There was another seed planted. “He was studying architecture and now he is one ” says Johnson  not without pride. It’s a scholarship  not a loan  he reiterates. He chose to work in Lima  because there  poverty is life-threatening; and there  $1 500 will buy a full year of college education. “Giving (money) away is a blast ” he says. “And when you see some kid throw his hat in the air because now he’s a medical doctor or he’s a new lawyer or an architect – that doesn’t have a price. “That’s something that can’t be taken away  either from him or me. … That graduation ceremony is more than payment enough.” Now he’s not only given scholarships to about 30 young adults  but he spends a couple of hours a day on Skype  mentoring them. “It’s cheaper to learn from somebody else’s mistakes ” he says  “than to repeat them yourself.” When he’s in Lima  he does that in person. “I could tell you their life stories ” he says. “I watched them grow up. They’re family.” Looking ahead Johnson has always loved and sold Oriental rugs  and now they are a means to an end. The sign in his living room showroom says  “When you find a beautiful handmade treasure here to add to your home  you are also making it possible for someone across the world to achieve a dream.” “I am full to overflowing ” says Johnson  who is 68 years old. “If the good Lord takes me tonight  I’ve had more life than the next 10 people ever had  because of the intensity. That can’t be taken away.” There’s a question that he asks himself every day  and it drives him  Is the world a better place today because I walked on it? “And not because you earned money or whatever. But did you generally make it a better place? By helping the old lady across the street? By dropping a couple of cans in the Rescue Mission barrel? … Some days it will be a big thing and some days  it will be a small thing. You have your balance. So how is your balance doing?” Good works look different for each person. “Mother Teresa was about orphan kids; some people are about single moms. What you do doesn’t really matter; it’s why you do it – and the fact that you do it. What gets you up every day? “Is it chasing the money? Is it fulfilling job obligations? Or is it for filling something way bigger than you – and just being content to be part of something that’s bigger than you? … “I can’t scholarship every kid; I mean  it’s impossible ” says Johnson. “So you get to a point where (you say)  can I change your life? Is there something I can invest in your life to make yours better? “One at a time. Change one life at a time. So that’s what I do. … “I try to live every day that way.” Want to buy a rug to support the scholarship program? Call 208-631-9184 or email elbotino@yahoo.com to set up an appointment  or visit the website RarityRugs.com </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/2e1f0b77408cbae3dc6b812edb8e83a9.mp4</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/world/article207616564.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
