<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/home-garden/article207250404.html</field>
<field name="title">On Gardening  Solar azaleas create a heavenly storm in your landscape | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">On Gardening  Solar azaleas create a heavenly storm in your landscape | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 29  2018 04 00 AM Solar storms have been in the news the past couple of weeks in an almost   the sky is falling   scenario but it can be happening in your landscape  too  thanks to new Solar Flare and Solar Glow azaleas! As spring arrives in the south first  I can tell you landscapes are lighting up with what many consider one of the best of the best azalea bloom seasons ever. This dazzling show is thanks in part to the Rhododendron austrinum or Florida flame azaleas and their hybrids like Solar Flare and Solar Glow. If you haven t heard of Solar Flare and Solar Glow yet it s OK; they are another incredible creation of Buddy Lee in Independence Louisiana  a horticultural hero who also brought us the Encore series of repeat blooming azaleas. You ll find them both in the Southern Living Plant Collection and Sunset Western Garden Collection. Solar Flare and Solar Glow azaleas will mature at about 6 to 8 feet in height and 4 to 5 feet wide. They are cold hardy from zones 5 to 9 (-20) meaning much of the country can revel in their spring blooming beauty. Revel I did  with those planted outside my office when I was with the Coastal Georgia Botanical Gardens in Savannah. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW There is a sense of panic at my new house in Hamilton  Ga.  and probably a lot of other places too as homeowners see azaleas blooming at the neighbors and realize we all need them  too. I m talking I want Solar Azaleas  Encores  natives and other groups. Azaleas must have very well drained  organic-rich  acidic soil. When we get heavy rain  we want the water to drain freely. This is such a critical issue that many experts even suggest planting them high so to speak where the top one inch of the rootball is above the soil profile  and add loose  organic material around it. Azaleas are very shallow rooted plants. Considering that you are also planting high  in loose soil  you realize that azaleas are prone to drying out  especially those newly planted. Supplemental water will be needed. Mulch  which conserves moisture is an absolute. You ll love the shocking colors of both the Solar Flare and Solar Glow azaleas and relish the fact that they also have a honeysuckle fragrance and bring in butterflies and the first returning hummingbirds. You have to admit that is pretty hard to beat. You might be wondering will orange whether a Solar azalea or Florida flame clash with the other colors in the spring garden and all I can say is no. No sight is more stunning than the orange azaleas combined with dogwoods  Louisiana or woodland phlox and purple azaleas like Autumn Royalty. Do this  and you will have created the Kodak moment. No shrub can give your landscape the WOW factor like azaleas and now is the time to prepare the beds and get several planted. And  by spreading our selections around from deciduous natives and their hybrids like the Solar series to evergreen repeat blooming Encores we can have a layered look in the garden ensuring our spring bloom extends all the way to fall. (Norman Winter  horticulturist  garden speaker and author of   Tough-as-Nails Flowers for the South  and  Captivating Combinations  Color and Style in the Garden.  Follow him on Facebook @NormanWinterTheGardenGuy.) </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/home-garden/article207250404.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
