<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/national/article207622049.html</field>
<field name="title">Stephon Clark protester hit by Sacramento County sheriff s vehicle during march</field>
<field name="name">Stephon Clark protester hit by Sacramento County sheriff s vehicle during march</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 12 16 PM A protester at a vigil Saturday night for Stephon Clark was hit by a Sacramento County Sheriff s Department vehicle on Florin Road  the latest tense moment between law enforcement and activists following the March 18 police shooting death of the unarmed black man. Witnesses and the struck protester said the sheriff s vehicle left the scene. The collision  captured on video by Guy Danilowitz of the National Lawyers Guild  occurred as protesters marched on Florin Road in south Sacramento. The activist struck was Wanda Cleveland  a regular at Sacramento City Council meetings. She lay immobile on her side in the street until a fire department crew arrived to pick her up. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Cleveland was released from Kaiser Permanente South Sacramento Medical Center after midnight  with bruises on her arm and the back of her head.  He never even stopped. It was a hit and run. If I did that I’d be charged   Cleveland said at the hospital.  It s disregard for human life.  Watch  The Bee reporter Nashelly Chavez covered the protest on Facebook Live In a press release early Sunday morning  sheriff s spokesman Sgt. Shaun Hampton confirmed the accident had occurred. The release said two sheriff s department vehicles were surrounded at about 8 40 p.m. by protesters who were yelling and kicking the vehicles.  Vandals in the crowd  caused  scratches  dents  and a shattered rear window  to a sheriff s vehicle  the release said. The release did not address why the vehicle that struck Cleveland did not stop  and Hampton did not immediately respond to a request for further details. Dominique Poydras  who was attending the vigil  said a group of protesters had surrounded a Sheriff s Department vehicle and a few were throwing eggs at it. Based on footage captured by Channel 10   a sheriff s vehicle pulled up  lights flashing  as protesters marched in the street. About three dozen people then surrounded the vehicle and kept chanting. The sheriff s deputy four times sounded his siren and said   Back away from my vehicle.  He slowly pulled forward and left the scene. A second sheriff s vehicle followed and struck Cleveland  sending her to the curb  the Channel 10 video shows. Cleveland said that when the first vehicle said to clear out  she started to walk toward the curb because her arthritis was making her knees weak. The second vehicle driver made no request  she said  and abruptly accelerated and hit her in the knee  sending her into the air.  I heard wheels spin. And then I saw her body flung to the curb   Tifanei Ressl-Moyer  another legal observer who witnessed the incident  said.  The vehicle sped off and some protesters went after them.  The sheriff s department release said the patrol vehicle was traveling at  slow speeds  when the collision occurred. Chris Vestal  a spokesman for the Sacramento Metropolitan Fire District  confirmed that the department responded to a collision between a vehicle and a pedestrian near 65th and Florin and transported the pedestrian to the hospital. He did not elaborate. Legal observer Cres Velluchi recorded the number of the patrol car that hit Cleveland as 1476894 and reported it to the California Highway Patrol. Velluchi said the Highway Patrol declined to take the information. The sheriff s department is conducting an internal investigation and the California Highway Patrol is also investigating  according to the sheriff s department press release. About 100 protesters  mostly young people in their 20s  remained after the collision and shut down traffic in all directions at the intersection of 65th and Florin Road. A small group approached the nearby Sacramento County Sheriff s Department station  but stopped across a parking lot from the building. A row of officers lined up outside the station. The protesters began chanting  hit and run.  A helicopter overhead ordered them to disperse or be arrested  and they returned to the larger protest. SHARE COPY LINK A vigil-turned-march for Stephon Clark continued late Saturday evening  with CHP and Sacramento Sheriff s deputies forming a line to prevent the crowd from advancing. Renee C. Byer Jamier Sale of the ANSWER Coalition  who organized the vigil  called off the protesters at around 10 40 p.m. and many went home. Then about three dozen California Highway Patrol and sheriff s department officers formed a riot line and pushed approximately 50 remaining protesters back to a parking lot.  We were trying to leave and the police once again were provoking people into confrontation   Sale said. About 40 minutes later  the organizers had protesters turn away from the riot line and walk into the parking lot. Most police retreated to their cars and left the area. About two dozen protesters remained  walking in the street and blocking traffic  until shortly after midnight. At 7 p.m.  approximately 150 people had gathered at the corner of 65th Expressway and Florin Road for a vigil honoring Clark and other victims of police shootings. Attendees held candles as they chanted at the intersection. Two held up a large white sign reading   It s a phone  not a gun!  Cars zooming by honked in support. Clark  22  was shot the night of March 18 after being chased into his grandmother s backyard by two officers responding to reports of a man breaking car windows. Deputies in the helicopter reported seeing a man in a backyard pick up an object and break a window  though the helicopter video did not capture that moment. Police said the officers thought Clark had a gun. After the shooting  they determined he was holding a cellphone . Sale said the vigil was meant to hold the Sacramento County Sheriff’s Department accountable for its part in Clark s shooting  unlike previous protests that focused on the Sacramento Police Department. Police say a sheriff’s department helicopter came to help local officers responding to reports of broken car windows nearby.  The dominant narrative has really focused on the two officers who pulled the trigger   Sale said.  We have to realize they didn t just find themselves there. They were directed to this position by this other officer in a helicopter.  Sale questioned why authorities used a helicopter to respond to what he described as a  petty crime   and he called for the firing of the deputy or deputies in the helicopter that responded to the 911 call leading to Clark’s shooting. While city leaders have faced calls for reforms within the police force following the shooting  he added  the Sacramento County Board of Supervisors has not received equal calls for accountability within the sheriff’s department. Hampton said earlier Saturday he would not respond to the vigil because the Clark case was being reviewed by the Sacramento Police Department. The vigil followed nearly a week of protests — largely nonviolent  though at times confrontational — in downtown Sacramento. Up to 300 protesters marched Friday night until nearly 1 a.m.  after Clark s family released a private autopsy showing that he was shot eight times  including six times in the back  by Sacramento police. Sale said the vigil was intended to create a space for residents of south Sacramento. Most of the protests and rallies held following the shooting have played out in the central city. Sacramento Mayor Darrell Steinberg issued a statement Friday calling for peaceful action   From the bottom of my heart  I urge our entire community to continue to work together through nonviolent civil action as we pursue justice and demand reform.  Alexander Clark  who is not related to Stephon Clark  said he came to Sacramento from Minneapolis to participate in the protests. He lost a cousin to a police shooting in 2015.  I felt like it was important to be here. I feel like his life mattered   Alexander Clark said of Stephon.  The revolution is coming. We need to spread awareness.  The protesters did not return downtown Saturday evening  as fans attended Golden 1 Center for a Kings game against the Golden State Warriors. Protesters caused an arena lockdown at two recent games  preventing thousands of fans from entering. But the team and police instituted higher security measures starting Thursday that enabled fans to enter without disruption  and they continued Saturday with the presence of an estimated 170 police officers in riot gear. Roger Resek  a Kings fan from West Sacramento  said he felt  confident and comfortable  attending Saturday’s game after learning the added security features put in place during Thursday night’s game would also be in place that night. Resek arrived at the game several hours earlier than usual as an added precaution  however  he said. He was one of the thousands of fans who were turned away during the team’s March 22 game against the Atlanta Hawks. That night  he arrived to Golden 1 Center just before tipoff  as he usually does  only to see fans headed the opposite direction.  It was inconvenient for the patrons  but I understand the concept   he said of the protests. SHARE COPY LINK Sacramento police shot and killed 22-year-old Stephon Clark Sunday night  March 18  2018. Clark was unarmed and holding only a cell phone. David Caraccio Earlier Saturday  several hundred gathered for a rally across from City Hall  where Sacramento native and former Kings player Matt Barnes announced a college scholarship fund for Clark s two sons. Barnes said it is the beginning of an effort to address the violent death of young black men that he would like to expand across the country.  This is a nationwide problem   he said.  Once we get it up we are to going carry it nationwide  to provide kids who have lost their father to unfortunate stuff like this a chance to still come up and be productive men.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/623c4c56b487010f0bfa3f5bdb6fa081.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article207622049.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
