<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/home-garden/article207403879.html</field>
<field name="title">Keep an eye out for ruby-throated hummingbirds this weekend | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Keep an eye out for ruby-throated hummingbirds this weekend | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Brown-headed cowbirds  like this female  will generally move on in a few days. John Ennis Brown-headed cowbirds  like this female  will generally move on in a few days. John Ennis Keep an eye out for ruby-throated hummingbirds this weekend By Taylor Piephoff Order Reprint of this Story March 29  2018 11 38 PM Start looking for the returning ruby-throated hummingbirds this weekend. If you haven’t seen one yet  you have an excellent chance Sunday or Monday. Traditionally April 1 and 2 have been the dates I start to receive multiple reports. I would not be surprised if some of you have already seen a bird. A few early individuals are already here. They will be males. Male birds in migration generally move in advance of the females  their mission being to stake out territory sites to impress the females upon their arrival. Best males get the best territories and become the best choices for breeding partners. Don’t be disappointed if the first birds don’t hang around. Most of them are headed further north. You may even see birds every day for a week or so then see a big drop-off in activity. If you are lucky enough to have a feeder up in an established territory  you may see action through the spring and early summer. It is very possible  however  that you won’t see birds until they turn around and start heading back south in late July through August and September. More spring migrants are arriving and passing through right now  too. Louisiana waterthrushes have arrived in some breeding areas already. Their loud  ringing songs can be heard along creek bottoms throughout the county. It seems this species shows up earlier each year. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Blue-gray gnatcatchers will be very conspicuous in the next few days. Their constant wheezy whines will give them away. They will get down to nesting business right away; completed nests are often found before the foliage fully busts out. White-eyed vireos will follow  their harsh songs coming from thick brush. Northern parulas will be with them  giving their buzzy  rising trill from the treetops. It’s a great time of year for birders. Something new will be arriving daily for the next five weeks. Speaking of new  some of you may have been seeing plain  sooty gray birds invading your feeding stations. There may be some shiny black individuals with brown heads with them. They are brown-headed cowbird males and females. They will generally move on in a few days  but some may hang out longer. I have been getting reports and seeing online requests for identification of this species as they move through residential areas. Taylor Piephoff is a naturalist with an interest in the birds and wildlife of the southern Piedmont  PiephoffT@aol.com . </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/03d51f920ab284325a7927de2f0d2bff.com/living/home-garden/xhhrvm/picture207403859/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Brown-headed_Cowbird_4955</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/home-garden/article207403879.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
