<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article152690609.html</field>
<field name="title">Gallery  NASCAR at Charlotte Motor Speedway 05.25.17 | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Gallery  NASCAR at Charlotte Motor Speedway 05.25.17 | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2017-05-25T17:23:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Email NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr.  left  has been NASCAR s Most Popular Driver 14 times in a row  on Thursday  May 25  2017 he stopped preparing to climb into his car to pose with a fan in the garage of Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. prepares to climb into his car for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. adjusts his ear buds as he prepares to climb into his car for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. adjusts his ear buds as he prepares to climb into his car for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. prepares to climb into his car for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. tightens the straps of his helmet as he prepares to climb into his car for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. stops to sign autographs for fans prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR crew chief Chad Knaus  left and driver Jimmie Johnson  right  talk atop the team s transporter prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR crew chief Chad Knaus  left and driver Jimmie Johnson  right  talk atop the team s transporter prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR crew chief Chad Knaus  left and driver Jimmie Johnson  right  talk atop the team s transporter prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Joey Logano relaxes in the garage prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Clint Bowyer  center  talks with crew members in the garage prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Jamie McMurray sits in his car preparing for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Chase Elliott  right  talks with a crewman  left  while preparing for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Chase Elliott relaxes in the garage prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Brad Keselowski  left  checks out an i-phone with a crewman  right  while preparing for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Brad Keselowski walks along his car while preparing for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Martin Truex Jr.  right  talks with a crewman  left  while preparing for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Paul Menard watches his team work on the car while preparing for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch  center  stops to sign autographs for fans while walking to the garage for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch prepares for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch tightens the straps of his helmet for practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kevin Harvick stops to speak with a passerby prior to practice at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr.  right  sits in the media workroom at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC following practice on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr.  right  sits in the media workroom at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC following practice on Thursday  May 25  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. answers a reporter s question during a media session at Charlotte Motor Speedway on Thursday  May 25  2017 in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR drivers Clint Bowyer  left and Kevin Harvick  right  joke around on pit road prior to qualifying for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Harvick won the pole for the race to be run on Sunday  May 28  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR drivers Clint Bowyer  left and Kevin Harvick  right  joke around on pit road prior to qualifying for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Harvick won the pole for the race to be run on Sunday  May 28  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kevin Harvick wins the pole for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. runs qualifying laps for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kevin Harvick won the pole for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kevin Harvick won the pole for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Martin Truex Jr. waits to qualify for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr.  center  enjoys time with his team along pit road while waiting to qualify for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr.  right  enjoys time with his team along pit road while waiting to qualify for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. waves to someone along pit road while waiting to qualify for the Coca-Cola 600 on Thursday  May 25  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com 1 of 36 </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/c38e9e9bc9db56ca01e67b876b0d07ed.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/90k2tj/picture152690469/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/NASCAR_CMS_01</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article152690609.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
