<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/article207285679.html</field>
<field name="title">Movie review   Isle of Dogs   a mechanical phenomenon | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Movie review   Isle of Dogs   a mechanical phenomenon | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 29  2018 04 00 AM Wes Anderson has returned to cinema with his highly anticipated film   Isle of Dogs.  Following the story of a young boy in the age of the Japanese Archipelago  the film tells the story of a future in which the dog flu has plagued canines and deemed them unable to be house pets. All of  man s best friends  are sent to Trash Island in exile to preserve human beings on the orders of the corrupt Mayor Kobayashi (played by Kunichi Nomura). Atari Kobayashi  a 12-year-old boy  sets out on an odyssey with a stolen plane to find his missing dog  Spots. He crash lands on the forbidden island and enlists the help of five alpha canine companions  Chief (Bryan Cranston)  Rex (Edward Norton)  King (Bob Balaban)  Boss (Bill Murray) and Duke (Jeff Goldblum). Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. Wes Anderson s attention to detail and remarkable visual effects make  Isle of Dogs  an undeniable mechanical phenomenon. Anderson s aesthetic approach is carefully crafted to make each scene almost perfect  symmetrical and compelling. The director s ability to design fictional worlds and combine them with fantastical scenarios and misfit characters is unparalleled and highlights the intrigue surrounding this film. The characters in  Isle of Dogs  have identifying qualities that make them distinctive  adding to the offbeat and contrasting tone of the stop-motion picture. The film s Japanese setting also adds to its commendable efforts at exploring cinematic territories yet to be discovered. It s usage of Japanese language in a manner that is native to the story  rather than disregarding it  marks a commendable storytelling method. From the futuristic cities  immoral leadership  talkative tail-waggers and approach to human mistakes   Isle of Dogs  creates a plot that is both unpredictable and sensational  paying a beautiful homage to Asian culture. The music of  Isle of Dogs  also manages to send audiences to a whole other world  capturing a distinctive Japanese style with the heavy drums  ominous flutes and vintage trumpets  composed by Oscar-winning composer Alexander Desplat. Each theme channels the film s emotions thoroughly. The score  along with the glorious optical sights and quirky dialogue  create a film both unexpected and astonishing. ABOUT THE WRITER Nicholas Brito  Teenlink correspondent  Archbishop McCarthy High Teenlink is an online and quarterly print newspaper produced by and for South Florida high school students. The students work with professional journalists from the Sun Sentinel  South Florida Parenting and Forum Publishing. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/article207285679.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
