<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article164217452.html</field>
<field name="title">Lake Norman s Outrigger Harbor and summer sermons in 1971</field>
<field name="name">Lake Norman s Outrigger Harbor and summer sermons in 1971</field>
<field name="created">2017-07-31T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story July 31  2017 07 10 AM A Duke Divinity School student brought the gospel to Lake Norman from 1969 to 1971. Two sermons on summer Sundays  one at Ye Olde Campground (off Hwy 73 West?) and the other aboard the “Polynesian war canoe” at Outrigger Harbor . Outrigger Harbor leased the property from Crescent Resources until the mid-’90s when Crescent decided not to renew their lease. Today  the Peninsula Yacht Club and expensive homes sit on land once filled with trailers and tents. Read on to learn more about the Moravian preacher who gave nondenominational sermons to Lake Norman visitors 46 years ago. + + + + + + + Student Goes to Parishes to Preach By Sam R. Covington  Observer Staff Writer Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW July 26  1971 The young preacher was picking up trash in the “church” when his congregation began straggling in  carrying their “pews” with them. The preacher  Keith Hutcherson  a Duke Divinity School student on summer intern work  has one church in a Lake Norman campsite pavilion  another on a pontoon boat at a marina. His parishioners are campers  and at the first service Sunday  at Ye Olde Campground  nearly all the campers came to church carrying folding aluminum-framed chairs for there are no permanent seats in the open-sided shelter. The chairs’ plastic webbing made a colorful array matched by the casual vacation clothing of the church-goers. Nearby  the waters of Lake Norman  gray and sullen under overcast skies  lapped fitfully at the beach. A powerboat  tiny in the distance  growled its way toward deep water. Hutcherson’s second service was at Outrigger Harbor  another campsite and marina a few miles away. He followed the same order of worship at both  preached the same sermon. The locale differs in that the Outrigger church is held aboard the camp’s long  low cruise boat  a party craft decorated in pseudo-Polynesian. The services attracted between 80 and 100 persons at the campground  where Hutcherson said people tend to return each weekend  and about 50 persons at the Outrigger where faces change more often. The July Fourth weekend seemed to have been the peak so far this summer  Hutcherson said  with about 225 persons at both services. The services are short  about 30 minutes  and it may be that Hutcherson’s pretty young wife  Sheila  worked harder than the preacher. At the campground  Mrs. Hutcherson played for the hymn-singing on a weather-beaten upright piano. On the boat  she used a portable pump-organ  pedaling to make the music come. In his sermon  Hutcherson told the vacationers that rest from the grind of a competitive world is necessary for all men. “One of the favorite resting places of Jesus was a lake  much like the one you see before you ” Hutcherson said. It is easier to develop faith in God when surrounded by nature  the young student said  urging his listeners to use their leisure time to think deeply on eternal matters. Worship itself is recreation when looked at as “re-creation ” the renewing of our spirits  attitudes and innermost selves. The “re-created” believer needs to carry back to the work-a-day world the message that God loves all men  he continued. Hutcherson  26 and a native of Winston-Salem  is an interesting example of the lakeside ministry’s ecumenical approach. The services he conducts are a project of United Methodists  but Hutcherson is a Moravian. One summer  he has learned  the student-minister was a Baptist. His sermon was carefully free of denominational position  nothing that the “faith of all believers has equal standing.” A former sportswriter for the Winston-Salem Journal  Hutcherson began to examine his career choice while serving in the Army in Vietnam. Being drafter was  as he described it  the first time he was pulled out of a middle-class environment and began to realize “the world was in lots worse shape than I realized.” It was seeing “guys who just didn’t know where in life they were going ” that caused him to consider the ministry  Hutcherson said. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/de1a0cc5155abd57e5bda8f1e82c130f.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/jr26ua/picture164217432/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/preach%2071A</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article164217452.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
