<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/article207633354.html</field>
<field name="title">JJ Redick  Ex-Duke Blue Devil lifts NBA s Philadelphia 76ers</field>
<field name="name">JJ Redick  Ex-Duke Blue Devil lifts NBA s Philadelphia 76ers</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T18:25:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story If you just look at J.J. Redick — the eye test alone  not knowing anything else about him —  longtime NBA veteran  likely isn t the first thing that comes to mind. After all  Redick is just 6-foot-4  190 pounds (and even that s generous). He s a thin  fairly average-looking guy. Even when he starred at Duke  he was never the fastest or strongest or biggest player on the court. And yet  he s an NBA survivor. Really he s much more than that. Now in his 12th professional season  Redick has developed into one of the NBA s savvier players. Given their youth and inexperience  the Philadelphia 76ers drastically needed some of that NBA know-how. Signing the 33-year-old Redick to a one-year deal worth $23 million in the offseason gave it to them. Now that move is paying dividends. Take for example Sunday s game between the 76ers and the Charlotte Hornets. The 76ers built up a 20-point lead to begin the fourth quarter (most of which Redick didn t play) and easily cruised to a 119-102 victory. Redick finished with 20  just above his career-best mark this year of 16.6 points per game.  Incredibly well   Hornets coach Steve Clifford said when asked how Redick fits in Philly.  Just like he fit in incredibly well with the Clippers. He has such a basketball IQ and plays at such an energy level.  Those may sound like cliches for a veteran  but in Redick s case  they re true. Without size or strength  it was going to take something for him to stick in the NBA for over a decade. Of course  Redick s shooting is one thing — he s making 40.9 percent of his 3s this year  41.4 percent for his career and sank 5 of 8 Sunday — but it had to be more than that  too. And so  Redick learned how to move.  He s in constant motion. He can back-cut  he can front-cut  he s just perpetually moving   Philadelphia coach Brett Brown said.  I think he gets fouled all the time. I think people bear-hug him all the time.  That was on display Sunday  as well  as Redick constantly drove to the baseline only to then pass the ball away ... and then move some more to get open for his own shot. That s something of a lost art in the league  and Redick is one of the best there is at it. Underappreciated as it might be  it s something Redick s game has been founded on — and a technique his young teammates  such as Ben Simmons and Joel Embiid  can learn from. And it s not just on offense that Redick has carved out a role.  What people don’t realize is he’s very good defensively   Clifford  who coached Redick when he played in Orlando  said.  His team defense is great. Watch him. He doesn’t get blown by. He’s a very solid individual defender.  Charlotte Hornets flat at home as playoff-bound Philadelphia 76ers complete sweep After this NBA season ends  Redick very well may don another team s colors  selling his skills for the maximum value . In an era where max contracts reign supreme and longevity is key  Redick has shown this season that yes  there is still another way to do things. As the 76ers have grown  as their young players have blossomed and turned into leaders themselves  Redick s influence has been less paramount. He is not by any means the future of this team. But as for whether his signing was worth it?  They knew what they were doing (signing him)   Clifford said.  I remember talking to Brett about him. He’s the ideal guy. You have a young team. He’s a pro s pro.  Watch him talking to the younger guys during the game — they are learning every second he’s out there.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/954f0a3536ea0ed7deaaa1b261b0cead.JPG</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/article207633354.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
