<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/article207645319.html</field>
<field name="title">The Latest  Miss. St.  Notre Dame tied after 3 quarters | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">The Latest  Miss. St.  Notre Dame tied after 3 quarters | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">April 01  2018 07 51 PM COLUMBUS  Ohio The Latest on the NCAA women s national championship (all times local)  ___ 7 40 p.m. Notre Dame has erased a 13-point halftime deficit to tie the score with Mississippi State after three quarters in the women s NCAA championship game. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. After trailing 30-17 at halftime  the Irish finished the quarter with a 17-1 run and knotted the game at 41. The Irish stepped up their play after a dreadful first half. All five Bulldogs starters have picked up at least three fouls. Mississippi State reached the final for the second straight year and is trying to win the first national championship in school history. Notre Dame advanced to its sixth title game and fifth in the last eight years. The Irish lost the previous four. They won their lone championship in 2001. ___ 7 p.m. Mississippi State has stretched its lead over turnover-prone Notre Dame in the women s national championship game. The Bulldogs rallied with from a first-quarter deficit to lead 30-17 at halftime in Columbus  thanks in part to a dozen Irish turnovers. Notre Dame scored just three points in the second quarter  an NCAA championship game low for a single quarter. Victoria Vivians has 14 points for Mississippi State  and Teaira McCowan has nine points and eight rebounds. Mississippi State reached the final for the second straight year and is trying to win the first national championship in school history. Notre Dame advanced to its sixth title game and fifth in the last eight years. The Irish lost the previous four. They won their lone championship in 2001. ___ 6 40 p.m. Mississippi State has rallied to take 17-14 lead over Notre Dame at the end of the first quarter in the women s national championship game. The Irish reeled off an 8-2 run to start in front of an energized full house at Nationwide Arena in Columbus. Mississippi State stormed back  finishing with an 11-2 run of its own to erase the Notre Dame lead. Teaira McCowan has seven points for Mississippi State  and Victoria Vivians has six. Mississippi State reached the final for the second straight year and is trying to win the first national championship in school history. Notre Dame advanced to its sixth title game and fifth in the last eight years. The Irish lost the previous four. They won their lone championship in 2001. ___ 6 16 p.m. The women s national championship game has tipped off. Mississippi State reached the final for the second straight year and is trying to win the first national championship in school history. Notre Dame advanced to its sixth title game and fifth in the last eight years. The Irish lost the previous four. They won their lone championship in 2001. Both teams won their national semifinal games in exciting fashion on Friday night. Mississippi State beat Louisville in overtime but first needed a tying 3-pointer with seven seconds left in regulation to force the extra period. Notre Dame needed a jumper from Arike Ogunbowale with 1 second left to overcome UConn in OT on Friday. The Irish are playing with just seven scholarship players because of injuries. ___ 5 26 p.m. Mississippi State and Notre Dame have arrived in style  walking the red carpet into the arena a few hours before the women s basketball NCAA championship game. The Bulldogs are looking for their first national championship in school history  while the Irish are trying to win their second — 17 years to the day after Muffet McGraw s team won the program s only title. Both teams advanced to Sunday s title game with thrilling overtime victories in the Final Four. The Irish will need to find a way to slow down Mississippi State center Teaira McCowan  who set a national semifinals record with 25 rebounds. The game has been sold out for a month  and dozens of scalpers were outside looking for tickets hours before tipoff. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/40330d53828114dd120540a9c9364946.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/article207645319.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
