<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/article207622759.html</field>
<field name="title">Charlotte Hornets</field>
<field name="name">Charlotte Hornets</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 12 46 PM Center Cody Zeller’s season is over  as the Charlotte Hornets scrambled for bodies Sunday in a home game against the Philadelphia 76ers. Zeller had missed the previous 11 games with soreness and swelling in his left knee. He told the Observer last week he’d been advised he’d need several weeks of rest for optimum healing  but didn’t dismiss the possibility of playing in one or more of the final handful of games this season. Sunday morning  Clifford said it seems pointless to try to have Zeller play with five games left and the team eliminated from playoff contention. “I would say we’re at the stage now where it almost becomes  ‘Why?’” ask him to play  Clifford said. “It’s so hard to not play for long stretches off the season. Why  with five games left  would we even play him? It makes more sense to me to let him get back to 100 percent and then just start again next (season).” Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Zeller  the fourth overall pick in the 2013 draft out of Indiana  will play in 33 of a possible 82 games this season. He missed the first four games of the season with a right knee bruise  then 27 with the surgery for a meniscus tear in his left knee. He’d been warned by the surgeon who did that procedure he might have additional swelling the rest of the season. The Hornets had a number of injuries following Sunday’s road loss to the Washington Wizards  particularly at small forward. Treveon Graham is now in the NBA’s concussion protocol  which could potentially end his season. Rookie Dwayne Bacon suffered a right ankle sprain in that same game  and sat out Sunday. Jeremy Lamb missed the Wizards game with a sore left foot  but will play versus the Sixers. The Sixers are also depleted  as they jockey for playoff seeding. Center Joel Embiid is out following surgery to repair and orbital bone fracture  a collision that also caused a concussion. Also  forward Dario Saric is sitting out Sunday’s game with a right elbow injury. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/81ce86b31be42d9c5a612737a9612ccb.com/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/nn4vdr/picture207622754/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Zeller</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/article207622759.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
