<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/article207461524.html</field>
<field name="title">NC failed theme park  Land of Oz  is reopening for 6 days</field>
<field name="name">NC failed theme park  Land of Oz  is reopening for 6 days</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 30  2018 04 25 PM North Carolina’s most infamous failed theme park  Land of Oz  is going to reopen for a six days in June. In a surprise move  the park s website says it is offering one-hour guided tours every Friday that month  as well as Saturday  June 30. The tours are a variation of live action role playing  with guests invited to play key characters from the  Wizard of Oz   says the park.  With Dorothy as your guide  you will skip down the yellow brick road through the magical Land of Oz   the park s website states.  You or other members in your group are randomly selected to play the characters of the Scarecrow  Tin Man  Lion  Witch and Glinda. This is a completely immersive interactive experience.  Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Land of Oz  located on private property in Beech Mountain  is internationally famous in part because of curiosity generated by an Internet fad called “urbex” for urban exploration. Adventurers seek out spooky  deserted places and post eerie pictures of their expeditions on sites specializing in what is called “ruin porn.” The fad has been troublesome for the Land of Oz  because more than a few visitors have stolen bricks from its signature Yellow Brick Road. (The third-of-a-mile road is paved with 44 000 bricks.) One thing the park wants to make clear  It is not abandoned. It s just  sort of  in a hibernation state that has lasted more than 35 years. The park officially opened in 1970  with the intention of becoming a re-incarnation of the Land of Oz featured in the classic film  The Wizard of Oz.  On opening day  actress Debbie Reynolds cut the opening-day ribbon as daughter Carrie Fisher ( Star Wars ) stood by her side. The Park would literally become an overnight success  with 400 000 visitors in its first season. That success was short lived  however. A combination of factors  including a national gas shortage  cut into attendance and reduced profits at a rapid pace in the mid  70s. In December 1975  a fire was set to the Emerald City  destroying the amphitheater and its contents  as well as damaging the surrounding shops and restaurant. The park closed in 1980s  and has been open only sporadically in the years since. Tickets for the June tours go on sale April 20. Details are at www.landofoznc.com/journeywithdorothy. Mark Price  704-358-5245  @markprice_obs </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/5488e4e5525e307761dbfc37b3286d61.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/article207461524.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
