<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/opinion/op-ed/article207447684.html</field>
<field name="title">Trump s VA nominee needs to be closely examined</field>
<field name="name">Trump s VA nominee needs to be closely examined</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">April 01  2018 12 23 PM From an editorial Friday in the Washington Post  Ousted Veterans Affairs Secretary David Shulkin blasted a  toxic  chaotic  disrespectful and subversive  Washington environment for costing him his job. No doubt there is some truth to his critique of Washington s political climate  but if Dr. Shulkin wants to place blame for his downfall he need look no further than the mirror. His arrogant misuse of taxpayers  money undermined efforts to reform the agency and gave ammunition to those who sought his removal. He is far from a victim. That designation unfortunately goes to veterans who look to his troubled department for vital services  and in many cases have been underserved. The dysfunction makes it all the more important to determine if the person named by President Donald Trump to lead the agency  White House physician Ronny Jackson  is up to the job. Shulkin s dismissal  announced Wednesday  was the latest in an administrative shake-up that has included changes for the secretary of state  the national security adviser and CIA director. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW The challenges that will face Jackson  if he is confirmed  are significant and have long vexed both Democratic and Republican administrations. Jackson  a career Navy officer who came into the public spotlight with his disarming discussion of Trump s annual physical  has no real experience managing a large bureaucracy. That has rightly prompted concerns about his ability to lead the federal government s second-largest department  with some 377 000 employees and more than 1 200 health-care facilities. Hard questions about whether Jackson s résumé qualifies him to do this job need to be asked at Senate confirmation hearings. There also should be scrutiny of his plans for the agency  specifically his views on the controversial issue of the privatization of VA services. If it is to make good on its members  frequent promises to the men and women who have served the country  the Senate must take seriously its responsibility to advise and consent on the next VA secretary. It should not rubber-stamp an appointee who makes the president feel comfortable. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/opinion/op-ed/article207447684.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
