<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/national-business/article207648564.html</field>
<field name="title">FirstEnergy unit that runs power plants files for bankruptcy | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">FirstEnergy unit that runs power plants files for bankruptcy | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">FirstEnergy unit that runs power plants files for bankruptcy By JOHN SEEWER Associated Press April 01  2018 07 51 PM AKRON  Ohio A subsidiary that runs FirstEnergy Corp. s nuclear and coal-fired power plants has filed for bankruptcy after the utility said earlier that it planned to close its three nuclear plants in Ohio and Pennsylvania. The move announced by FirstEnergy Solutions late Saturday signals the parent company s plan to get out of the power producing business and concentrate on supplying electricity. The subsidiary  which has been saddled by mounting debt  said in a statement that it s seeking bankruptcy protection to  facilitate an orderly financial restructuring  and believes the filing is in the best interests of the company and creditors. The filing for bankruptcy protection includes FirstEnergy Solutions  along with all FES subsidiaries and FirstEnergy Nuclear Operating Co.  according to the statement. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW FirstEnergy Corp.  parent of FirstEnergy Solutions and the FirstEnergy Nuclear Operating Co.  is not part of the filing. Donald R. Schneider  president of FirstEnergy Solutions  said the Boards of Directors for FirstEnergy Solutions and FirstEnergy Nuclear Operating Co. determined that the Chapter 11 filing represents  our best path forward as we continue to pursue opportunities for restructuring  asset sales and legislative and regulatory relief.  FirstEnergy Solutions and its subsidiaries collectively have more than $550 million in cash  which they believe is  sufficient to continue normal operations and meet post-petition obligations to employees  suppliers and customers as they come due   according to the statement. The company s aging and costly fleet of coal and nuclear plants has been unable to compete in recent years with the growing number of natural gas power plants in the East and Midwest. FirstEnergy first warned that it could be forced to close its power plants in Ohio four years ago when it sought to change how it is paid for electricity. It also has been unable to get financial help from federal and state leaders to keep its nuclear plants operating. The utility said on March 28 that it intended to shut down its three nuclear plants within the next three years. Akron-based FirstEnergy supplies electricity to about 6 million customers in Ohio  Pennsylvania  New Jersey  West Virginia  Maryland and New York. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/national-business/article207648564.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
