<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/national-business/article207617299.html</field>
<field name="title">The Latest  Trump calls on Mexico to stop flow of immigrants | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">The Latest  Trump calls on Mexico to stop flow of immigrants | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">April 01  2018 06 16 PM WEST PALM BEACH  Fla. The Latest on President Donald Trumpx (all times local)  11 25 a.m. President Donald Trump says Mexico has  got to help us at the border.  Trump says a lot of people are coming into the U.S. from Mexico because they want to take advantage of a U.S. program that protects  Dreamer  immigrants from deportation. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Trump ended the Obama-era Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program last year  though a federal judge has ordered the administration to continue renewing permits. Months of negotiations between the White House and lawmakers in both parties have failed to produce a deal to protect the  Dreamers.  Trump tweeted about the issue before he attended Easter services at a church near his Palm Beach  Florida  home. Asked about the tweets  Trump blamed Democrats  saying they blew a  great  great chance  to make a deal. ___ 11 10 a.m. President Donald Trump is attending Easter services at an Episcopal church near his home in Palm Beach  Florida. The president was accompanied by his wife  Melania  and daughter Tiffany. He was expected to return to his Mar-a-Lago estate afterward to join other families for annual Easter festivities  including brunch and an Easter egg hunt. Trump has attended the Church of Bethesda-by-the-Sea for years. It s also where he and the first lady got married in 2005. The president opened the religious holiday by tweeting  HAPPY EASTER!  to his many followers. He complained in a follow-up tweet about  ridiculous liberal (Democrat) laws  that he says make it harder for Border Patrol agents to do their jobs. He also said a deal to help immigrants known as  Dreamers  was  NO MORE.  ___ 10 40 a.m. President Donald Trump says he ll stop Mexico s  cash cow  unless it does more to stop its people from crossing into the U.S. Trump tweets on Easter that Mexico is doing next to  NOTHING  to stop illegal immigration and laughs  at our dumb immigration laws.  The president adds that Mexico must  stop the big drug and people flows  or I will stop their cash cow  NAFTA. NEED WALL!  The U.S.  Canada and Mexico are currently renegotiating the North American Free Trade Agreement at Trump s insistence. Trump says NAFTA hurts the U.S. Trump promised during the presidential campaign to build a southern border wall to stop illegal immigration and drugs coming in from Mexico  but Congress has frustrated the president by not moving as quickly on the wall as he would like. ___ 10 25 a.m. President Donald Trump is claiming that Border Patrol agents can t do their jobs properly because of  ridiculous liberal (Democrat) laws  that allow people caught for being in the country illegally to be released while they await a hearing before a federal immigration judge. Trump tweets on Easter that the situation is  Getting more dangerous  and  Caravans  are coming. He offers no information to back up his claims. Trump also says Republicans in charge of the Senate  must go to Nuclear Option to pass tough laws NOW.  Senate rules require 60 votes for legislation in the 100-member Senate. Republicans only control 51 seats  and GOP Senate leaders basically have rejected Trump s calls to change the longstanding rules. Trump also says  NO MORE DACA DEAL!  to help immigrants known as  Dreamers.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/b648134ab1a16942e9bc3aeb6b6c3bde.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/national-business/article207617299.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
