<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article202469174.html</field>
<field name="title">What to see in galleries  museums in Charlotte for the week of March 4</field>
<field name="name">What to see in galleries  museums in Charlotte for the week of March 4</field>
<field name="created">2018-02-27T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">February 27  2018 06 00 PM Where to go Hear Liliya Zalevskaya talk about her work at the new gallery in Rock Hill  Met Contemporary   noon-1 30 p.m. March 9. We can’t wait to learn more about Liliya’s multi-media work exploring the absurd – something the artist traces back to growing up as the last Soviet generation. Focusing on the duality of social structures  language and believe systems  Liliya’s videos  performances  and two-dimensional works question fact versus fiction  reality versus artificiality. The scene at last year’s Sun Drop Pound Cake Portrait Paint-Off at ClearWater Gallery. Courtesy of ClearWater Gallery Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW What to do Enjoy ClearWater Gallery ’s fourth annual Sun Drop Pound Cake Portrait Paint-Off   3-6 p.m. March 10. Five participating painters (Todd Baxter  Martha Manco  Arthur Rogers  Tucker Fraetis  and HappeningsCLT Carolina Art Crush Felicia van Bork ) will have just two hours to complete a portrait before a live audience. Additionally  you can check out the studios or demonstrations from the Southern Piedmont Woodturners . Who to meet HappeningsCLT Carolina Art Crush Danny Gerwin   assistant professor of art at Queens University  will speak March 7 at Mint Museum Randolph. Hosted by the Delholm Service League  the Mint’s ceramics affiliate  his talk  titled “ New Questions  ” begins at 5 30 p.m. Admission is free. Each week  Grace Cote and Lia Newman offer Observer readers a to-do list on immersing yourself in visual arts around town. Newman is director/curator of the Van Every/Smith Galleries at Davidson College  Cote is senior coordinator at Jerald Melberg Gallery  and they collaborate on the blog HappeningsCLT (happeningsCLT.com). For a seasonlong visual arts calendar  go to  www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article172583126.html . </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e920dc113c3ece22395d960a7b3836d7.com/entertainment/arts-culture/d8giy1/picture202469169/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/image003</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article202469174.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
