<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/college/article207401884.html</field>
<field name="title">NCAA Final Four basketball odds  Best quirky bets  more</field>
<field name="name">NCAA Final Four basketball odds  Best quirky bets  more</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 30  2018 12 18 PM Even for people who don t gamble  a look at betting odds for major sports events still offers insight and entertainment. The Final Four  college basketball s championship weekend  always creates a few quirky bets. Of course  everyone wants to know the favorites and long shots. This helps build that tension that makes sporting events compelling. If you re at a Final Four party or sports bar on game night but don t normally pull for Villanova  Michigan  Loyola-Chicago or Kansas  it s natural to adopt the underdog. Here are a few interesting bets found in a casual cruise on the web. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW 1.  Sister Jean  is habit-forming. If you didn t know already  the Loyola-Chicago chaplain is the runaway breakout star of the tournament . Sister Jean Dolores Schmidt is 98  and probably knows more about basketball than the loudest know-it-all you ll hear far too many times at your local sports bar on Saturday night. betDSI.eu has three prop bets just for Sister Jean for the Loyola - Michigan semifinal. This includes not only how many times you ll hear about or see Sister Jean  but also the bobblehead made in her likeness. That bobblehead — 10 000 were sold within 48 hour of its release  according to an email from Phil Sklar  the co-founder and CEO of the National Bobblehead Hall of Fame and Museum — is wildly popular. That s probably a good indicator of which way to go here. An  over  on any of these seems to be a no-brainer  especially if the game is a dud. Read More This nun is core to the heaven-sent story of the Final Four. The Panthers want in. 2. The NCAA wishes these didn t exist. betDSI.eu also has prop bets for how many times you ll hear the words  “NCAA violations ” “NCAA investigation” and  scandal.  These or  Sister Jean  could make for a great drinking game. Read More </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/c840d78a71e17340bf3811d094160f67.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/college/article207401884.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
