<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/article207251999.html</field>
<field name="title">NC home from Nicholas Sparks   Nights in Rodanthe  for sale</field>
<field name="name">NC home from Nicholas Sparks   Nights in Rodanthe  for sale</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 29  2018 10 15 AM One of the most celebrated houses on the North Carolina coast is up for sale  and it s furnished. The “Nights in Rodanthe” house  used in the Nicholas Sparks  romance starring Richard Gere and Diane Lane  was put on the market this week. Price tag  $1.25 million. Hatteras Realty is marketing it as  the No. 1 icon ocean front house on the Outer Banks.  Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Known as the  Inn at Rodanthe  in the film  the rustic looking six-bedroom home sits on the ocean just off N.C. 12  in the village of Rodanthe. It has been used as a beach rental in recent years.  I’m getting calls from Germany already   Outer Banks realtor Frank Jakob told the Virginian-Pilot . “I expect this house to go for more than I’m asking.  A North Carolina couple who were extreme fans of the movie purchased the home in January 2010. They had it moved a few hundred yards away to another ocean-front lot  because rapid beach erosion caused surf to lap at the underside of the home  according to SunRealtyNC.com. The couple  Ben and Debbie Huss of Newton  decorated four rooms to match the sets in the movie  Richard Gere’s blue bedroom  Diane Lane’s room with willow tree designs on the wallpaper  the kitchen and the sitting room  report media outlets. During production of the 2008 movie  blue shutters and wraparound decks were added to the house  and the couple worked to keep the exterior as close as possible to the film s original vision. Huss was not staying in the home as much as he wanted and decided to sell  Jakob told the Virginian-Pilot. Hatteras Realty listed the home five days ago  and reports it was bringing in $125 000 in seasonal rental income before going on the market. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/daafa562aff938e25d0a1cfd437efe37.</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/article207251999.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
