<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article205666529.html</field>
<field name="title">A timely  resonant production of ‘The Mountaintop’</field>
<field name="name">A timely  resonant production of ‘The Mountaintop’</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-17T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 17  2018 11 21 AM The man in room 306 has holes in his socks. His feet stink. He curses when he can’t find his toothbrush  wipes his hands on his slacks after going to the toilet  bums cigarettes off the maid and flirts with her. He’s 20 hours away from a bullet that will crack his spinal cord and kill him. This is Martin Luther King Jr. He’s in the Lorraine Motel in Memphis on April 3  1968. He’s been to the mountaintop  as he said in a speech that night  but he’s not going see the poor and oppressed of America reach Canaan. The production of “The Mountaintop” at Actor’s Theatre of Charlotte has special resonance for two reasons. First  it mines the pathos and jokiness in Katori Hall’s script. (There’s a lot of unexpected humor.) Second  we’re a few weeks from the 50th anniversary of King’s assassination  so it’s a natural time to reflect – as the play does – on how far we have and haven’t come in the last half-century. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. King (Gerard Hazelton) and Camae (Erica Truesdale) in Actor’s Theatre’s “The Mountaintop.” Carol / Ron Cranford Courtesy of Actor’s Theatre of Charlotte Because we think we know King  who has passed partway into legend among disciples and detractors  Hall begins by stressing his ordinary side  He’s weary  justifiably anxious after uncounted death threats  worried about who will carry on if he can’t. His flight to Memphis has been delayed by a bomb threat  and he has just spoken of his fears to a crowd at Mason Temple. (In real life  King said  “Some began to…talk about the threats that were out. What would happen to me from some of our sick white brothers?”) We meet him after that speech  as he waits for Ralph Abernathy to bring him a pack of Pall Malls from a nearby store. King (Gerard Hazleton) asks room service to send coffee  and a maid named Camae (Erica Truesdale) delivers it. But just as King himself is not merely the “ordinary man” we see fumbling around in the beginning  Camae is not an ordinary maid. She reveals her mission halfway through the one-act play and turns the story around. King (Gerard Hazelton) and Camae (Erica Truesdale) in Actor’s Theatre’s “The Mountaintop.” Courtesy of Actor’s Theatre of Charlotte Director April A. Jones (assisted by Jeremy DeCarlos) makes clever and ultimately inspirational use of video  taking us in one montage to a time when Vi Lyles can be Charlotte’s first black female mayor  and Braxton Winston can go from public protestor to Charlotte City Council member in 14 months. Jones knows this play about social change has to show the characters changing  too  even in the 105 minutes we spend with them. So as King grows from a man terrified by death and failure into one who understands his place in the world  Hazleton deepens and intensifies his performance. As Camae’s character takes on more hues  Truesdale’s comic sassiness gives way to compassion and wisdom  especially in a monologue where we learn her backstory. Director April Jones watches the final dress rehearsal of “The Mountaintop.” Courtesy of Actor’s Theatre of Charlotte Yet Hall sends us away feeling the real protagonists in this encounter are ourselves. “The baton may have been dropped  but anyone can pick it back up ” Camae tells King  as he envisions his death getting closer. King fought for 13 years for civil rights  economic fairness and an end to war  and Hall wants us to finish that race — or  at least  to take a lap or two in our own lives. That we leave resolving to do so is the triumph of the play. “The Mountaintop” WHEN  Through March 31 at 7 30 p.m. Wednesday-Thursday  8 p.m. Friday-Saturday  2 30 p.m. Sunday. WHERE  Actor’s Theatre of Charlotte  Hadley Theater at Queens University  2132 Radcliffe Ave . RUNNING TIME 105 minutes without intermission. TICKETS  $25-$44. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/9ece244c244f6423d656aadce6264de4.com/entertainment/arts-culture/6n3qfn/picture205666504/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Mountaintop%201</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article205666529.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
