<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/business/article207127099.html</field>
<field name="title">FCP buys Reserve at Providence apartments in Charlotte  NC</field>
<field name="name">FCP buys Reserve at Providence apartments in Charlotte  NC</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-28T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 28  2018 01 00 PM An investment company from Maryland has purchased a large south Charlotte apartment community for $60.8 million  and plans to renovate the buildings and add more amenities. FCP bought the 574-unit Reserve at Providence development from a California company. The former owners paid $37.3 million in 2015 for the apartments near Providence and Old Providence roads  which was previously called Landmark at Lynden Square. “We are excited about this acquisition because of its excellent location in South Charlotte  where strong population and job growth are contributing to a wave of new construction and a corresponding decline in the workforce housing stock ” said FCP senior associate Alex Cathcart  in a statement. Workforce housing is a term that generally refers to housing that s affordable to workers such as teachers  police officers and nurses. FCP plans to spend money on the property by building a new clubhouse and leasing center  improving the amenities such as pools and picnic areas  and turning the clubhouse into a  state-of-the-art fitness and amenity center.  The development includes apartments and townhouses with one to four bedrooms  making it appealing to families  FCP said. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW A one-bedroom apartment starts at just above $700 at the property. The garden-style apartments date to 1980  according to property records. As Charlotte s apartment market continues booming  older buildings have become increasingly appealing targets to  value add  investors. Such companies buy older buildings  renovate apartments and add amenities  then raise the rent to recoup their investment. An Observer analysis this year found such investment firms have purchased almost 13 000 apartments in Charlotte since 2013  adding to the city s growing affordability problem. Read More </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/0b4b9a58433996f8629f3b8a0e993026.png</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/business/article207127099.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
