<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/latest-news/article207565294.html</field>
<field name="title">NCAA Latest  Villanova-Michigan set for national title game | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">NCAA Latest  Villanova-Michigan set for national title game | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Kansas won the last of its five national titles five years ago  the last time the Final Four was in San Antonio s Alamodome. ___ 9 40 p.m. Kansas is running out of time to make a comeback in the national semifinal against Villanova. The Jayhawks were with 71-57  the closest since the opening minute of the second half  when Malik Newman made a jumper. But they then missed their next five field goal attempts. Villanova led 74-57  after its first free throw and a field goal  at the under-eight media timeout. ___ 9 30 p.m. Villanova went to the free throw line for the first time with 8 48 left in the game — after the Wildcats had already made 17-of-36 3-pointers. Jalen Brunson made 1-of-2 free throws after being fouled by Silvio De Sousa. ___ 9 20 p.m. The Villanova Wildcats keep setting new records with all those 3-pointers they are making in the Final Four. Their 17 3s so far against Kansas on way to a 67-47 lead are the most ever in a Final Four game. They had 13 before halftime to match the previous mark. With four more 3s in the second half  the Wildcats have 65 in this NCAA Tournament  breaking VMI s the previous record for a single tourney with 61 in 2011. Villanova earlier in the game broke VMI s single-season record for 3s. Eric Paschall has four of Villanova s 3s so far. ___ 8 55 p.m. Villanova has already matched the record for the most 3-pointers in a Final Four game with 13 against Kansas. And the Wildcats still have a whole half left to play in the national semifinal. Seven different players made 3-pointers for the Wildcats as they jumped out to a 47-32 halftime lead. Jalen Brunson  the AP national player of the year  had three 3s for Villanova as part of his game-high 13 points. Four other players had also hit multiple 3s. Kansas had 13 total made field goals in the first half. Big 12 player of the year and AP All-America guard Devonte  Graham led the Jayhawks with 10 points. ___ 8 40 p.m. Those long-range shots keep going in for Villanova. The Wolverines have made 13 3-pointers (out of 21 attempts) in the first 17 minutes against Kansas for a 43-28 lead . They came into the national semifinal only six made 3s shy of the NCAA single-season record. Seven different players already had made 3s for Villanova. Five of those had multiple 3s  led by AP player of the eyar Jalen Brunson s three. The Wildcats were 4-of-24 on 3s in their East Region final  but had made 44 3-pointers in their previous three NCAA Tournament games. Villanova now has 449 made 3s for this season  breaking the record VMI had set in 2007. ___ 8 15 p.m. Villanova is hitting its 3-pointers in the Final Four  matching an NCAA record and jumping out to a 22-4 lead over Kansas. The Wildcats made six 3-pointers in the first 7 minutes of the national semifinal game. Those early 3s gave the Wildcats have 442 this season  matching the NCAA single-season record set by VMI in 2007. The Wildcats started 6-of-10 from long range. Five different players made 3-pointers. After Kansas got the first basket of the game  three different Wildcats hit from 3-point range in a span of 1 24. Jayhawks coach Bill Self called timeout at the 17 13 mark after 3s by Eric Paschall  Mikal Bridges and Omari Spellman. Villanova made only four 3-pointers in their 71-59 East Region final victory over Texas Tech  its second-lowest total of the season. ___ 8 p.m. It s time to determine which No. 1 seed — Kansas or Villanova — will play against Michigan for the national championship. The Jayhawks and Wildcats  who both have won multiple national titles  have tipped off in the second national semifinal game. Michigan beat Loyola-Chicago 69-57 earlier in the Alamodome. Villanova won its second NCAA championship only two years ago in Houston — which is only about a 200-mile drive along Interstate 10 from San Antonio. The Wildcats got their first title since 1985 when Kris Jenkins hit a buzzer-beating 3-pointer to beat North Carolina. Kansas has won five national championships  but its last was 10 years ago. That was also the last time the Final Four was played in the Alamodome. __ 7 15 p.m. Michigan is moving on to the national championship game for the first time since 2013 after ending Loyola-Chicago s incredible run in the NCAA Tournament. Moe Wagner had 24 points and 15 rebounds for the Wolverines  who overcame a 10-point deficit early in the second half to beat Loyola 69-57. Charles Matthews added 17 points. The Ramblers  the No. 11 seed in the South Region  were in their first Final Four since 1963 — the year they were national champions. Freshman center Cameron Krutwig had 17 points and Clayton Custer 15 for Loyola  which finished the season 32-6. That was a school record for wins. The Wolverines (33-7) will play Villanova or Kansas — a pair of No. 1 seeds meeting in the other semifinal game Saturday night in the Alamodome — in the championship game Monday. Michigan has won 14 games in a row after ending Loyola s 14-game winning streak. ___ 7 05 p.m. Loyola-Chicago is going to need some more answered prayers to have another game at the Final Four. Moe Wagner and the Michigan Wolverines are trying to end the magical ride in the NCAA Tournament for the Ramblers and Sister Jean. Wagner has 24 points and 15 rebounds for the Wolverines  who have overcome a 10-point deficit in the second half to lead 61-53 with 1 39 left in the first national semifinal game. ___ 6 55 p.m. Marques Townes is hobbled for Loyola-Chicago after coming down awkwardly on his left knee while missing badly on a 3-point shot. Townes was on the bench when Michigan tied the game at 47 at the 6 56 mark  though he re-entered with 6 20 left after trying to stretch it out on the bench and convincing coach Porter Moses he was OK to get back in the game. ___ 6 45 p.m. Michigan fifth-year senior Duncan Robinson is the first player ever to score in a Division I and a Division III men s basketball semifinal game. And his two second-half 3-pointers in the second half could be a good sign for the Wolverines. Michigan is 28-0 when Robinson scores six points or more. He was scoreless at half. Before transferring to Michigan three years ago  Robinson played at Williams College in Massachusetts. He played for the Ephs in the 2014 Division III semifinals. ___ 6 20 p.m. Michigan started the second half against Loyola-Chicago with its biggest deficit in the NCAA Tournament since falling behind 10-0 in the first 4 minutes of its first-round game against Montana. Loyola-Chicago  the No. 11 seed from the South Region  led the Wolverines 29-22 in the Alamodome. Then the Ramblers started the second half with a three-point play to make it 32-22. The Wolverines  the No. 3 seed in the West Region  erased their deficit against Montana and led 31-28 at halftime of that game. This was the first time they have trailed at halftime in the NCAA Tournament. ___ 6 10 p.m. Ten of the 13 members of the Basketball Hall of Fame s newest induction class have been introduced at halftime of Michigan s game against Loyola Chicago at the Final Four. The Alamodome crowd warmly welcomed the group of basketball luminaries  which includes Steve Nash  Jason Kidd  Grant Hill  Ray Allen and Tina Thompson. Their honor was announced earlier in the day  and they ll be enshrined in Springfield  Massachusetts in September. Even Sister Jean Dolores-Schmidt joined in the cheers and applause for the honorees. From her seat two rows behind courtside  Loyola-Chicago s 98-year-old superfan clapped the longest for Hill  Allen and Thompson  the WNBA great. ___ 6 05 p.m. Sister Jean and the Loyola-Chicago fans are feeling pretty good at halftime  with the Ramblers leading Michigan 29-22 in the first game at the Final Four. Donte Ingram ended the half for Loyola-Chicago by grabbing an offensive rebound and making a short jumper just before the buzzer. The Ramblers were down by as many as eight points early after missing eight of their first 10 shots. They made eight of 14 shots after that and have three players with eight points — Aundre Jackson  Marques Townes and Cameron Krutwig. Moe Wagner has 11 points and 11 rebounds for Michigan  which is 9-of-31 shooting (29 percent). The Wolverines are 2-of-13 on 3-pointers. ___ 5 50 p.m. Michigan center Moe Wagner already has a double-double in the first half against Loyola-Chicago. Wagner  the 6-foot-11 junior from Germany  had 11 points and 10 rebounds with 2 46 left in the half. He had five offensive rebounds  though the Wolverines had fallen behind 25-19. ___ 5 35 p.m. Loyola-Chicago has finally ended its long field-goal drought at the Final Four. The Ramblers missed eight straight shots and went 7½ minutes without a basket before Donte Ingram found Aundre Jackson for a layup inside at the 10 17 mark. Loyola-Chicago started the game by missing nine of its first 11 shots. But Jackson got open inside  then Marques Townes hit a contested jumper over Jordan Poole at the 9 19 mark to beat the shot clock. Michigan leads 12-10. ___ 5 25 p.m. Loyola-Chicago is off to a bad start in the Final Four  missing eight of its first 10 shots and going more than 5 minutes without a field goal. The Ramblers are also getting out-rebounded 12-6 and have already given up seven second-chance points less than 8 minutes into the game. Michigan was up 12-4 at the 12 38 mark. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/221031f498f70623ff574a9f7949435b.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/latest-news/article207565294.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
