<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/article207632824.html</field>
<field name="title">Charlotte Hornets</field>
<field name="name">Charlotte Hornets</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 03 36 PM The wear-and-tear sure appears to be catching up to Kemba Walker. Meanwhile  Ben Simmons is peaking as the playoffs approach. Following a week in which he set the Charlotte Hornets career scoring mark  Walker looked tired and ineffective in a 119-102 home loss to the Philadelphia 76ers Sunday. Simmons  a candidate for NBA Rookie of the Year  finished with 20 points  15 assists and eight rebounds. J.J. Redick added 20 points  making five of his eight 3-pointers. Walker finished with 10 points and was 2-of-7 from the field. Michael Kidd-Gilchrist and Malik Monk scored 16 each for the Hornets. Reserve center Willy Hernangomez added 15 points and 11 rebounds. This 1 p.m. tip-off started less than 24 hours after a road loss to the Washington Wizards Saturday; Walker and most of his teammates looked overmatched against the playoff-bound Sixers. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW The Sixers led by 20 with 10 1/2 minutes left  despite playing without two starters  All-Star center Joel Embiid and forward Dario Saric. The Sixers swept this four-game season series against the Hornets  with all four games coming in the last month. Three who mattered Simmons  He had 13 assists in the first three quarters. Monk  His 3-point shooting makes a big difference in his overall productivity. Redick  He was a terrific one-season signing  adding experience to a young roster. Observations ▪  Hornets backup center Cody Zeller’s season is over. Coach Steve Clifford said there’s no point   with four games left and Zeller’s left knee still swollen  for him not to shut it down and rest the injury for several weeks. Charlotte Hornets guard Kemba Walker  center  is tied up as he drives to the basket against the Philadelpia 76ers’ Ben Simmons and Ersan Ilyasova. Walker looked tired and ineffective in Sunday’s 119-102 home loss to the Philadelphia 76ers. Nell Redmond AP ▪  Hornets injuries are piling up  particularly at small forward. Treveon Graham is now in the NBA’s concussion protocol and Dwayne Bacon missed Sunday’s game with a right ankle sprain. Both players suffered those injuries in Sunday’s road loss to the Washington Wizards. ▪  Jeremy Lamb played Sunday  after missing Saturday’s game with a sore left foot. ▪  If his concussion ends Graham’s season  then it could also be the end of his time as a Hornet. He’s a free agent at the end of the season  and has certainly improved his NBA-wide resume. As close as the Hornets are to the luxury tax next season  spending money on Graham at small forward might not be a priority Worth mentioning ▪  Only one Hornets home game left  and it’s another Sunday matinee — April 8 against the Indiana Pacers. ▪  If an NBA referee has to work on Easter  it’s at least nice to be at home. Haywoode Workman  who once starred at Myers Park  was one of three officials on Hornets-Sixers Sunday. ▪  Dwight Howard’s 49th double-double this season tied him with Larry Johnson for a Hornets record. Report card C- OFFENSE  Other than get to the foul line frequently  there wasn’t a lot the Hornets did well scoring-wise Sunday. F DEFENSE  Simmons’ size at point guard creates a huge matchup problem  but the Hornets did little to disrupt a Sixers team missing two of its top four scorers. C- COACHING  The schedule and injuries were factors  but the Hornets didn’t put up much resistance. [LATEST  Full Charlotte Hornets coverage] 76ers 119  Hornets 102 PHILADELPHIA (119)—Covington 7-21 2-2 17  Ilyasova 5-8 2-2 16  Johnson 1-5 2-2 4  Simmons 10-17 0-0 20  Redick 7-15 1-1 20  Holmes 3-3 0-0 6  Fultz 2-5 0-0 4  McConnell 3-6 0-0 6  Korkmaz 1-1 0-0 3  Anderson 0-3 1-2 1  Belinelli 9-10 1-1 22. Totals 48-94 9-10 119. CHARLOTTE (102)—Kidd-Gilchrist 6-13 4-4 16  Williams 2-9 0-0 5  Howard 4-7 2-5 10  Walker 2-7 5-5 10  Batum 3-9 2-2 8  Kaminsky 3-8 3-4 10  Hernangomez 2-3 11-14 15  Monk 6-13 0-0 16  Stone 0-0 0-0 0  Lamb 5-13 0-0 12. Totals 33-82 27-34 102. Philadelphia </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5c9e125f91ef3e5ef744d272c034d2e.com/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/b627fi/picture207632819/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/Simmons</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nba/charlotte-hornets/article207632824.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
