<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/state/south-carolina/article207626164.html</field>
<field name="title">Charleston  SC area food truck Wraps Around the World stolen</field>
<field name="name">Charleston  SC area food truck Wraps Around the World stolen</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 02 48 PM A pair of Charleston-area food truck owners are desperate to find their family business after the truck was stolen in the Lowcountry on Tuesday morning. Tanarra Mason and her boyfriend Matthew Taylor both of West Ashley had been running Wraps Around the World for about a year  Mason told Live 5 News . She last saw the truck parked in the lot near her apartment before she took her kids to school Tuesday morning. “We were getting ready to get somewhere with this ” Mason told Live 5 News. “It was getting serious.” Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW A small piece of the truck was found across the street from it s regular overnight spot  Count on 2 reported. Gouge marks were left in the pavement which showed the path along which the trailer had been dragged. It was last seen by witnesses attached to a black truck. A small handle is all Mason has left of the truck for now. She was able to buy the food truck after the death of her father  who left behind some money and a dream to start a culinary business of some sort  according to Mason s description in a GoFundMe campaign.  My heart is shredded   she wrote.  This is how I pay my bills and feed my three children.  The GoFundMe campaign had been shared over 100 times and raised over $1 200 of the $20 000 goal in about three days. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/9707788280a4f51e26ccbc2009076b45.JPG</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/state/south-carolina/article207626164.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
