<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/entertainment/arts-culture/article205299734.html</field>
<field name="title">Breaking  Here s Charlotte s Broadway Lights lineup for 2018-19 season at Blumenthal</field>
<field name="name">Breaking  Here s Charlotte s Broadway Lights lineup for 2018-19 season at Blumenthal</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-18T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 18  2018 05 00 AM How do you top a 2017-18 Broadway Lights season so cool that it ends with four weeks of “Hamilton”? You don’t try. Instead  you come up with a season so hot that five of the eight shows are currently playing on Broadway  one closed just eight weeks ago  another comes from the early playbook of sizzling Benj Pasek and Justin Paul  and one will tour just three U.S. cities. Throw in the revival of an unusual  Tony-winning musical to make up the expanded nine-show package  and you have the 2018-19 PNC Broadway Lights lineup from Blumenthal Performing Arts. Add a hellish bat  half a dozen tap-dancing dogs  countless cats  a guitar wizard and some wizards without guitars  and you have the Broadway Extras lineup  too. Season tickets go on sale today; single tickets will be available closer to the opening of each show. (Remember  the current Broadway Lights/Extras slate has nine productions left on it.) Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW As before  you can swap tickets for four shows  changing them for anything the Blumenthal offers. And for the second year  you can buy ticket insurance for about 6.5 percent of the cost of a ticket; it works like travel insurance  reimbursing you if you can’t attend a performance. Blumenthal president/CEO Tom Gabbard believes the BPA pioneered this concept nationally; he’s seen it work when shows went on during bad weather but patrons decided to stay home. Tickets to the eight-show series range in price from $268.50 (the cheapest seats on a Tuesday) to $889.50 (the costliest seats for a Saturday night). The nine-show package ranges from $350 to $996. You can get details at 704-372-1000 or blumenthalarts.org . Here’s what to expect for 2018-19. For the PNC Broadway Lights  “A Christmas Story” Dec. 4-9; Ovens Auditorium  When this faithful musical adaptation of the perennial holiday movie opened in 2012 – and closed after 15 previews and 51 performances – Pasek and Paul had not shared an Oscar with Justin Hurwitz (for the song “City of Stars” in “La La Land”) or won two Tonys for “Dear Evan Hansen.” Now they have  and this story of Ralphie and his forlorn but loving family will be on the road again. “Matthew Bourne’s Cinderella” Jan. 6-12  2019; Belk Theater  His name signifies a new take on a familiar story  as fans of “Sleeping Beauty” and “The Red Shoes” know. Cinderella’s a nurse during the blitz in 1940s London  caring for a Royal Air Force pilot. (It’s Prokofiev’s music.) Gabbard says the show will play only Los Angeles  Washington  D.C.  and Charlotte; “Red Shoes” also hit New York  but Bourne couldn’t get a good booking this time. Why Charlotte? He likes Gabbard and the city  and you often find the British choreographer here on opening nights. “Miss Saigon” Feb. 19-24  2019; Belk  No  Charlotte’s Eva Noblezada won’t tour. Yes  there’s a helicopter (and not just on video  as in the last tour). The big draw  says Gabbard  is grittiness  The producers of the 25th-anniversary revival  which opened in London in 2016 before reaching Broadway last year  give us “a stronger sense of being in the slums of Saigon  and the emotions are more real in every way. They’ve cherry-picked the best elements from productions over the last 25 years.” “Dear Evan Hansen” March 19-24  2019; Belk  Speaking of Pasek and Paul  this show won six Tonys last year and inspired rabid fandom via brilliant use of social media. The protagonist  a high schooler who suffers from social anxiety disorder  feels neglected by his mother. When a student he barely knew commits suicide  he invents a relationship with the dead boy to impress classmates and forge a relationship with the suicide’s family. This may sound a bit creepy  but critics and audiences say otherwise. “Hello  Dolly!” “Hello  Dolly!” July 9-14  2019; Belk  No  Bette Midler won’t tour. But without disrespect  that’s not a bad thing  We’ll see Betty Buckley  the original Grizabella in Broadway’s “Cats” and a memorably tragic Norma Desmond in “Sunset Boulevard ” as the forceful matchmaker who straightens out lives in 1900s New York. Gabbard says director Jerry Zaks has made the show tighter and faster  found laughs where you might not look for them and made the characters more down-to-Earth and credible. “The Band’s Visit” Aug. 6-25  2019; Knight Theater  Though the 2007 Israeli movie barely made a ripple at U.S. cinemas  the Broadway version has been acclaimed. An Egyptian police band on a concert tour to Israel mistakenly ends up in a small town in the Negev Desert  where they find no hotel or transportation to a city. David Yazbek (“The Full Monty ” “Dirty Rotten Scoundrels”) wrote the lyrics and Middle Eastern-flavored music  and some actors in the onstage band play their own instruments. “Aladdin” Sept. 10-29  2019; Belk  The Disney musical  which celebrates its fourth anniversary on Broadway this week  paired composer Alan Menken with three lyricists  Howard Ashman  Tim Rice and Chad Beguelin (“The Wedding Singer”). It created a splash by casting a black genie – James Monroe Iglehart  who won a Tony – and  says Gabbard  “When I first saw it  after he did his big number  African-American audience members jumped up in triumph at what he had accomplished. I couldn’t wait to bring it.” “A Bronx Tale.” “A Bronx Tale” Oct. 8-13  2019; Ovens  Back-to-back Menken! Here he teams with Glenn Slater (“Sister Act”) to produce a 1950s-style score that takes us back to the days of street-corner doo-wop groups. Chazz Palminteri created the piece as a one-man show in the 1980s  wrote and starred in the 1993 movie and wrote the book for this musical. It’s about a boy who’s torn between loyalty to his bus-driver father and the friendship of a charismatic gangster  and who gets into trouble when he begins an interracial romance. “Falsettos” June 25-30  2019 (an add-on for the nine-show package); Knight  The William Finn-James Lapine musical was decades ahead of its time when it debuted in 1992. Act 1 depicts relationships among an elementary schooler  his mom  his gay dad  his dad’s male lover and a therapist. Act 2  set two years later on the eve of a bar mitzvah  introduces a lesbian couple. As we grapple today with what “family” means  this show – set in 1979 and 1981 – has never been more timely. And for the Broadway Extras  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/2c8dff887b33481961f2d0e0544a9f55._Photo_by_Deen</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/entertainment/arts-culture/article205299734.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
