<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/food-drink/article207150159.html</field>
<field name="title">Fried Chicken Wars  Part II  Publix vs. Charlotte s favorite gas-station yardbird | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Fried Chicken Wars  Part II  Publix vs. Charlotte s favorite gas-station yardbird | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 29  2018 08 25 AM Three women  two days  one car. Our assignment  To decide which supermarket deli turned out the best fried chicken. And then take it to the limit  with a taste-off between the winner and a Charlotte fan favorite. While we were planning our story on the fried chicken sold at Publix  Harris Teeter  Food Lion and Walmart  we couldn t help wondering how the ultimate winner would hold up against Charlotte s cult favorite  the fried chicken served at two Quik Shoppe Shell stations  at Eastway Drive and at the busy intersection of South and East boulevards near uptown Charlotte. While I ve had my share of the well-known Quik Shoppe Shell chicken  my partners in this story  Sallie Funderburk of Charlotte Five and photographer Khadejeh Nikouyeh  had never experienced it. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. The final taste-off  Publix vs. Shell Quik Shoppe. Kathleen Purvis We agreed it was time for a throwdown  The winner of our supermarket samples vs. Shell Quik Shoppe No. 3. There had been no contest in the first round. Publix won easily  with the best combination of crunchy crust; juicy  well-salted meat; large pieces; and the potential for serving it cold at a picnic. The Shell Quik Shoppe at South and East boulevards has an array of fried chicken pieces  in regular and spicy. Kathleen Purvis On Wednesday  we got a second box of Publix chicken and headed to the Quik Shoppe Shell station to put both through the same rigorous testing. The results  Publix  $7.99 for an eight-piece box. 1. Crispiness/crunchiness  10. Craggy and bumpy enough to shed lots of crumbs  the crust on this one wins every time. 2. Spiciness/seasoning  9.5. The meat under the crust was definitely salty  with plenty of flavor. This wassn t one of those chickens where you just want to eat the crust and stop. 3. Juiciness  10. There was plenty of moisture under that skin  even on the white-meat pieces. 4. Size of pieces  10. The largest of every sample we tried in these tests. A breast held up next to an open hand stretched from our wrists to beyond our fingers — and easily would have served a couple of people. The other pieces were also large and meaty. 5. Potential to serve cold  10. With a crunchy crust and well-flavored  juicy meat  this would still be good chilled. 6. Greasiness  9. Using our paper-napkin test  it definitely had grease. All that juiciness comes from somewhere. Score  58.5. Quik Shoppe Shell  $13.99 for an eight-piece box with rolls. (Available in spicy and regular; we evaluated regular.) 1. Crispiness/crunchiness  8.5. The crust was thinner  but that also made it beautifully crisp. 2. Spiciness/seasoning  10. There was definitely flavor here. Even though the store has claimed there is no seasoning  just fresh chicken fried well  something about this crust had the savory meatiness of seasoned salt. 3. Juiciness  10. The chicken underneath the crust was moist. No dry-chicken issues here. 4. Size of pieces  9. The pieces were generous with lots of meat  but not quite as big as the Publix pieces. 5. Potential to serve cold  10. With the flavorful crust and the moist meat  this would hold up great for a picnic. 6. Greasiness  10. It passed the napkin test with plenty of flavorful fat. Score  57.5. The winner  by a single point  Publix. But we also agreed to a personal split decision. Funderburk preferred the great crust of the Publix version  Purvis went with the flavor of the Shell station s. Either way  there s no bad decision here. That s it  Charlotte  Go forth into picnic season. And spread your wings. Kathleen Purvis; 704-358-5236. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/4c340a3c9d69cfe28966d3e109201844.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/food-drink/article207150159.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
