<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/nation-world/national/article207623534.html</field>
<field name="title">Train drags 7-year-old girl down tracks in Alabama</field>
<field name="name">Train drags 7-year-old girl down tracks in Alabama</field>
<field name="created">2018-04-01T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story April 01  2018 01 06 PM Shequllia Galloway rarely lets her four daughters play outside their Birmingham  Alabama  home  but around 7 30 p.m. Wednesday she let them go out for spring break while she prepared dinner  she told WBRC. A train rumbled as it moved down the railroad tracks behind their home. Then she heard her 7-year-old daughter  Curteria Thomas  scream. “And when I looked up  I saw my oldest daughter had her by the hand and Curteria was being dragged up the track and my daughter was trying to help her from under there ” Galloway told WBRC. The train had been stopped on the tracks when Curteria crawled through a hole in a fence and began playing underneath it  Galloway said. The train backed up  trapping Curteria. Galloway couldn’t yank Curteria out from under the train  but a neighbor came to the rescue  pulling the 7-year-old free. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW “She said  ‘Mommy  stop crying. God’s got me.’ ” Galloway said. “That’s all she kept saying … that’s all she kept saying.” Four Birmingham Police Department officers  part of a high-intensity policing team  were on patrol one street over when they heard the commotion and rushed to help   reported The Birmingham News. “We literally got to her in 30 seconds and then the medics pulled up. They were right there too – that just shows you how God works ” Officer Ivy Edmond said. “He put us in that spot. Everybody in the neighborhood came together and helped us. It really felt like a family.” Curteria was taken to Children’s of Alabama Hospital in critical condition with non-life threatening injuries  reported WIAT. All four officers were touched by Curteria’s demeanor after the accident  they told The Birmingham News. “Her smiled just warmed my heart ” Officer Darion Lewis told the publication. They decided to do something to help out the family  collecting donations from fellow officers and later visiting Curteria’s hospital room with balloons  crayons  toys  activity books  paint sets  snacks – and a princess tiara.  We know the child s life is going to change forever and we just wanted to help make it smoother    Officer Joseph Hassell said. Galloway later wrote on Facebook that the neighbor who pulled Curteria from beneath the train also visited her in the hospital. “To see the face of the man WHO LITERALLY Saved YOUR CHILD S LIFE IS WAS THE Biggest GIFT OF ALL ” Galloway wrote. She also posted photos of Curteria  wearing her tiara  standing beside her hospital bed with the help of a child-size walker.   </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/f9df90fdd8b173c48e8b223b11f104cf.com/news/nation-world/national/gn7mi4/picture207623529/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/curteri_fitted</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/nation-world/national/article207623534.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
