<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/home-garden/article207439019.html</field>
<field name="title">Debating whether to remodel or sell your house? Ask these 7 questions first | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Debating whether to remodel or sell your house? Ask these 7 questions first | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-30T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Debating whether to remodel or sell your house? Ask these 7 questions first By DANIELLE BRAFF Chicago Tribune Order Reprint of this Story March 30  2018 04 00 AM Sandy Tremain and her husband  Jeff  bought her 1960s Deerfield home in 2008. Back then the four-bedroom home with original pink bathrooms  galley kitchen and vintage appliances worked just fine. Six years later  though  the Tremains felt the time was ripe to move on. In that period  their household had grown to include three children  an au pair and a handful of pets.  The thought of major construction was scary to say the least   said Sandy Tremain  43  a sales manager. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW But when she and Jeff Tremain  39  began searching for houses  the sticker shock hit.  Ultimately  after looking at dozens of houses that were substantially more expensive and easily needed over $100 000 worth of upgrades  we decided to pull the trigger and renovate   she said. After all  they loved their neighborhood and location  their property taxes would still be lower with the renovation than they d be with a bigger  newer house – and with a renovation  they could create the home they always wanted  Tremain said. The couple completely gutted and reconfigured the house. They built an office/bedroom  another bathroom and 1 000 square feet of additional living space  making the kitchen  family room and master suite more spacious. They also replaced the exterior with new siding and incorporated new landscaping  along with other improvements.  We have our dream house now  and the cost proved to be less than buying something new   she said  declining to reveal what the couple spent on the renovation. Choosing whether to renovate or to move – essentially  in the words of HGTV  whether to love it or list it – is a complicated decision. Before forging ahead  you need to weigh multiple factors. Experts suggest you ask yourself these questions. – How long have you been in your home? Consider waiting three to five years before selling  said Joshua Lybolt  president at Lifstyl Real Estate in northwest Indiana.  Typically  at three years is when you break even  as one should consider costs like real estate agent commissions and moving expenses   Lybolt said. Property values also can change during this time  which could improve your home s value  he said. – Did you think about the reality of renovations?  Renovating is time-consuming  waiting for permits  inspectors  communicating with your general contractor and picking out finishes and fixtures   said Evelyn Clifford  a broker with @properties in Chicago. Along with being drawn-out  the endeavor can be expensive – Clifford advised that those considering a remodel should budget for 20 percent more than the estimated cost to allow room for unforeseen expenses. – Are you going to over improve your home? The best investments you can make are upgrades to the bathroom  kitchen  landscape  carpet  and paint  Lybolt said. Your home value is in part based on comparable houses in the neighborhood  he said  so if there s a chance you might sell your home down the line  be careful not to renovate so extensively that your home s value far outpaces homes in the area – you ll be less likely to recoup the costs of the remodel when you sell. – Do you like your location?  Location is and always should be the first consideration   said Robert Boudreau  a certified home inspector with Metro-West Appraisal and Home Inspections who s based in Detroit. If you love your current location  then you may want to renovate to stay there  rather than move to a better home in a less desirable location. – How much can you get for your home? Talk with a local realty agent who knows your neighborhood well  said Jonathan Self  a real estate broker with Center Coast Realty in Chicago.  They can give you insight into homes that have recently sold  and what the demand was like for those homes   he said. Depending on what the market is for homes like yours  the agent will tell you whether now is a good time to sell your home – and whether you ll be able to find or afford the home you want  Self said. – Would you be happy with a face-lift? Megan Clancy  Glencoe  Ill.-based owner of Orderly Manor  organizes and stages homes to get them ready to be sold. But often  after she preps a house by painting it  changing light fixtures and getting rid of the clutter  clients change their mind about selling.  Then we get new tiles and spruce it up to cosmetically look even better   Clancy said.  We basically put some makeup on it to make it look a little prettier.  Clancy suggested that before you go through the effort of moving  think about whether you d rather spend a little money to organize  declutter  and redo a few aspects of your home to freshen its appearance. – Have you truly outgrown your space? If you need extra bedrooms and can t split one in two  then you may have outgrown your space. Or if you re always feeling cramped in the common areas and have no more walls to knock down  then perhaps it s time to seriously consider a move. But if your issues can be resolved with renovations  you can expand the backyard to allow for more outdoor space and you re fond of your neighborhood  you are probably better off staying where you are  Self said. The cost of moving combined with house-hunting time and effort won t be worth it  especially if you haven t lived in your home for long.  If you ve been in your home less than five years  haven t outgrown the space  and are dreaming of living in an upgraded space in your current neighborhood  chances are you d be better off going through some renovations   Self said. But when it comes down to the nitty-gritty of renovating  he warned   Just know that this is not going to be like an HGTV show.  </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e5a8b7ed4650c2cc8f9b02a0c1761562.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/home-garden/article207439019.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
