<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article199923454.html</field>
<field name="title">The Piedmont Kennel Club s 1938 dog show in Charlotte  NC.</field>
<field name="name">The Piedmont Kennel Club s 1938 dog show in Charlotte  NC.</field>
<field name="created">2018-02-14T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">February 14  2018 06 40 AM *Slideshow at bottom* Hundreds of dogs competed but in the end a “handsome Smooth Fox Terrier dog” from Long Island named Nornay Sadler won the 1938 Piedmont Kennel club dog show grand prize. Other winning breeds  Pointer  English and Irish Setter  Springer Spaniel  Cocker Spaniel  Afghan Hound  Beagle  Dachshund  Foxhound  Collie  Doberman Pinscher  German Shepherd  Great Dane  Samoyed  St. Bernard  Airedale  and Bull  Cairn  and Fox Terrier (smooth and wire). Read more about the show here  then enjoy the slideshow at the bottom. + + + April 21  1938 - The Charlotte Observer Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. DOGS ARRIVING FOR SHOW HERE Piedmont Kennel Club to Sponsor Exhibit at Armory Friday and Saturday Well pedigreed dogs from a score of States began to arrive in Charlotte yesterday in preparation for the seventh annual dog show of the Piedmont Kennel club Friday and Saturday at the Armory-Auditorium. It is expected that about 400 dogs will be exhibited. Elaborate silver trophies and many valuable prizes have been offered for the show dogs from the kennels and for local dogs of a score of breeds and several hundred classifications. Fuller Hendrix is president of the Piedmont Kennel club. Edgar A. Moss of Greensboro will be the show superintendent. The judges will be G.V. Glebe of Bryn Athyn  Pa.  F.H. Farwell of Orange  Texas  G. Fred Thomas of Filbert  S.C.  and Mrs. Annie Rankin of Charlotte. The Junior department of the Charlotte Women’s club will be in charge of the sale of tickets to the show. The junior department will be in charge of a fashion show at 9 o’clock Friday night at the dog show to be known as “Blue Ribbons on Parade.” The show will bring to the women of Charlotte some of the advance summer styles in cottons and other washable materials. The models  all of whom are Charlotte girls  will display some of the most popular numbers which milady will select for her summer wardrobe. The following young women are among those taking part in the fashion show  Mrs. Thomas Watkins  Mrs. Elizabeth Montgomery  Mrs. W.P. Meeks  Miss Mattie Covington  Miss Hilda Malavere  Miss Sara Anthony  Miss Eleanor Matheson  Miss Vivian Goley  Miss Carolyn Rivers  Miss Alma Richardson  and Miss Nita Mitchell. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/1db29b8e14fbeff1114a4bc87ee7a20e.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/qmeenq/picture199923369/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/ViewScan_dog0000-page-0A</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article199923454.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
