<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/living/religion/article207279734.html</field>
<field name="title">Christians and Jews celebrate major holidays this weekend</field>
<field name="name">Christians and Jews celebrate major holidays this weekend</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-29T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 29  2018 09 15 PM This is the holiest of weekends for Christians as well as the start of Passover  a major holiday for Jews. On Holy Thursday  or Maundy Thursday  Christians remember Jesus  Last Supper with his disciples. At churches such as St. Peter Catholic in uptown Charlotte  priests and lay servers imitated Christ by washing parishioners  feet and dispensing the Eucharist. On Good Friday  Christians will mark Jesus  death by crucifixion. And on Easter Sunday  the most important day on the Christian calendar  church bells will ring and choirs will sing  He is risen!  as Protestants and Catholics celebrate Jesus  resurrection. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. SUBSCRIBE NOW Orthodox Christians  who follow a different calendar  will celebrate Easter  or Pascha  on April 8 this year. At sundown Friday  Jews will usher in Passover  or Pesach  an eight-day festival that commemorates the Israelites  freedom from slavery in ancient Egypt. Jewish families mark this event with a ritual meal called a Seder. Passover this year will end at sundown April 7. On Maundy Thursday  Christians remember Jesus  Last Supper with his apostles. At St. Peter Catholic Church in uptown Charlotte  NC  priests and lay servers washed parishioners  feet  as Jesus did for his disciples  and dispensed the Eucharist  which was introduced at that last meal. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com At St. Peter Catholic Church in uptown Charlotte  NC  priests and lay servers on Maundy Thursday imitate Christ by washing parishioners’ feet  as Jesus did for his disciples. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/976953d26dbb1fe9b334c1770ca2f623.jpg</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/living/religion/article207279734.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
