<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article187516223.html</field>
<field name="title">The Viking Twin Drive-In Theater on Freedom Drive  Charlotte  NC</field>
<field name="name">The Viking Twin Drive-In Theater on Freedom Drive  Charlotte  NC</field>
<field name="created">2017-12-05T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">September 3  1969 - staff report The Viking Twin Drive-In Theaters will open Wednesday  Sept. 10. The theaters  back to back with separate screens on the same huge lot at Freedom Village represent a half million dollar investment on the part of Consolidated Theaters Inc. The theaters will feature the most modern equipment and some new diversions as well  all designed to upgrade the image of drive-in theaters. The lot covers an area of 22.5 acres  with two wide Cinemascope screens at either end  and a large  modern brick and glass concession building in the center. Among other features  there will be a cafeteria-style dining room  a game room with game machines  and a supervised playground. + + + Viking Drive-In Showing Its Last Picture Shows September 7  1981 When the Viking Twin Drive-In  3123 Freedom Dr.  opened Sept. 10  1969  Paul Newman and Dustin Hoffman topped the bill in “Winning” and “The Graduate.” “Angel In My Pocket ” with Andy Griffith  and “Interlude ” with Oskar Werner  played on the other side. Tonight  almost 12 years after the star-studded opening  the Viking Twin Drive-In will close permanently. “Cannonball Run ” “9 to 5” and “Deadly Blessing” will be the last picture shows. Herman Stone  vice president of Consolidated Theaters Inc.  the company that owns the Viking Twin  said  “We just lost our lease on it. We’re just going to dismantle it.” The screens  tower  everything will be dismantled beginning Tuesday morning. The process could take two or three weeks  Stone said. The screens have been sold to a competitor. The playground equipment will be divided between two of Consolidated’s drive-in operations  one in Greenville  S.C.  the other in Spartanburg. If you want to catch the last shows at the Viking  the theater opens at 7 30 p.m.  shows begin at 8 30 p.m. - Mary Martin </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/e0900ea962f04a9aff3b9c781848c73f.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/3w3co0/picture187516183/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/frnt%202A</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/news-columns-blogs/retro-charlotte/article187516223.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
