<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206827569.html</field>
<field name="title">Kyle Busch close again at Martinsville</field>
<field name="name">Kyle Busch close again at Martinsville</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-26T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">March 26  2018 07 53 PM Martinsville  Va. It speaks volumes that Kyle Busch  currently in first place in the NASCAR standings  was so stinkin’ unhappy. Now  take that statement with a caveat  Busch can’t be too unhappy to be atop the Cup series leaderboard. But the way he’s gotten there? Well  that’s certainly a cause for frustration. Busch finished second on Monday at Martinsville Speedway  barely behind Clint Bowyer. It was his third runner-up finish so far this season ... and we’re only six races in. Sprinkled between those silver medals is a bronze  too  from last weekend in California. So yeah  frustrated is a fair way to put it. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. “We take solace  sure  but you know  ultimately we’re here to win each and every week ” Busch said. “I know everybody is  but we’ve been that close each and every week. “We’re right there  we’re knocking on the door.” But so far  Busch and the rest of the No. 18 team have been unable to knock it down. And after the way their 2017 season ended  they cannot be pleased with that. Last season  Busch made an exceptional run through the playoffs and into the championship race at Homestead. There he was  as he was all season  one of the best cars. But not the best. That went to Martin Truex Jr.  who kept Busch from winning his second Cup Series championship. But given the way he plowed through the playoffs in 2017  it was expected before this year that Busch would continue his hot streak. And he has. Just  that hasn’t converted into victories yet. Yet. “We’ve been the closest thing to everybody each and every week ” Busch said. “ I wouldn’t say it’s one particular thing that we can pinpoint  we’ve just been beat by somebody kind of hitting it a little bit more than we have.” This week that somebody was Bowyer  who snapped a 190-race winless streak and stole the chance for Busch to win back-to-back grandfather clocks at Martinsville. His victory at the track in the fall clinched his spot in the championship race. But instead of another addition for his living room  Busch could never quite catch Bowyer. He got close  real close – nearly bumping Bowyer’s bumper at one point – but eventually he couldn’t wade his way through the lapped traffic. And so another second place it would be. Make no mistake – Busch could win multiple races this season. And we might not have to wait long   if his first six finishes are to be believed. But for now  it’s more of a waiting game  especially since drivers have next weekend off. That clearly irks Busch. That’s also not a surprise  given how competitive he is. But the point remains – he’s ticked  even while spearheading the NASCAR leaderboard. “Just didn’t quite have it ” Busch said of his performance Monday. “We’re right there  just not being able to knock it through.” </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/8fe4cf6ee350ce2d7ae20b9aa2cf823a.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/gksifj/picture206922969/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/NASCAR%20Martinsville%20Auto%20Racing</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article206827569.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
