<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article207140324.html</field>
<field name="title">Danica Patrick reveals car she’ll drive in last race ever</field>
<field name="name">Danica Patrick reveals car she’ll drive in last race ever</field>
<field name="created">2018-03-28T00:00:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Order Reprint of this Story March 28  2018 12 42 PM Danica Patrick’s final NASCAR race was earlier this year at the Daytona 500  but now Patrick is preparing for her  final race as a professional. Patrick will compete in May’s Indy 500 race as the second half of the ‘Danica Double ’ a two-race finale to her longtime racing career in both NASCAR and IndyCar. This week she revealed what her car will look like in her final race  – and for fans of her mid-2000’s GoDaddy.com commercials  you’re in luck. Never miss a local story. Sign up today for a free 30 day free trial of unlimited digital access. Danica Patrick will compete in the Indy 500 in May in the last race of her professional driving career. GoDaddy Inc. Patrick’s Indy 500 car  as was her Daytona 500 ride  is a nod to her longtime sponsors at GoDaddy. When Patrick first debuted in NASCAR in 2012  GoDaddy was right there with her. Now the domain registry site is also going out with its most famous athlete. As for the actual race  Patrick will be  driving for Ed Carpenter Racing. It will be her first time driving an IndyCar since 2011. The 102nd Indy 500 is set  for May 27. </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/39cbce797acc212a67254d7171c5ece1.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/vayeh6/picture207140319/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/danica</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article207140324.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
