<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<add><doc>
<field name="id">com.charlotteobserver.www:http/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article151796142.html</field>
<field name="title">Gallery  Kyle Busch wins Monster Energy All-Star Race at CMS | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="name">Gallery  Kyle Busch wins Monster Energy All-Star Race at CMS | Charlotte Observer</field>
<field name="created">2017-05-20T22:23:00Z</field>
<field name="desc">Email NASCAR driver Kyle Busch celebrates winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch crosses the finish line to win the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch bows to the cheers of the fans after winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Joey Logano waves to the fans as he and his team are introduced to the fans prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Jamie McMurray waves to the fans as he and his team are introduced to the fans prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com A motorcyclist performs wheelies during driver introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com A crewman for NASCAR driver Denny Hamlin pumps up the fans during driver introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR fans cheer the drivers during driver introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. waves to fans as he and his team are introduced prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR fans reach out trying to slap hands with driver Dale Earnhardt Jr. during driver introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kurt Busch motions to the fans during introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Jimmie Johnson waves to fans during introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kevin Harvick reaches out to slap hands with fans during driver introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch looks to give two lucky fans a hat during driver introductions prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch and his team are introduced prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Larson and his team are introduced prior to the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch celebrates winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch celebrates winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch  second from left  begins to make his move to pass driver Brad Keselowski  left as they cross the starting line in the final stage of the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Busch would take the lead to win the race and $1 000 000. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch pumps his fist as he performs a burnout after winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch exits his car in a haze of smoke after winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch jumps into the air at the finish line after winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch carries the checkered flag after winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Kyle Busch acknowledges the cheers of the fans after winning the NASCAR Monster Energy All-Star Race on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway in Concord  NC. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR drivers Paul Menard  left  Danica Patrick and crew members wait along pit road for the NASCAR Monster Energy Open to begin on Saturday  May 20  2017 at Charlotte Motor Speedway. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com The American flag is carried into the infield of Charlotte Motor Speedway by a skydiver prior to the running of the NASCAR Monster Energy Open on Saturday  May 20  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com Former President and General Manager of Charlotte Motor Speedway Humpy Wheeler walks down pit road prior to the running of the NASCAR Monster Energy Open on Saturday  May 20  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Clint Bowyer laughs with passerby as he waits along pit road for the start of the NASCAR Monster Energy Open on Saturday  May 20  2017. Bowyer would win the first segment of the race. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Chase Elliott  left  speaks with a crew member along pit road prior to the start of the NASCAR Monster Energy Open on Saturday  May 20  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Daniel Suarez laughs with passerby along pit road prior to the start of the NASCAR Monster Energy Open on Saturday  May 20  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com NASCAR driver Austin Dillon  left  talks with his grandfather Richard Childress  right  on pit road prior to the start of the NASCAR Monster Energy Open on Saturday  May 20  2017. Jeff Siner jsiner@charlotteobserver.com 1 of 31 </field>
<field name="tag">charlotteobserver</field>
<field name="group">1</field>
<field name="category">1</field>
<field name="picUrl">_i/thmb/nws/charlotteobserver/2018_Apr/8dafbf6a7b91b91ba033cc4a2fe92603.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/hppvrv/picture151795987/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1140/NASCAR_ALLSTAR_14</field>
<field name="sourceUrl">http://www.charlotteobserver.com/sports/nascar-auto-racing/thatsracin/article151796142.html</field>
<field name="userRating">0</field>
<field name="callToAction">0</field>
<field name="isActive">true</field>
<field name="contributor">alghiwot@gmail.com</field>
</doc></add>
